<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1893-04-21/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport&amp;r=-0.722,-0.219,1.98,0.957,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FOE MEN AND WOMEN.
Basket Ball as Playod in Y. M. O.
A. Gymnasiums.
Mj
ClifcliertcyE"i,j-,h EVrsetraM ?m&amp;
JK. MIS
sure, 2l-v' litl. Unl5t, n-I M
k -UfisS&amp;iJsiv ""Pl?
ft
t&amp;Wj
7"s "TwVi
A f
ftUVJtoir tfifiT-I b tuu t.l3 j Tnl?) VSy
ChnA!lpr. Jff a 6ienntt ft iir- v
!(jaudnlr..J fit AtD'ss'ti ..t.ri'S-.
"ltr-Ucr for I cUf" Sr vi fr -ctrir
Vnll. 1U.1MK. r-ia Hmtr 1 f
mw,t iipi-'in".' tt BcsraKi
THOMAS F. BAYARD.
STb Xtoiiorab'-a Career' at Onr 2Vew Am
lMador to J Cngantf.
Thomas Francis J 'ayard, the new
Bmbassaaicrto the con rt of. St. Jamets
-cvas borchi Wibninglton, Del., in 1S2S.
Ecrras fitttidfor a m:rca;atiIo life-ami
f-
IF
II OX. TnOMAS T. BATAHD.
placed in a businessliause in Xew York
.Hty. He returned to "Wilmington in
1S48, studied In vr, and -was admitted to
tho bar in 18rl. He was appointed
United -States -district attorney for Del
aware, but resigned tin- following yer.
"n 18'r he reciox d to Philadelphia,
-ivheiehe becamo the partner of Vil
liam bliippeu. He returned tolVilraing--son
and succeeded Ins father to the
.United State.- senate in 1S08. ITe was
reelected in lc7o and again jn ISl. ?k.
Cleveland appointed him scrctarj' of
Atate iu 1SS5. On tho day -on which he
was olecU-d to the serrate for a full
term his father was also reelected a
A Knme for lloth Sexe It Is Something
Like 1'i.otball, I'.ut Has No Hough
features and J 5 Full
or Fun.
For a long1 time gymnasium instruc
tors were confronted by the necessity
for a game which could be played in
doors by old and young, male and fe
male. They wanted a game devoid of
lough features, yet one which should
be thoroughly scientific, and which
should atford plenty of opportunity for
good healthy exercise for the scholar
or business man, and training for the
athlete, feuch possibilities, says the
New York Sun. have been discovered in
the game of basket ball, which has be
come so popular in Fchool and club
fjjnnnasiums throughout thp country.
The (fame was first introduced by the
directors and pupils of the Y. M. C. A.
fill
tSOAI.3.
training school at Springfield, Macs.
Its advantages were t,oon perceived,
and the sport, spread to the gymnasiums
controlled by the Young Men's Chris
tian association, and was further in
troduced in scholastic institutions and
club gymnasiums. At the training school
Ihc g.iuic was developed, and a strong
team was drilled in the simple work
ings of it by James Naismlth, one o the
Springfield instructors, and an earnest
worker in i be Held of all-around sport
and recreation. In New York and
senator lVoui Delii ware to-servo for tha IJrooklyn.are sereral good teams, and
unexpired fl of his original term. H1 P'V "lt; a ir"IU w' l-l"ie-
This is the only case cf a father and The game can readily be played in al-
-sonLeing voted for by tho same icgis- ost the smallest gymnasium. As the
lature to fill the senatorial office. In sizeb of tht! exercising rooms vary, the
vpnate he served on tho committees sjauie purycu uy cuii iwiu ia suKuiy
on finance, judiciary, prh'atc land
rlaims, libiary and revision ofDaws. In
1SS1 ho was elecrcd president pro tem
nore of the senate. He was a.candi-
different. All th match games axe
played under regular rules, however,
-andth" peculiar disad vantage which a
"gym" may have for the visiting team, is
idate for president in ISSO and 1S54. In- remecieil so Xar as possible. Hie game
Wudinghigrest-rraiidfather, Gov. Has-, can be played out of doors on a large
Ptt. h i the fifth member of his fam- umuiibwcu an i .11 Syw
r 1 i. iin?iim. rrin r
piy wni) nave oecnpicu seats 111 11191
jUnitfldita,tes senate,
WHEELMEN'S PRIZE CUP.
r9 Be Competed Vov at tho Gr(At Kce
j The League of Ameiiean TVlieclmen
iJUavo been presented with a very hand
jsomo -trophy to baxrapcted for in their
;Sntcrna,tannal jaco meet, to bo held at
idiica'o next? Augnst, Il&amp;nry Ij. Sal- j
fojistall, a. memUT of the Elizabeth A.
jfff Wheelmen, is the donor of the prize.
jit is a sterling bilvcr cup, gold lined,
itod stands twenty-eigBt inches high ou Jl". "v
The goals pictured in this col
umn arc iised, the upright one for the
field, on wliich it can be placed at any
point, and the other for Indoor play.
The latter is attached to the gallery or
the wall of the room. The string is
used to turn the goal so that tho ball
may readily be regained. These goals
are the improved article The first
goals, from which the game got its
name, were only peach baskets nailed
to tho wall or running tiack.
The game can be played by a number
of men at once. In a small jrvmnasium.
howover, flvo aside is the most con-!
In larger rooms nine
men can piay on a biae. Lnis is con
sidered the regular, number, and they
are placed a -hown in the accompany
ing illustration. Tho game itself is
strictly one of passing the ball fiom
man to man. It can neither be kicked
nor batted with the fist. The object is
to get the ball into the basket or goal.
A large person is useful, but one of the
best players it tho Twenty-third
htreet Y. Jf. C. A. gymnasium is
a little hap not much oTer
GOAL,
KOMT
iTjsagvtfROi.
imitTPimimmmm,
XV
aT&amp;slr araxzE xt the iszesjtjltioxai.
-iix-inch ebony base. The figure of
jFamtttnding upon a globe surmounts
phe lid. 'The jieadsof Bacchus and Icr
WuTy ndorn the arms of the urn, under
(wliich ro American eagles. Tho Tj. A.
pVV. emblem is engraved upon ihc back.
The cup-will be a perpetual challenge
trophy, and the -conditions under winch
It wiil -bo .competed for will be deter
ruined rupon by thcxacing "board of the
league Jt is tho most valuable prize
ver -donated .to the L. A. W. by any in
diridiiol onem.bttr of the organization.
It WiIi"boxacedJorannuallv.
1.
"Upcf, Lfuicmt uuil Clieen." j
1 An American naval officer says that i
once4 -wheal -a great function took place
5n the harbor of Cherbourg, several
.vessels of our American squadron vcre
present ,asd wcie drawn up in line to
baluto the rmpress' yacht as it passed,
Kiyss an article on the navy. TheTTrcnch
ffailors-manned the yards of their -ship s
xuid Blio-uted: Yire l'lmpci-strice!"'
Ivnow ing tliat he could not school his
men to repeat those woids in the brief
Sirao left to him, the American admiral
Wrderefi his crerr to cry: "leef. lemons
Jiud cheese. Tlie imperial yacht came
sweeping on, and as it reached the licet
amlghtj' roar went up of "Beef, lemons
jicd cheese" that entirely drowned the
toIcos of the Frenchmen. And the em
yreR 6aid she had never been so compli
tnented. T'acla Abut Ire-l.iad. t
The population of Ireland in 1S91, ac
fcording to the revised return- just is
uad, was 4,0sl.2-,S. The natural in
crease of population, or eeex of births
Uver death, for the year was '22.117, and
S ho loss by emigration wns 59.023; 21.
75 marriages were registered within
"the year, and it significant of the re
ligious feeling which exists in all parts
ol Ireland that only 399 were by civil
oontracts in the registrars' ofticesT
wftHnjKiin
?'G0AL
POSEMOXS OF TITE FLAYTJIS.
four feet tail. To get an un
covered position is of the utmost im
portance, as the player can thus easily
get the ball and as easily pass it to one
of his side near the goal. It requires a
great deal of practice to put the ball in
the goal, wliich is placed at some dis
tance above the players' heads. 2Cbt
alone must a pla-or be bkillful, he
must also be very lively. A player
must thiow the ball from the spot
w here ho catches it, but ho can turn
around to throw it. 2vo interference is
allowed, and tackling and pushing are
strictly prohibited. A player may only
obstruct the passage of the bail after it
is thrown.
When the game is played 011 a field
the player may run with the ball if he
continually throws it above his head
and cr.tcho it again. The ball may
also be diibbled along the ground with
the hand.
Tt-.di play counts for everything in
basket play. Tlie t.wo forwards and
the home man should always work to
gether to get the ball into the goal.
The backs guard the goal, and the cen
ter men are supposed to get the ball
and pass it forward toward the home
man.
The game is usually played in two
halves of fifteon minutes each, with a
slight intermission. When a goal is
made the same goes right on. It is
perhaps the fastes' game played to
day, and is played with a snap "which
football player in lining up may well</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.902,0.216,2.804,1.355,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
Baticing Baae Ball inCaml In
stitute Gyuasuiuu.
A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.
a"er nianean r @Medsee-A Osmbinmttm
et haswases and feet natI-36e Ned eor
Deun-e.ss-A pset Reeuiring indsabnm
Tse laus ethe Game.
N INDOOR BPORT
which is new to this
city has bees iatre
duced by Mr. MauaI
A. Joyce, the athletic
instructor at the Car
roll Istitute. The
game has met with
great popularity is
other places where it
has been played, and
from the interest which
it hnt excited among
the members of the
Carroll Institute is bids fair to asset with the
Succes here that it bas in other cities. Almost
owery might basket bell is played in the gym
anshetts the institute, and the sport is not only
Smithy and invigerating, but exciting and full
ot interest.
Bushet ball wva Arst started about a year ago
ad ree that time it hes spread throughout
Se esuntry esecially in the gymnasiums of
he yong Men a Christian asociatioss. It is
paticularly adaptable to business men. as little
narmarx A. Joyce.
se metpractice is required to learn it and there
6, no incident roughness if the rules are
stictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr.
deyce is try to have other teams formed in the
symmasisme in the city and to have regular
entestn between them. It eomameade itself in
s it can be played in almost any sized room
den any had of lot. whether it be large or
mail, and that the number of player. need
only be limt. I b the size of the ground. It
bkings into play all maseles of the body. thus
being a healthy exercise, and at the same time
te a ws incidens to moet sports are want
1. The only apparatus neessary for the
oe to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball
mnd re half-bushel baskets.
movwr rT PL 6TD.
Theegh she courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Stan
aoprter witnessed a game of basket ball played
M the Carrer Institute on one of the evenings
of this week. The two baskets are attached to
th =anig strack at the opposite ends of the
gymmsam and U.s object of the game is to
Shen e heU in the opponent'e basket. The
uame consist of mine men each. made up of a
gaiheeper. two backs to assist him. a center, a
eight and left henter, two forward and a home
ma. They are arranged in this order from
Oe gnal whica they are defending. It is not
asessmry that the players thou!d remain in
teir glaces. but they should move in such a
way as to gie the forward player an oppo:
baesy Is gee a good tos at the goal or the
baecks to keep theer opponents from obtaining
so mmm by taking it from thea when they are
ghbntsto throw. It is the luty of the goal
ba~to beep the ball away fromi the vicinity.
etgoal. end it is more often neessary for
hi to bat the bail with his had tha for
e~er meambers of the seama to do so.
L. Serim. 3. leeward
4.ame.. eae...
4. Sm. .a.5
en.. ...s-....e.
The game is started by the teems lining up
ba their respseutve positions and then the
safeae tomes the ballian the air, It must not be
te.-d antal it strikes the ground. Thea the
players ean catch it. and the object of the one
who obtains it isto pass istso one of the players
ahis own sidec.who either passes itto inotherwho
msay be in a favorable position to tom f~ar goal
or else attempts to auake a goal himself. To
bee a foot bal into a basket euasiended ten feet
a cen SsA.av
beG airani eiasest lags en~t. held it.ie
net en eas messean means, end thee.
thanmy ethe at guat are madebut
as t ase -s eemtl, and e sensty
ohB~in meds. esnammty, an the
qshad esty. The haDeam be aoma
an ists with -n or beth --a-~
In bM the sesm s e 40 -a -e
e be h ss:
asmmmS he es h the det er hased
A e esms e with te hasb mUs
am thmm... ..a. a. he
Gotas o ben shile rmaI and Mas to stop
The har maw be held in ds baud The arms
Iee or bod soat not be used for blding it.
If h lb is beld for any length of time th
referee tess it into the air. as in the baegtnmg
of theam
o the5 ein, holding, J~n .trp, n
or striking b allowed. The t iafringem m
'f this rule eosnts a foal and a second dis
q"mli= a player, but, as in foot ball, a substi
tats may take his place.
IN TaN BAsKET. C
When a ball goes out of bounds it is put in
play in the same way as in a foot ball game.
The game consists of two halft of twenty
minutes each or such time as the captains may
decide on. and time is taken out for delays.
A goal counts three points and a foul one
point for the opponent. and a majority of the
points decides the game.
There are a referee and umpire, whose duties
are the same respectively as the same officials
in a foot ball game.
Any player has a right to get the ball at any
time while it is in the field of play. provided
that he handles only the ball and not the op
ponent.
ADVANTAGEs OF THE GAME.
To an observer the game seemed to be one
that will solve the problem, which has been a
knotty one for some time, of introdncing a
game which will meet the excitement incident
to most outdoor sports and at the same time
be suitable for indoor play. At present when
the outdoor season closes most of the athletes
drop tbe sports in which they have been in
terested and the benefits thev derived from
them are lost. This game is one that requires
skill and agility. but strength is not one of the
necessary factors. and, consequently. men of
all physical conditions can take part in it. It
has also been found to have been a useful
sport for girls and women, as it is especially
APTEn THE FALL.
adapted to securing good health without having
the nervous strain caused by some of the
sports now indulged in.
In its principli. it is a combination of foot
ball and lacrosse. It resembles foot ball in
most of the rulings, but in the method to be
pursued to obtain a goal the game more closely
resembles lacrosse. Although at first glance it
would hardly seem possible to have any amount
of team play in the game, still it is only by the
concerted action that a team can play to the
beet advantage. A novice in the game inva
riably feels disposed when he obtains the ball
to make a shot for the goal, which could not be
made from any distance one time in a hundred,
as in order that the ball should remain in the
basket it has to be skillfully and easily tossed,
not thrown. A good player will. when he has
the ball, quickly look for one of his own team
who is in an uncovered position to whom he
can tos it. In this way a well-drilled team
could almost entirely keep the ball from the
hands of a team made up of new men. Quick
ness of eye, hand and foot is one of the first
requisites for a good player, and he also must
keep his head about him. A moment's hesita
tion or a wrong pass may give considerable
advantage to the other side.
If an umpire is chosen who strictly follows
the rules of the game there is little chance for
any roughness, as running with the ball is
prohibited, and thus the injuries coming from
sharp tackling in foot bal are done away with.
The attention of the player is fastened on the
ball and personal feeling in the matter is lost
sight of. The object of each player when one
of his side obtains the ball is to place himself
in an uncovered position so that one of his own
team can pays it to him, while the opponents
should in this eae stick closely to the men
with whom they are paired so that a pass to
them would gave an equal opportunity for each
to catch the ball. It is in this respect that
cool-beadedt.euand quickness count. Idi
vidlual play on the part of one man will destroy
all the good work that the rest of the team may
do. If the game in played indoors in a gym
naisium the passee should be more of a toes
rather than hard straight throw.
As the game has apparently obtained a good
foothold in this city and as it is a healthful and
at the same times exciting sport it is to be
hoped that the efforts of Mr. Joyce to make the
game a popular one in this city will meet with
success, Some of the men under him are bo
conming quite proficient and before long he will
have a iirst-class team,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023253/1895-01-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Games+Sport+Baskets</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BASKET BALL.
Those who were interested in the
basket ball games played last winter
will be pleased to learn that the town
and school boys are tohaveonemore
battle for the supremacy. A word
about the game which has become so
popular in the past few years will
be interesting to those who enjoy
good honest sport.
Basket ball was invented in 1889 by
ames Nuismith, teacher in the interna
tional training school, Springfield. Dur
ing its first season it wasnot particularly
popular hut has gained in favor and may
now be called quite as important sport in
the Y. M. C. A. world as football and
baseball, but it is essentially an indoor
game and the interest that is excited in
an exercise confined to the gymnasium
can perhaps never equal the zest which is
thrown into a game like football, played
under the blue of heaven, in the fresh out
door atmosphere and sun's rays that seem
to penetrate the muscles ot the athlete
and impart added vivacity. However,
at the season when football bruises have
long ago healed and conquests on the
gridiron are matters for rumination, he
who sighs for the pigskin can find much
satisfaction in basket ball, it possessing
all the elements of football but, if rules
are enforced, lacking the excessive rough
ness. The ball used is perlcctly round,
made of a rubber bladder, covered with
leather and is about a foot in diameter.
Briefly outlined the game according to
official rules for 1805, is played as follows:
baskets especially constructed tor the
purpose, are placed in a vertical position
with the mouth ten feetlrom the ground,
one at each end of the field (gymnasium),
occupying much the same position in re
lation to the players as do football goals.
i ne competitive teams tane positions on
the field as in football, save that there is
no line-up, The teams are composed of
five men when the playing space is less
than 1800 square feet, seven when it is
more than 1800 and less than 3600 and
nine men when over 3600. The referee,
with a player from each side, takes posi
tion in the center. He puts the ball in
play by throwing it up. Which side has
first ball depends on which center man
secures it. The ball is not kicked or
struck with the fists but thrown or batted
with the flat of the hand and the object
is, to get it into the basket, doing which
scores a goal. On the number of goals
secured depends the victory. The net
work of rules which govern the action of
the game is quite as elaborate as football
and will not be given here. Suffice it to
say that spectators easily comprehend
its action. The putting of a ball into the
basket may seem a veryeasv thing to do
but as a matter of fact it is very difficult
to acomplish with the floor empty and,
of course, much more so when two teams
are at strife. One of the rules says that
the ball shall always be kept in motion.
Two twenty-minute halves are played
with a rest of ten minutes between "the
halves. This is the time of actual play.
Each side has itscaptain while position
is the same as in baseball. The referee is
judge of the ball. He is the superior offi
cer ot the game and decides all questions
uul ucuimciy lulling on me umpire, i lie
umpire is judge of the men, calls all fouls,
notifies the offenders and has power to
disqualify men.
The game which was to be played
on Thursdayevening of this week has
been postponed until Saturday even
ing. The two teams have been prac
tising faithfully and will be able to
play a very interesting game. It is
hoped that the public will turn out
and encourage the gymnasts, as all
the proceeds over and above the ex
penses are to go towards much need
ed new apparatus for thegymnasium.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1895-11-26/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Play+Games+Game+Foot+Sport&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.05,0.237,0.721,0.697,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>An InlercNtliiir ??'ime of Bitaki-t
Hull.
The game of basket ball played last
evening ln the rifle gallery of the National
Guard between the teams of the Y. M. C.
A. and the Cycle Corps was one of the
cleanest, hardest-fought games that has
been played in the series. Although the
Cycle Corps came out victorious by a score
of to 1, they had to work with all their
energies to attain that end, and several
times It looked squally for them.
It has been claimed by several persons
Interested In the game of basket ball that
the contests were degenerating Into wres
tling matches and slugging bouts, with a
little foot ball thrown in, but last evening's
game demonstrated that basket ball can be
played as lt should be. if the players will
only conform to the rules. A number of
persons were present to witness the games,
and frequently applauded the good plays
made.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-04-02/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Co-eds+Basket+Ball+Match+Basketball+Basket-ball+Teams+Team</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CO-EDS AT BASKET BALL
Secret Practice at Berkeley for
the Great Match on
Saturday.
Greek Letter Fraternities to Present
Plays Paul Revere Lodge
Was Honored.
BERKELEY, Cal., April I.— The Berke
ley Co-ed basket-ball team are ready for
their battle with the Stanford nine next
I Saturday. They have gone into secret
practice and are devoting their time and i
i attention to signal work and to giving
their muscles the hnal course of ex
ercise before they stand up against
the wearers of the cardinal. They
are ail on the gui vive, as are
j the other women athletes of the
i university, for the contest on Saturday
will be t*e first contest they have entered
for honors. "We have the reputation and
the athletic prestige of the university to
uphold," said one of the fairest members
of the team to-day, "and we are going into
1 the struggle with* the purpose of coming
i out victors. We realize the odds we will
have to contend against in not being in as
I good training as we might, and then the
Stanford girls are much more experienced
than we. At any rate we will do our best,
J since we have accepted Stanford's chal
i lenge."
Two or three of the young women have
the appearance of being overtrained,
judging from their pallid faces and worn
expression. This may be due, however, to
anxiety over the result of the came. Tlieir
new costumes consist of white sweaters
and blue bloomers with gold trimmings.
University Cotillon.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92053934/1904-11-19/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Rules+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Dribble</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW RULES ON BASKETBALL
Changed Conditions For Championship
Contests.
Up to the present the basketball
rules have been amended each season
by additions and omissions in various
places. This year, however, the rules
have been rearranged and many rules
bear different numbers and are not
found in the same successive order.
An advantage in the new rule book
also is that at the top of the page i3
the page, so that it is no longer neccs-
indicated the rule number printed on
that page, so that it is no longer ne
cessary to turn back or forth to ascer
tain which rule is being read.
The first new feature is that the
rules became effective Nov. 1, 1904.
This settled a fixed time for everywhere
and did not leave it open for teams to
play old Ule3 because "they did not
have the new book and there is noth
ing in the rules saying when they be
come effective," In referring to the
basket, the word "basket" is not used
in contradiction to "goal."
The minimum size of playing space
(2,400 square feet) is omitted in rule 1.
section 1. Rule 3, section 1, requires
a background of wood at least three
quarters of an inch thick for the bas
kets. Screens are no longer permitted.
The paying of the officials expenses in
serial championship games is no longer
mandatory.
An important change in rule 11, sec
tion 10. prohibits more than one player
of each team from tackling the ball at
the same time. A "dribble" is now
only counted such when the player ad
vances more than two steps wtiile roll-ing or bouncing the ball.
The rule that in a dribble both hands
shall not be used simultaneously more
than once is still effective. Under rule
11, section 17, a man is not out of
bounds if only one foot is outside.
Players may be changed at any time
during the game (new rule 1, section
26). Last year's rules as well as the
new rules authorizes the referee to
award one point to the man fouled by
an opponent while trying for goal.
There was some doubt formerly as to
whether the team whose player was
fouled should also have a free throw
for goal.
The uew rules add that "this shall
noi interfere with a free throw for goal
from foul line," thus making It pos
sible to secure four points on this olio
play, if while being fouled the player
throws the goal, two points are scored,
oue point is awarded by the nfere
aud the ilayer is allowed an additional
free throw for the foul giving him uu
opiiortunity of scoring one point moro
if he throws the foul goal.
Under the old rules if a player threw
for goal from outside and missed thu
basket the ball went to the center,
while under the new rules the ball con
tinues to play. r
Under rule 12, section 1 and 4. tho
referee is required to promptly dis
qualify any player using profane or
abusive language.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.198,-0.07,1.395,1.395,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TOO MANY fOijl Fo1ftjj l
IN BASKET BASKETPresent 1 1Present
Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
l
BY ELWOOD S
BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
r
bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
etEd ujxi np
entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
cs
ginger s and In i inn
general Generl makes the thean ui uin
an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
rather than good team work l lluther
luther tem a aacular
tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
I Iblame
or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
fou
opponents opponent much more than is nee
Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
are called caled for holding tripping A
tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
fnc
offenses but tepresnt preSfnt ytm o t
ing i ng a foul on someone somenp Eo V er TV tini tinimen tn
men i touch each other evry fr tltneTj Hme tln
moves an Inch and Vnn l
every timf time timearm 1m 1marm m marm
arm arm gets part way around an uppcEeni I
dead ded wrong and Is spoiling spiing th UPJt gas ga b
gl
loge lee rules rule permit permi a great deal more f
teal moe
dom of play pIn than do the A A f TL TLto i aD
The college dribble rule
colege permitting a
to throw the ball In the th pritn air or roll k i I t tthe
the floor take ta1t any number numbfr of steps stei rol t
catch it and try for or a baskft bkft i i is isone steP M I f JM1 JM1one
one The A A I r rules rul s make it a I dl
for a man to take more than two tw i vl t i
in a dribble In regard resrd t to the therule pror
rule rle a man running at full ful speed p us r rnecessarily l lnecessariy
necessarily necessariy take an extra step spe or orand uj i1 r rand
and his momentum usually usual bring brjn brjnar bringsarm jjr
arm ar in contact contct with wih his opponent L P Pspite
spite of the fact fac that tht the opponet rules rule saylL sy say
lowance Jownce shall shal be made md for a man mancatches r rcatches
catches the ball while whie on the run ru runare f fare Etj Etjcatches e eare
are invariably called caUe If a man eve evemuch t evemuch r
much as takes a small smal extra step stepCauses 1 1much t t tt tCauses
Causes Many Fouls FoulsAnother fra fraAnother
Ie IeAnother
Another rule that causes cU trouble Sa is Iiwhich SMJ bb bbhic
1i
which hic says sas putting puthI one ant or both bothabout i1 if ifthis
about an opponent cnsttutes constitutes arc arcThe a 1
The strIct Interpretton interpretation now OW applir i
apPl
this rule Ie causes c es more fouls tojle tojlew to be bethan bethan
than other and th the
any makfS g gslow 1 1s10w
slow w and uninteresting uninteretng M Mhave Many Tfn rnet g
have been suggested suggeste by different diftrfnt b bbal bat DSL
ball bal authorities authortes and there therp is i no douWt5 doub dOUbfethat
that the next rule book bok will wi show showeffect how howffcct T1 T1effect
effect of this agitation agItaton Manager Managtr OTT OTTT O T
the Crescents suggests that in ordf ordfsave orrf orrfsave r t
save time and in order to maka the post postwon por porwon
won on fouls a less los Important Imprtant fartc fartcdeciding faC faetrdeciding p
deciding a game that a man fouled fouledhe fou1e fouledtry
tr try a tree throw ge from tht the spot on w whe t the
he was fouled arguing arging that there therebe w i I Iplayer f
be no running to a certain lne line th tbx tbxplayer tU
player would have less chance to toa ri ria 1
a free throw that the throws wouW wouWquently woWdquently
wou
quently quenty be long ones one and that this thiswould ts tswould thuwould
would lend a spectacular clement Clement ta tagame Iigame
J
game I do not favor this rule rule bK bKwhen 1wJ b bwhen
when a guard gard was fouled foulEd under IB IBponents b bi bironents
ponents onen1s basket he would ould bfi so far is isMs t this
Ms hI own basket that a successful succesful tt ttwould t ttiitz ttiitzwould 2
would be almost impossible Impslblp an4 an4would ad an anwould f3i 1 1would
would encourage forwards forwads to foul foulguards fou f fguards
guards with impunity impunityNeutral impunityNeutral impunityNeutral
Neutral Men for Officials OfclS OfficMlsThe I IThe
The Canadians Cnadians have a system irtkj irtkjsatisfactory wt0 wt0satisfactory b
satisfactory satsfactory providing the officials officialsneutral oWc iU iUneutral
neutral which is not very ver of ofen often tenths te the OH OHIn t tt ttIn
In Canada the instant a man is A Athe t iit iitthe 1
the referee blows his wnistlP wnlst tM tMkeeper t tI t tkeeper
keeper awards one point to tho oifesei oifeseiteam oKftteam
team and without further delay dela on tb t w wIs Jt JtIs t tis
Is thrown up between the te two B Ilt10opponents i iopponents ot
opponents and the game gae goes on onscheme on onscheme o oscheme
scheme would ould be good with absoBM absoBMneutral abot abotneutrl abeOneutral
neutral neutrl officials oftclals but under this systts systtsan z syltean et
an official was the uner least l ot bit bi partial partialcould partiatlo partiatlocould
to pUO pUOcould
could swing a a close game either vrtft vrtftI m s1lth s1lthI ti
swng
I favor a rule which gmo provides that thatneutral trhp trhpevery thaJb thaJbevery
every match game the oficia officials sh S1ItdS S1ItdSneutral Uls Ulsneutral
neutral men and gme shall sQl be speciflcaDrs speciflcaDrsstructed speccUS specIflcaU3tructed f
structed to use their judgment judget as aswhether 8 83whether
whether or not the foul was wa wasintentIonally comm cr t tintentionally d T TIntentionnlv
intentionally Intentionnlv This I think tink would wuld wouldthe 5T 5Tthe rthe
Tl
the situation sltuat n The T1e trouble doesnt doet doesntmuch t tmuch 1 n nmuch
much in tho rules themselves themselvCB nUb alt nUbsome r rsome 11 11some
some of them th m are too tight tght bat ba in I1ttl I1ttlpresent 11 11present t tt ttpresent
present close interpretation Interpretaton and a andgeneral it itgeneral r rgeneral
general rule rlo cose was a inserted allowing aUowmgclals e eCJUIS Ccials
clals CJUIS a a ltte little 11LUW more 1UUIO use not u of thfir their fcii ii iiment own 3 3ment
ment and providing always that OW tHJi tHJiabsolutely thtf thtfabsolutely
absolutely h neutral neutrl men the game gamebe TT TTwithout
absolut be greaty greatly ben bencfited fited I It Is impos imposplay 1mposshb 1mposshbplay go r
play a gae game as fast a as bket baskethd1 baskethd1In
in such 3 a Umled limited space 2f as 0 a gn gnwithout gynin gyninwithout
without having scores score of foulsfinato1 foulsfinato1der touls mflI mflIder
der the strict stict interpretation Interretion of mht tha thaUUl t a abut r r rbut
officials would refrain fm fromIng
but UUl 11 It uUbiaio oficials refrn w III 1 1Ing
ing fouls which in iio io o way IirJurtv IirJurtvchances h1u in1urO in1urOchances
chances for either team tem for scoriTig Bcong Bcongwould scofl8would w5 w5would
would bo dono to elmnate eliminate toul troublBASEBAIATHIII trouble trouble</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1907-02-24/ed-1/?sp=30&amp;q=College+Athletes+William+Lush+Basket+Base+Ball+Sport+Game+Basketball</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CoIIprs banket ball being a Sme that
tin coma to atay. It la only tha part of
araclouaneaa to take tba pm at tba valu
ation that baa been put upon It bjr moat
tollps rnen and admit that tbera ara rea
son for Ita popularity. Only a while ago
It was very much the fashion to sneer at
the same and say thnt it was a girl s
game and tha like. A short view of a fast
fame of basket ball Is enough to convlnoe
anyone that, whatever else it may be, it
Is not a girl s game when college men
ylay It.
The aonr.twhat tardy recognition of the
endurance and speed giving qualities of
the game by college coaches now la be
ginning to arrive. Man who looked at the
game once with fear because It w.n lm
jf adding another to what they cmlclred
too large a list of aporta now ara this
to sea that It has its place In the winter
eaaon for helping to develop men for
the spring outdoor cimpaVn In many
porta.
Billy Lnsh mm Basket Ball.
For a general all round eulogy of the
game It would be linrJe to find anything
more complete than tho utterances of
William Iiush, the former Cleveland baae
ball player, who la In charge cf the base
ball team at Tale. It covers the subject
ao well that It la worth wnile quoting at
length. Bomeone waa talking to Luah out
In Bt. Paul when 'he Title basket ball
team waa there awhile fro nnd thla Is what
the baae ball coach bad to aay about basket
ball:
"Of the various bransnes of college sport
that go to fill up tbe interim between rhe
foot ball and baae aall naaaom all have
gradually given way before basket ball
until It now atanda as the most popular
winter sport among the colleges aa well
as the most useful and benoflclal, both for
men who are training for one of tha major
sports and for those whose sole r art ..In
college athletics la plav.d on the gym
nasium floor In thla branch.
"For ten yeara or more It haa been
growing gradually in college favor and
even without the forward pasa of the foot
ball field to throw it Into still brighter
relief the game was sure to win Its way
on the merits of Its play. The qualities It
demands and those It develops were enough
In themselves to Insure ultimata favor, but
the play of the last few yeara in the Inter
collegiate banket ball league, together with
the audden prominence which the grafting
of ita forward pass on the fot ball tulea
has given It, placea basket ball far ahead
of the position It held In former yenra
and gives an added Importance to the play
of thla aeason, both Inside and outside the
league.
What It Develops.
"Among tha qualities developed In the
men who take It up seriously are coolness,
decision, auppleneas, activity and team
play. Weight, height and auperlor strength
are advantageous, but with the exception
of the center position, where height Is a
requisite, there is no special premium put
upon any of theae qualities. Speed and
agility are the qualities most desirable.
After them come endurance and the ability
to submerge self In order to play for and
with the team. The new man at the game
Is apt to be 'all nerves.' He passes too
quickly, worka too hard, and when he gets
a chance to shoot for a goal he Invariably
doea It too quickly, with tbe result that his
try misses, where an Instant's hesitation
for poise and aim would have converted
bis worthless try Into a valuable goal.
"It Is disconcerting to know that one
man on the other team Is specially placed
to guard' him and the knowledge that he
Is ever near and trying his utmost to In
tercept the shot gives a green man the
rattles' as quickly as anything could.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-12-11/ed-1/?sp=53&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Popular+Sport+Game</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1915-12-26/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Basket-Ball+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Sport</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Basket-ball Has Made
Great Progress In the
Past Twenty-five Years
Dy JACK HAAS.
The game of basketball originated
oer twenty-five ears ago. It was
Invented to satisfy the need of team
competition under indoor conditions In
which large numbers of relatively
untrained people could take part. The
majority of games that were being
piajed prior to basketball failed to
achieve any great Influence, nor did
they gain any wide popularity
All of our standard games are the
result of a gradual evolution and
have developed because they possess
ed those qualities that appeal strongly
to play or the fighting spirit. The
demands for special skill, speed and
strategy that is required in those who
indulge in baseball and football, are
great factors in the real pleasure and
interest that accompany the playing
or watching of these games, and are
in a large measure responsible for
their development and wide popular
ity. "Until the invention of basket-ball
there was no Indoor game that was
in any way comparable to baseball
and football In these respects. The
need for an Indoor game that could
be used by active, sturdy men was
keenly realized by the faculty of the
Y. M. C. A. Training School at Spring
field, Mass. Dr. James A. Naismlth.
now a member of the Collegiate Basket-ball
Committee, was an Instructor
at this school In 1S91 and undertook
to devise an Indoor game which
should satisfy these general specifica
tions. Basketball In Its first form was very
simple in Its plan and technique. It
was designed to be plajed by as
many as could occupy the playing
space, nine to fifty plaers on each
side.
It soon became apparent that too
many plavers In a gams hindered the
development of team work; so after
a time the number of players on a
team was reduced to nine. A little
later, about 1S94, the number of play
ers on the teams was determined by
the area of the floor on which the
game was played.
For the first year or two, at the
start of the game, the men were lined
up at the opposite ends of the field
and rushed for the ball when it was
tossed by the official Into the middle
of the playing space. This was modi
fled in 1S94 so that the ball was toss
ed up in the middle of the field and
had to be touched, by the center men,
to make the play legal.
In the meantime. In 1891-91, the
good qualities of the game were rec
ognized by Miss Berenson, the direc
tor of physical training at Smith Col
lege, and she Introduced It as a part
of the gymnasium work for girls. In
order to lessen the physical strain,
which was found to be too severe for
girls playing the men's rules, the
floor was divided Into three sections
by lines running across the Held at
right angles to the side lines. The
centers (the girls' teams under these
rules, which are essentially unchanged
today, haye two centers), the two
guards, and the two forwards, are re
stricted to their own sections of the
floor, so that the players in a given
section have an opportunity to get a
breathing spell when the ball Is in
any other part of the field. This de
vice not only made the game less
strenuous but also favored the de
velopment of team play.
It U doubtful If the history af coat-
jt-JVV A,-evi.-
petitlve games contains an example of
more rapid growth than that shown
by basket-ball during the first two
or three years of Its existence. Even
...im. nwwic pjnrau ji iM?cuail ill
the jears immediately following the
civil war was second to this. The
rapidity with which the knowledge of
basket-ball spread throughout the
world was due. first to the fact that
the game was so constituted that it
met in an adequate way the real need
for a vigorous Indoor game, and, sec
ond, the game was developed In an
institution which sent Us students, all
of whom had learned to pla) the
game, to all parts of the world.
The movement which has resulted In
the formal co-operation of the rules
committees representing the Young
Men's Christian Association, the Ama
teur Athletic Union, and the National
Collegiate Association, promises to be
a most valuable Influence In promot
ing the development of the game of
basket-ball along right lines and
should mark the beginning of a new
epoch in the history of the game as a
most desirable and useful indoor
sport.
Basket-ball makes no uncertain de
mands on heart and lungs and on en
durance generally. It develops alert
ness, self-control, skill, i-peed and
team work; and It brings Into action
every part of the body. A good game
of basket-ball arouses Interest and
enthusiasm In both player and specta
tor. Its essential simplicity and the
small amount of inexpensive apparatus
required, taken In connection with Its
other qualifications, make it one of
the most valuable of our competitive
games.
Along about 1900 or a few years be
fore that time, those who had plajed
basket-ball In Phlladelnhln mil v.
York City came to the conclusion that
they could make a little coin for them
selves and the National Professional
League was organized. Their conclu
sion was certainly Instilled for the
national league, now known as the
Eastern League. Is still a successful
organization. The Central, in West
ern Pennsylvania, the Hudson Blver,
the New England, and Peunsjlvanla
State Leagues have been organized in
the last ten years, and from the re
ports received they are very success
ful and are ail drawing capacity
houses. Philadelphia Is the banner
city in turning out good basket-ball
players. It is stated that there are
5.000 boys playing the game In and
about the Quaker City.
The reason for the success of pro
fessional basket-ball is, that the game
is played In a cage and Is just about
50 per cent faster than games that
are played without the net.
In 1907 local amateur players, hav
ing heard of the wonderful success of
professional basket-ball In the north,
jumped the traces and organized the
District League. Nearly every player
of any marked ability became a pro
fessional. It is stated by one who
ought to know, that the league was
a big success financially, and the hall
was packed to overflowing at every
contest.
The league games were played
under Chase's Theater and after the
first season had to be discontinued for
the reason that the owners refused
to rent the hall for basket-ball and
there was not a suitable floor in the
city where the sport could be staged.
Basket-ball in the District since
c .1. C.V.-O

that time has been a dead Issue. Am
ateur leagues have been organized
but had to be abandoned for the rea
son that there was not enough inter
est taken to maintain the sport. This
was partly caused b the very tame
rules under which the amateur game
as played
The game this season Is taking on
new lease of life. Every hall that
can be obtulned Is now being used by
leagues and Independent teams. Under
the new rules. If the are strictly ad
hered In. the game should be much
faster and more cleanly played.
Although the girl's game had been
plaved since
IbSI. not much had been
heard of these contests, especially in
the District, until the organization of
the Ingram Memorial Church girls'
team in the fall of 1910. The game
became greatly advertUed because of
the much-talked-of success of the In-
gram girls who in the season of 1910
II. and in 1913-12 plujed forty-five
games, of whiih fort) -three were vic
tories. The team was conceded the
championship of the South in the
above seasons' having defeated every
team of any note
Goucher College, of Baltimore; Na
tional Park Seminar), at Forest Glen,
Maryland: George Washington Univer
sity and Ingram Church have very
formidable teams, although the In
gram girls are not nearl) as strong
as In the two seasons In which they
won the championship.
There are a half dozen leagues In
the District that are bound to be suc
ceesful. The Mrongest among them is
the Hll-echolastic, pla)lng their games
at the Arcade.
The George Washington "Frat,"
Sunday School. Y. 31. C. A., and Noel
House Leagues have been pla)lng for
some time, and arc having great suc
cess. There are two Important factors in
regard to basket-ball In the District,
that If promoted will make It most
popular. One l. that the officen. of
the Arcade where the best ftoor and
also the greatest seating capacity Is
located, install a cage. The way the
playing floor Is located now at the
Arcade, there Is so much out-of-bound
space that the game Is slowed up con
siderably. By having a cage, the game
will be 50 or 60 per cent faster. The
faster the game, the more enthusiasm
will be created, and a larger attend
ance at the games is assurel.
The second is this, that Georgetown
and Catholic universltyles patch up
their differences by next season, ana
the formation of a District Collegiate
Basket-ball League with Georgetown,
Catholic and George Washington uni
versities. Gallaulet College and two
outside colleges, near by. possibly
Lojola. of Baltimore, and St. John's, of
Annapolis. This would make a mighty
strong organization and the city
would go wild with excitement and
enthusiasm. This matter should be
thought over this season so that
everything will be ready for the next.
"Get together" G. U. and C U. for the
good of all branches of sport.
Want Basketball Major Sport.
Providence. Dec. 25. The resumption
of basketball at Brown University as a
major sport has been a topic of discus
sion and Interest, and 43S undergrad
uates have petitioned the faculty to ap
prove It. but it is not likely that they
will be successful.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78000090/1949-09-23/ed-1/seq-33/#date1=1756&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Basketball+League+league+National&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=national+basketball+league&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE YEAR IN JEWISH SPORTS
One of the most important mergers in the history of American
(ports took place on August 3rd. when the National Basketball
League, long a power in professional basketball, and the three-year
jld Basketball Association of America stopped their warfare and
joined forces to form a new league—the National Basketball Asso
ciation. The guiding genius behind the merger was Maurice Podoloff
jf New Haven, Conn., president of the B. A. A„ whose expert organ
izational work resulted in both leagues getting together. Podoloff,
vrho headed the B. A. A. since its inception, was made president of
the new National Basketball Association.
Podoloff, a man of many and
varied facets, has made his pres
ence felt nationally since his
B.A.A. started professional bask
etball on a major league basis
back in 1946. A hockey mogul
for 20 years, president of a bank,
confidential real estate purchas
ing agent for Yale University and
an avid yachtsman, Podoloff
brought all of these experienceswith him into the complexities
of running a new league. His
talent for organization, his abil
ities to make quick decisive judg
ments have brought him the
plaudits of men who have been
part of the national sports scene
for many years.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1960-02-14/ed-1/seq-113/#date1=1756&amp;index=3&amp;rows=20&amp;words=NBA&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=nba&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024221/1946-02-02/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&amp;index=5&amp;rows=20&amp;words=NBA&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=nba&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88077226/1949-06-27/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&amp;sort=relevance&amp;rows=20&amp;words=NBA&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;index=8&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=nba&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=2</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1961-03-28/ed-1/seq-17/#date1=1756&amp;index=7&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Basketball+League+National&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=national+basketball+league&amp;y=17&amp;x=12&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NBA Coaches, Owners
Happy With Draft Picks
ST. LOUIS, Mar. 28XAP);— j
The field of senior college I
talenU-chlefly in super-tall i
players was supposed to be
leanest in years at the annual
National Basketball Associa- !
tion draft, but most coaches '
and owners came away smiling. 1
Walt Bellamy, Indiana’s 6- <
foot-11 Olympic player, was the ;
No. 1 choice, and St. Bonaven- !
ture’s 8-foot-5 Tom Stith, a
tremendous offensive player, <
was the second choice, as ex- <
pected. i
Tlie NBA owners started i
reaching into the services, the
amateur ranks and the East- 1
ern pro league, for some >
talented players who won’t be i
under the pressure of their
press clippings when they try
to crack the NBA next season, i
Only 12 rookies made it this
season.
Knicks Get Stith
It was obvious these , “sleep
er” picks were bringing the
smiles yesterday. Chicago, the ;
NBA’s ninth and newest club,
chose Bellamy and was given
the first five choices plus the 1
last one in the second round. .
Coach Jim Pollard seemed i
.
■
Lakers Hoping:
To Take Title i
Tomorrow
ST. LOUIS. Mar. 28 (AP). ‘
The fiery Los Angeles Lakers (
thanks to uncanny Elgin
Baylor have the St. Louis j
Hawks down 3-2 in the West- (
ern finals for the second ]
straight year, but they vow “we j
won’t let ’em up this time.”
’ The Lakers to a man (
remembered they lost the i
series after taking a 3-2 lead <
by winning the fifth game at ]
St. Louis 120-113 last season, j
And they made it clear they 1
were determined to take it all 1
this tjjne, after winning the i
fifth game last night 121-112. I
"We’re going to win it in I
six this time,” said Baylor, 1
whose 47 points and great all- t
around game killed the Hawks. <
Baylor Standout <
Ray Felix, the Lakers 8- 1
foot-11 pivot, pointed at the
still-nervous, sweating Baylor .
and said:
“Look at him —> he’s ready i
to play the sixth game right ]
now.” <
Baylor admitted, "I’m too i
excited to be tired.” 1
The Hawks won the sixth
game on the Lakers’ court last J
year by 21 points, then }
clinched the Western playoff
title of the National Basketball j
Association in the seventh <
game at home.
Fred Schaus, in his first 1 (
season as Laker coach, warned ’
his players "this is an advan- ■
tage- only if we capitalise on ;
lt ” !
Rookie' Jerry West, who |
came to the Lakers with 1
Schaus, his coach at West 1
Virginia, turned in another j
great game with 24 points, i
“I’ve never seen Baylor play !
a better all-around game,” '
Schaus said. "He stole -the ball, i
set up plays, got the big. re- ;
bounds.
“Baylor has had better 1
shooting nights (he hit 17 of 45
shota from the field, 13 of 18 :
frees)—but his ball-hawking, ,
floor play and rebounding ’
made it as goocTan all-around
game as he’s ever played.” 1
Lovellette Lost
Schaus thought the biggest (
factor in the game was that 1
the Lakers “never lost their !
poise, even when they had us
by 18 in the second quarter.” |
The Hawks admitted their :
situation is desperate but the i
regular season Western champs 1
and their coach, Paul Seymour, :
aren’t quitting. '
“We’ve won the big one all ■
year,” Seymour said. “And <
there’s never been a bigger one ;
for us than the sixth game at !
Los Angeles tomorrow night.
“Why —we wouldn’t know j
how to act unless our backs j
were to the wall.”
St. Louis will be without 6-
foot-9 Clyde Lovellette, a great
outside shooter who’s had a
tough series, but is always a
big threat. Big Clyde suffered a
twisted” lower spine and may
have a slipped disc. He is out
for the season.
LOS ABGEL'ES ST. LOUIS
G.FFt, Q.F.Pta.
Barter 1713 47 Pettit 10 S!f
Welt A 524 Hagan 11 426
Hundley 0 2 2 Lovellette 113
Felix 4 716 McCarthy 0 11
Hawkina 42 in Ferrari '! o 1 « ,
La Russo 3 410 Foust 0 ill
Selvy 4 311 SauldakrTl2 123 <
Wilkens ,_8 »,17 ■
. i
This Day in Sporm
■fi
MARCH 28,1989
dhUA'ZaUMMkwKK
LIGHT HEAVYWEIGHT OW, SKILLFULLY
WEJffMEKD MICKEY WALKER’S KAYO
ASSAULT IN THE FIFTH BOUND TO
KTAIN MIS CMWN WITH AlO-WUHD
WCWCOMMiWLEIIIEWBNG.
• Ml If Mew Sra4kat.J>. I
pleased over his picks—four of
them 6-foot-6 or over—and
anxious to “go out and sign
’em up."
The downtrodden New York
Knickerbockers, with the
worst won-lost record in the
NBA, picked Stith, tagged “the
closest to Elgin Baylor I’ve
seen,” by Knicks President Ned
Irish.
But the Knicks* first five
choices included not one man
over 8-foot-5, despite Irish’s
earlier statements that his
club needed a giant in the
worst way, Irish once threat
ened to pul} the Knicks out of
the NBA unless given a chance
at Bellamy.
Some friction seems certain
to develop between the NBA
and the new American Basket
ball League, although NBA
President Maurice Podoloff in
sists owners in both leagues
have assured him there won’t
be.
Syracuse was happy with its
first four picks—all little-pub
licized players in the 6-foot-6
to 6-foot-7 category and headed
by Ben Warley, ex-Tennessee
A&amp;I star, who played last sea
son with Cleveland in the ama
teur National Basketball League. 1
(Warley is a product of Wash
ington’s Phelps Vocational
School.)
But Cleveland picked the
1 same day as the NBA draft to
'turn professional and move into
the new ABL. This might
knock out the Nats* No. 1 choice.
Bellamy has been drafted by
the Chicago entry in the ABL.
Cincinnati Gets Siegfried
. Cincinnati, drafting third
after Chicago and New York,
picked Larry Siegfried, 6-foot-4,1
of Ohio State. This opened the
way for Detroit to draft Ray
Scott, 6-foot-9 and' 235, a vet
eran of three seasons in the pro
Eastern League with Allentown,
Pa., after one year at Portland.
' St. Louis surprised with
6-foot-1 Cleo Hill, a 26-point
scorer from Winston-Salem
College, as its top choice, with
Ron Horan, a 6-foot-7 All-Army
player who was a freshman at
Indiana with Bellamy, the No.
2 pick. NBA champion Boston
went for backline help, taking
6-foot-3 Gary Phillips of Hous
ton and 8-foot-2 Al Butler of
Niagara. Philadelphia’s top pick
was rugged 6-foot-7 Tom Mes
chery of St. Mary’s, Calif. Los
Angeles chose Wayne Yates,
6-foot-8 of Memphis State, as
No. 1.
The draft selections:
CHICAGO—WaIt Bellamy. Indiana:
U, hn , T ur ? e L'. V >uU J Ul f : Jttrl Graves.'
Mississippi State; York Larese. North
Carolina; Dob Kolia, Marquette: Doua
Moe. North Carolina; Jen Cohen, WU
* Mary; Bill Brtdses. Kanaas;
Roter Kaiser. Georsia Tech: Howie
Carl. DePaul; Dave Voss. Tulsa; Ron
Heller. Wichita; John Wessels. Illinois;
Steve Strange. Southern Methodist;
La L r .L., Co JIl e! L Kansas State.
NSW YORK—Tom Stith. St. Bona
venture; Whitey Martin, St. Bonaven
ture: Tony Jackson. St. John's; George
Blaney. Holy Cross; BIU Smith. Sc.
Peter's; Cleveland Buckner, Jackson
State (Miss.l; Donals Butcher. Pike
ville (Ky.l; Cedrie Price, Kansas State;
Charles Bowerman, Wabash: Ron Dibe
llus, Wisconsin State; Kevin Louchery,
St John's; Xarl Schults. California;!
Ned Jennings, Kentucky; Bin Kngessor.
Los Angeles State.
CINCINNATI—Larry Siegfried. Ohio
State; Bob Wleeenh.hn, Cincinnati;
Nordmann. st. Louis; Lowery
Kirk, Memphis State; Rossie Johnson.
Tennessee AJtl; Bob Slobodnlk. Du
quesne; Dave Zeller, Miami (Ohio);
Gerry Thelen. ViUa Madonna; Larry .
Kruger. Ohio University; Jack Waters.
Mississippi; Carl short, Newberry;
George Patterson. Toledo: Clair Mc-
Roberts. Monmouth; Carl Bouldin,
Cincinnati.
DETROIT—Ray Bc«tt. Allentown,
yirglnta.- Bert Fries. Wittenberg; Wal
ter Ward. Hampton Institute: Peter
Baltic. Kent Stkto; Wa ’« Monson.
Northern. Mlchisani Richard Kraft,
Brockpbft (ft. T.i;
WBl ANGELES—Wayne Yates. Mem
phis State: Fred Sawyer, Louisville;
Vrank Burgess. Goniaga: Charles
Henke. Missouri: Bill Liekert. Ken
tucky; Bill McClintock. Californio: Al
Alamanaa. Texas; BUI Ellis. UCLA:
gelos State (acquired from Phlladel
’^A?%M r ‘;w?r U Clavoland
Western Kentucky; Henry Whitney.
sisae rswfiwiinaiSi ’Kft
Chudy. Syracuse; Dick Sammons, Le
moyne.
"PHILADELPHIA Tom Mescheey.
St. Mary'S (Calif.); Ted LuckenblU.
Houston; Jack Egan, St. Joseph's
(Pa.); John Tldwill. Michigan; Bruce
Spragglns. Virginia Union; Diek Goid-
S r £' MUsUiiDOl Southern; Charlie
McNeil. Maryland.
_ ST. LOUIS.— Cleo HIU. Wlaston-
Salem: Ron Horn. Indians; Tom Chil
ton. Eastern Tennessee; Ous Ouydon.
Winston-Salem; Larry Swift. Worth
'll Bt ? u (acquired from
Gray. North Carolina. ABT: Tom
Fassholx. Concordia.(St. Louis): Dick
Kenley. North Carolina; Jackie Craw
ford. Centenary (La ); Howard Stacey.
Louisville.
Di Stefano. North Carolina State; Ned
Twyman. Duquesne; Mel Klein. Aber
deen state (S. Dak.).
Two Terps
Drafted by
NBA Clubs
ST. LOUIS, Mar. 28 '(Spe
cial) .—Two University of Mary
land players and eight Wash
ington selections in the recent
American Basketball Associa
tion draft were among those
tapped in the National Basket
ball Association draft yesterday.
Maryland’s Bob McDonald
was chosen in the sixth round
by St. Louis and Charlie Mc-
Neil, who played with the Terps
last in 1959-80, was Philadel
phia’s sixth pick.
Ben Warley, former Phelps
Vocational School star, was the!
No. 1 selection of the Syracuse
Nationals. Warley, who played
at Tennessee A&amp;I, was with
Cleveland of the amateur Na
tional Basketball League last
season.
Doug Moe of North Carolina
and Roger Kaiser of Georgia
Teeh, the two top choices of
the Washington entry in the
new African League, both
were tapped by the NBA’s newi
I Chicago taaixL
Washington draftees
chosen were John Egan of
Providence, Ho. 2 by Detroit:
Ted Luckenbill of Houston, No.
2 by Philadelphia; Cleo Hill of
Winston Salem, No. 1 by St.
Louis;; , Charles Osborne of
Western Kentucky, by Syra
cuse; Bruce Spraggins of Vir
ginia Union, by Philadelphia,
and Waiter ward- 6f Hampton
Institute, by</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-interpretation-of-dreams</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063952/1893-03-27/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Dream+DREAM+dream+dreamed+dreams+Dreams+DREAMS+Interpretation+interpreter+meaning+means+mind+minded</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DR. TALMAGEON BIBLICAL AND MOD
ERN NARRATIONS OF DREAMS.
Tlie Canon of Revelation llelng RuRIoIent
For Conimon Life, God Very Itarely
Bpeaks to Mnn Today Nevertheless on
Occasion tho Dream Is Employed.
Brooklyn, March 20. A remarkable
eennon was preached by Rov. Dr. Tal
mago in tho Tabernaclo today, tho sub
ject being a psychological and religions
study of the phenomena of tho mind
dnring sleep and tho significance of
dreams as evidence of Immortality. Tho
text chosen was Genesis xsviii, 11, "Ho
took of tho stone3 of that place and put
them for his pillows and lay down in
that place to sleep, and ho dreamed."
Asleep on a pillowcase filled with hens'
feathers it is not strange ono should
have pleasant dreams, but hero is a pil
low of rock, and Jacob with his head on
it, and, lol a dream of angels, two pro
cessions, those coining down the stairs
met by thoso going up tho stairs. It is
the first dream of Bible record. You
may s.iy of a dream that it is nocturnal
fantasia, or that it is tho absurd combina
tion of waking thoughts, and with a
slur of intonation you may say, "It is
only a dream," but God has honored tho
dream by making it tho avenuo through
which again and again ho has marched
upon tho human soul, decided the fate of
nations and changed tho course of the
world's history.
God appeared in a dream to Abime
lech, warning him ngainst an unlawful
marriage: in a dream to Joseph, foretell
ing his coming power under the figuro
of all the sheaves of tho harvest bowing
down to his she.if to tho chief butler,
foretelling his disimprisonment; to the
chief baker, announcing hii decapitation;
to Pharaoh, showing him first tho soven
plenty years and then tho soven famine
struck years, under tho figure of the
soven fat cows devouring tho seven lean
cews: to Solomon, giving him the choice
between wisdom and riches and honer:
to tho warrior, under the figure of a bar
ley cako smiting down a tent, encourag
ing Gideon in his battle against the
Amelekites; to Nebuchadnezzar, under
tho figuro of a broken image and a hown
down tree, foretelling his overthrow of
power; to Joseph of tho Now Testament,
announcing tho birth of Christ in his own
household; to Mary, bidding her fly from
Herodic persecutiens: to Pilate's wife,
warning him not to become complicated
with the judicial overthrow of Christ.
SUFFICIENT IS GIVEN TO ALL.
We all admit that God in ancient
times and under Bible dispensation ad
dressed tho people through dreams. Tho
question now is. Does God appear in our
day and reveal himself through dreams?
That is the question everybody asks, and
that question this morning I shall try to
answer. You ask me if 1 believe in
dreams. My answer is, I do believe in
dreams, but all I have to say will bo un
der five heads.
Remark tho First Tho Scriptures are
so full of revelation from God that if
we get no communication from him in
dreams we ought nevertheless to be sat
isfied. With 20 guidebooks to tell you how
to get to Boston or Pittsburg or London
or Glasgow or Manchester, do you want
a night vision to tell you how to mako
the jouruey? Wo have in this Scripture
full direction in regard to tho journey of
this life and how to get to the celostial
city, and with this grand guidebook,
this magnificent directory, wo ought to
bo satisfied. I have more faith in a de
cision to which I come when I am wide
awake than when I am sound asleep. I
have noticed that thoso who give a great
deal of their time to studying dreams
get their brains addled. They are very
anxious to remember what they dreamed
about the first night they slept in a new
house.
If in their dream they take the hand
bf a corpse, they aro going to die. If
they dream of a garden, it means a sop
ulcher. If somothing turns out accord
ing to a night vision, thoy say: "Well,
I am not surprised. I dreamed it." If
it turns out different from tho night vi
sion, they say, "Well, dreams go by
contraries." In their efforts to put
their dreams into rhythm they put their
waking thoughts into discord. Now,
tho Bible is so full of revelation that wo
ought to bo satisfied if wo get no fur
ther revelation.
THE PEEP SLEEP OF ADAM.
Sound sleep received great honor when
Adnm slept so extraordinarily that the
surgical 'incision which gave him Eve
did not wake him, but there is no such
need for extraordinary slumber now, and
ho who catches an Eve must needs be
wide awakel No need of such a dream
as Jacob had with a ladder against tho
sky, when 10,000 times it had been dem
onstrated that earth and heaven are in
communication. No such dream needed
as that which was given to Abimelech,
warning him against an unlawful mar
riage, when we have tho records of tho
county clerk's office No need of such a
dream as was given to Pharaoh about
tho seven years of famine, for now tho
seasons march in regular procession, and
Bteamer and rail train carry breadstuffs
to everj famine struck nation. No need
of a dream like that which encouraged
Gideon, for all through Christendom it
U announced and acknowledged and dem
onstrated that righteousness sooner or
later will get the victory.
If there should come about a crisis in
your life upon which the Bible does not
seem to bo sufficiently specific, go to God
n prayer, and you will get especial direc
tion. I have more faith 09 times out of
100 in directions given you with the
Bible in your lap and yonr thoughts up
lifted in prayer to God than in all the
Information you will get unconscious on
your pillow.
lean very easily undn stand why tho
Babylonians and the Egyptians, with no
Bible, should put so much stress on
dreams, and the Chinese, in their holy
book, Chow King, should think their
emperor get W directions through
dree frost God, aad tfct Bom
Umld think tut!! m
Jovo, and that m ancient times dreami
wore classified Into a science But why
do you and I put so much stress upon
dreams when wo have a supernal book
of infinite wisdom on all subjects? Why
should wo harry ourselves with dreamt?
Why should Eddystono and Barnegat
lighthouses question a summer firefly.
PROOF OF IMMORTALITY.
Remark tho Second All dreams havo
an important meaning.
They prove that tho soul is compara
tively independent of the body. Tho
eyes aro closed, tho senses aro dull, the
entire body goes into a lethargy which in
all languages is used as a typo of death,
and then tho soul spreads its wing and
never sleeps. It leaps the Atlantio
ocean and mingles in scenes 3,000 miles
away. It travels grpat reaches of timo,
flashes back 80 years, and the octoge
narian is n boy again in his father's
house. If the soul beforo it has entirely
broken its chains of flesh can do all' this,
how far can it leap, what circles can it
cut, when it is fully liberated!
Every dream, whether agreeablo or
harassing, whether sunshiny or tempes
tuous, means so much that rising from
your couch you ought to kneel down and
say: "O God, am I immortal? Whence?
Whithor? Two natures. My soul caged
now what when tho door of tho cago is
opened? If my soul can fly so far in tho
fow hours in which my body is asleep in
the night, how far can it fly when my
body sleeps tho long sleep of the grave?"
Oh, this power to dream, how startling,
how overwhelming! If prepared for tho
after death flight, what an enchantment!
If not prepared for tho after death flight",
what a crushing agony! Immortal! Im
mortal I
Remark tho Third Tho-vast majority
of dreams are merely tho result of dis
turbed physical condition and aro not a
supernatural message.
Job had carbuncles, and ho was scared
in the ight. Ho sajs, "Thou scarest
mo with dreams and terrifiest me with
visions." Solomon had an overwrought
brain, overwrought with public busi
ness, and he suffered from erratic slum
ber, and ho writes in bcclesiastes, "A
dream cometh through tho multitude of
business." Dr. Gregory, in experiment
ing with dreams, found that a bottle of
hot water put to his feet while in slum
ber mado him think that ho was going
up tho hot sides of Mount Etna.
Another morbid physician, experiment
ing with di earns, his feet uncovered
through sleep, thought ho was riding in
an Alpine diligence. But a great many
dreams aro merely narcotic disturbance.
Anything that you seo while under tho
influenco of chloral or brandy or "hash
eesh" or laudanum is not a revelation
from God. Tho learned Do Quincey did
not ascribe to divino communication
what ho saw in sleep, opium saturated:
dreams which ho afterward described in
tho following werds:
"1 was worshiped. I was sacrificed.
I fled from tho wrath of Brahma
through all tho forests of Asia. Vishnu
hated me. Siva laid in wait for me. I
pjimn suddenly unon lsis and Osiris. 1
had dono a deed, they 6aid, th.it made
tho crocodiles tremble. I was buried for j
a thousand years in stone coffins, with
mummies and sphinxes in narrow cham- j
bersat tho heart of eternal pyramids. 1 j
was kissed witu tne cancerous kiss or
crocodiles and lay confounded with un
utterable slimy things &amp;mong wre&amp;thy
and Nilotic mud." Do not mistake nar
cotic disturbance for divino revelation.
DREAMS OF DISEASE OR DRUGS.
But I have to tell you that the majori
ty of dreams aro merely tne penalty of
outraged digestive organs, and you have
no right to mistake the nightmare for
heavenly revelation. Late suppers aro a
warranty deed for bad dreams. Highly
spiced salads at 11 o'clock at night in
stead of opening tho door heavenward
open tho door infernal and diabolical.
You outrage natural law, and you insult
tho God who made those laws. It takes
from three to five hours to digest food,
and you have no right to tax your diges
tive organs in struggle when the rest of
your body is in somnolence. The gen
eral rule is, eat nothing after C o'clock
at night, retire at 10, sleep on your right
side, keep the window open five inches for
ventilation, and other worlds will not dis
turb you much.
By physical maltreatment you take
tho ladder that Jacob saw in his dream
and you lower it to tho netber world, al
lowing tho ascent of the demoniacal.
Dreams aro midnight dyspepsia. An un
regulated desire for something to eat
ruined the race in paradise, and an un
regulated desire for something to eat
keeps it ruined. Tho world during 0,000
years has tried in vain to digest that first
opplo. Tho world will not bo evangel
ized until wo got rid of a dyspeptic Chris
tianity. Healthy people do not want
this cadaverous and sleepy thing that
some people call religion. They want a
religion that lives regularly by day and
sleeps soundly by night.
If through trouble or coming on of
old ago or exhaustion of Christian serv
ice you cannot sleep well, then you may
expect from God "songs In tho night,"
but there are no blessed communica
tions to thoso who willingly surrender to
indigestibles. Napoleon's army at Leip
aio, Dresden and Borodino came near
being destroyed through the disturbed
gastrio juices of its commander. That
is tho way you have lost 6ome of your
battles.
Another remark 1 mako is that our
dreams aro apt to bo merely the echo of
our day thoughts.
I will give you a reclpo for pleasant
dreams: Fill yonr days with elevated
thought and unselfish action, and yonr
dreams will bo 6et to music. If all day
you are gouging ond grasping and avari
cious, in your dreamt you will see gold
that you cannot clutch and bargains in
which you were outshylocked. If dur
ing tho day you are irasciblo and pugna
cious and gunpowaery oi uujxuuu, juu
will at night have battle with enemies in
which they will get tne oesi oi you.
you are all day long in a hurry at nlght
you will dream of rail trains that yon
want to catch while you cannot wot"
one inch toward the depot,
EVI THOUGHTS AKK RVJL DBtUO.
If yea are always oTruspidoua asq
wpactui ot MMilt, to vfll towtt
4 Bk. I
TW '1' "1 T
night hallucinations of uso'iuiua with
daggers drawn. No ono wonders that
Richard HI,ho iniquitous, tho night bo
fore tho battlo of Bosworth Field dreamed
that all thoso whom ho had murdered
stared at him, and that he was torn to
pieces by demons from the pit. The
scholar's dream is a philosophic echo.
Tho poet's dream is a rhythmic echo.
Coleridgo composed hl3 "Kubla Klian"
asloep in a narcotic dream, and waking
up wroto down 800 lines of it. Tarth i.
tho violin player, composed 1.1 inc.
wonderful sonata while asleep in a dream
bo vivid that waking ho easily transferred
it to paper.
Waking thoughts have their echo in
sleoping thoughts. If a man spends his
life in trying to mnko others happy and
is heavenly minded, around his pillow
ho will seo cripples who have got over
thoir crutch and processions of celestial
imperials and hear tho grand march
roll down from drums of heaven over
jasper parapets. Yon aro very apt to
hear in dreams what you hear when you
aro wide awake.
Now, having shown you that having a
Bible wo ought to bo satisfied not get
ting any further communication from
God, and having shown you that all
dreams havo an importantmisslon, since
thoy show tho comparative independence
of the soul from tho body, und having
shown you that tho majority of dreams
aro a result of disturbed physical condi
tion, and having shown you that" our
sleeping thoughts are apt to bo an .echo
of our waking thoughts, I como now to
mv fifth and most important remark,
and that is to say that it is capable of proof
that God does sometimes in'ourday, and
has often since the close of tho Biblo dis
pensation, appeared to people in dreams.
THE PURE IN HEART DREAM AS THEY THINK.
All dreams that make you hotter aro
from God. How do I know it? Is not
God the sourco of all good? It does not
tako a very logical mind to nrguo that
out. Tertullian and Martin Luther be
lieved in dreams. Tho dreams of John
Hubs aro immortal. St. Augustine, the
Christian father, gives us tho fact that a
Carthaginian physician was persuaded
of tho immortality of tho soul by an ar
gument which ho heard in a dream. Tho
night bof ore his assassination tho wif o of
Julius Caesar dreamed that her husband
fell dead across her lap. It is possibloto
prove that God does appear in dreams to
warn, to convert and to savo men.
My friond, a retired sea captain and a
Christian, tells mo that ono night whilo
on tho sea ho dreamed that a ship's crow
were in great suffering. Waking up
from his dream, ho put about tho ship,
tacked in different directions, surprised
everybody on tho vessel thoy thought
he was going crazy sailed on in another
direction hour after hour, and for many
hours until ho came to tho perishing
crew and rescued them and brought
them to New York. Who conducted
that dream? Tho God of tho sea.
In 1003 a vessol went out from Spit
head for the West Indies and ran against
tho ledco of rocks called the Caskets.
Tho vessel went down, but the crow
clambered up on tho Caskets to die of
starvation, as they supposed. But there
was a ship bound for Southampton that
had tho captain's son on board. This
lad twice in ono night dreamed that
there was a crew of sailors dying on the
Caskets. He told his father of his dream.
Tho vessel came down by the Caskets in
time to find and to rescue thoso poor
dying men. Who conducted that dream?
Tho God of tho rocks, tho God of tho sea.
Tho Rev. Dr. Bushnell, in his marvel
ous book entitled "Nature and tho Su
pernatural," gives tho following fact
that ho got from Captain Yount in Cal
ifornia, a fact confirmed by many fam
ilies. Captain Yount dreamed twice
ono night that 150 miles away there was
a company of travelers fast in the snow.
He also saw in tho dream rocks of pecul
iar formation, and telling his dream to
an old hunter tho hunter said, "Why, I
remember those rocks; those rooks ore
in tho Carson Valley pass, 150 miles
away."
Captain Yount, impelled by this
dream, although laughed at by his neigh
bors, gathered men together, took mules
and blankets and started out on tho ex
pedition, traveled 150 miles, saw those
very rocks whioh he had described in his
dream, and finding the suffering ones at
the foot of thoso rocks brought them
back to confirm tho story of Captain
Yount. Who conducted that dream?
Tho God of tho snow, the God of tho
Sierra Nevadas.
HELP BENT BY DREAMS.
God has of ton appeared in dreams to
rescue and comfort. You havo known
people perhaps it is something I state
in your own experience you have seen
peoplo go to sleep with bereavements in
consolable, and they awakenod in per
fect resignation because of what they
had seen in slumber. Dr. Crannago, ono
of tho most remarkable men I over met
remarkable for benovolence and great
philanthropies at Wellington England
showed mo a house where tho Lord had
appeared in a wonderful dream to a poor
woman. The woman was rhonmatic,
sick, poor to tho last point of destitution.
She was waited on and cared for by an
other poor woman, her only attendant.
Word came to her one day that this
poor womaq had died, and the invalid ot
whom I am speaking lay helpless upon
tho couch wondering what wpnld be
come of her. Jn that mood eho fell
Bsloop. In her dreams sho said tho angel
of tho Lord, appeared and took her into
tho open air and pointed in one direc
tion, and there wero mountains of
bread, and pointed in another direction,
and there were mountains, of butter, and
Jn another dlrectlon.and there were moun
tain's of all kinds of worldly supply. The
angel of tho Lord said to her, "Woman,
all theso mountains belong to your Ta
ther, and do you think that he will let
you, hia child, hunger and dle'j"
Dr. Crannage told ine by pome divina
Imnnlso he weutiato that desti tate hose;
saw the suffering there and administered
fa u
gUHfc g gsU
UjjBgJ. 7 J j
that the phantasmagoria of a aiq
brain? o. k w aa all lymfattaUfl
God adurtaf poor wwaa. tkrosgk
irfftfs,
Furthermore 1 have to say that there
aro peoplo in ihi 1 onto who were con
verted to Gol through a dream. Tho
Rov. John Newton, tho famo of whoso
piety fills all Christendom, whllo a prof
ligate sailor on shipboard, In his dream,
thought that a being approached him
and gave him a very beautiful ring and
put it upon his finger and said to him,
"As long as j'ou wear that ring you will
bo prosporod; If you lose that ring, you
will bo ruined."
In tho same dream another personage
appeared, and by a etrango infatuation
persuaded John Newton to throw that
ring overboard, and it sank into tho sea.
Then tho mountains in sight wore full of
fire, and the air was lurid with consum
ing wrath. Whllo John Newton was re
penting of his folly in having thrown
overboard the treasure, another person
age camo through tho droamand told
John Newton ho would plunge into tho
sea and bring tho ring up if ho desired it.
Ho plunged Into the sea and brought
it up and said to John Newton, "Hero
is that gem, but I think I will keep it for
you, lest you lose it again," and John
Newton consented, and all tho fire went
out from the mountains, and all tho
signs of lurid wrath disappeared from
the air, and John Newton said that he
saw in his dream that that valuable gem
was his soul, and that the being who per
suaded him to tljrow it overboard was
eat an, and that the ono who plunged in
and restored that gem, keeping it for
him, was Christ. And that dream makes
ono of tho most; wonderful chapters in
the life of that most wonderful man.
A German was crossing tho Atlantio
ocean, and in his dream ho saw a man
with a handful of white flowers, and ho
was told to follow tho man who hod that
handful of white flowers. The German,
arriving in Now York, wandered into
tho Fulton street prayer mooting, and
Mr. Lamphier whom many of you
know tho great apostlo of prayer meet
ings, that day had given to him a bunch
of tuberoses.
Thoy stood on his desk, and at tho closo
of the religious services ho took tho tube
roses and started homoward, and tho
German followed him, and through an
interpreter told Mr. Lamphier that on
tho sea he had dreamed of a man with a
handful of white flowers and was told
to follow him. Suffice it to say, through
that interview and following Interviews
he became a Christian and is a city mis
sionary preaching tho gospel to his own
countrymon. God in a dieaml
John Hardook, whilo on shipboard,
dreamed ono night that tho day of jndg
ment hod come, and that the roll of the
ship's crew was called, except his own
name, and that theso peoplo, this crew,
were all banished, and in his dream ho
asked tho reador why his oyra name was
omitted, and ho was told it was to givo
him more opportunity for repentance.
He woke up a different man, Ho becamo
illustrious for Christian attainment. If
you do not bellove theso things, then yoq
must discard all testimony and refuso to
accept any kind of authoritative witness.
Godin a dreami
DREAM OF THE JUDGMENT DAY.
Rev. Herbert Mendes was converted to
God through a dream of the last judg
ment, and I doubt if thero is a man or
woman in this houso today that has not
had some dream of that great day of
judgment which shall be tho winding up
of tho world's history. If you havo not
dreamed or it, perhaps tonight you may
dream of that day.
There are enough materials to make a
dream. Enough voices, for there shall
bo tho roaring of tho elements and tho
great earthquake. Enough light for tho
dream, for the world shall blaze. Enough
excitement, for the mountains shall fall,
Enough water, for tho ocean shall roar.
Enough astronomical phenomena, for
the stars shall go out. Enough popula
tions, for all tho races of all the ages
will fall into line of ono of two proces
sions, tho ono ascending and tho other
descending, the one led on by the rider
on tho white horso of etornal victory, the
other led on by Apollyon on tho black
charger of eternal defeat.
The dream comes on me now, and I
see the lightnings from above answering
the volcanic disturbances from beneath,
and 1 hear tho long reverberating thun
ders that shall wake up tho dead, and on
ono sido I seo tho opening of a gate into
scenes golden and amethystine, and on
the other sido I hear iho clanging back
of a gate into bastiles of etornal bond-
ago, and all tho Bona, luting up their crys
tal voices, cry, "Come to judgment!'
and all the voices of tho heaven cry,
"Como to judgment!" and crumbling
mausoleum and Westminster abbeys and
pyramids of tho dead with marble voices
cry, "Como to judgment!"
And tho archangel sclzos an instrn
ment of music which has nover yet been
sounded, an instrument of music that
was made only for ono sound, and thrust
ing that mighty trumpet through the
clouds and turning It this way ho shall
put it to his lip and blow thd long, loud
blast that shall mako tho solid earth
quiver, crying, "Como to judgment!"
Then from this earthly croexnena quit.
Attired in atari wo shall form er slu
III Two Work of Art.
One day the swell nrtibt was passing
tho houso of the younger one, and tLe
lattor called to him, "Mr. I havo
Just finished two pictures entirely differ
ent hi subject und would liho to hayo
your opinion on thorn." The great man
aaid ha wonld bo only too happy to look
at them; so, ushering hjm Into tho house
and opening tho iwrlor, tho owner point
ed, to wp pictures' hanging on tho wall
and said j "Thero they are. One picture
Is of my father copied from an old fash
ioned ambrotype. The other is a paint
ing of Lily Pond."
The artist, after adjusting his eye
glasses and looking carefully at the paint
ings a moment, turned and .akod,
"Which ono did yos aayvra your, fa
tier,' Mr. 'f'-Jioim Globe. V
w.
TVe attane of Milton.' Ktw,
Milton, ii seems, had a Greek noaa la
jrottthj it afterward bepuu auriUalo
i;c). A ha)H of turning it up in mo
SMeta of tadlgauat morality would af
fect tbaooatour aad. fpyyajqp-LtfV
fetordfty IUtUw,
New Interpretation.
In ono of thoUtica schools tho oth
er day the teacher gavo out somo
abbreviations for tho children of a
class to write. Among thorn woro
M. D., B. O. and B. A. When sho
looked over the papers of ono of tho
pupils, sho found that M. D. was prop
erly scheduled "physician," B. O. re
ferred to the period "Before Christ"
and B. A. indicated "Beforo Adam."
Utica Observer.
Every Part of a Tree It Useful.
There are no parts of a tree that
cannot bo utilized for tho benefit of
man or animal and vegetable life,
and neither tho stem nor boughs aro
alike, yet neither can bo said to differ
in many of their characteristics and
tho elements governed by natural
law. Boston Transcript.
Opinion a to Salamander.
As to a salamander, tho ancients
woro divided in opinion, somo aver
ing that he ato tho fire up, the rest
that ho was so cold that ho put the
fire out, eithor of which procedures
was sufficient to meet the circum
stances. London World.
ITITlIIlXXXtX
COMPLETE
MANHOOD
AND HOW TO ATTAIN IT.
At last a medical work that tell the eue.
describes the effects, points the remody. This
Is scientifically the most valuable, artistically
the most beautiful, medical book that has ap-
nn aw na.A tutftrltif.
L u. a..--r .ii....-.l.tn In tint Knmn nf Inn
subject treated aro Nervous Debility, Impo
tenoy, sterility. Development, Varicocele, The
Xverv iVin irJio inwM t-now the Grand Trvth;
Sine nam tiers, iac via orcrwt ana new
coctrtri Mtdical JWrnee at apptltd to Nat
ritd Life, who would atone for patt follln
and itvjtil future rXtfalU. should write for thd
1 w, a- k. rj.
WONDKRFVL LITTLE BOOK.
it will be sent free, under seal, whllo the edl-
H ttnn lasts. If convenient enclose ten cents to
pay postage alone. Address the pubiuhtrs,
ERIE MEDICAL CO.,
BUFFALO, N. Y.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079246/1901-12-06/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=DREAMS+God+interpreter+Talmage&amp;r=-1.179,-0.036,3.359,1.624,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"DREAMS"
Dr. Talmage Says They Arc the Avenue
Through Which God Has Marched
Upon the Human Soul.
Proof of Immortality?Warned by dod.
Washington, D. C.-In this discourse
Dr. Talmage discusses a much talked of
subject, and one in which all are inter?
ested. Thc text is Joel ii, 28: "I will pour
out My spirit upon all flesh. Your old
men shall dream dreams, your young men
shall see visions."
In this photograph of thc millennium
the dream is lifted into great conspicuity.
You may say of a dream that it is a noc?
turnal fantasia, or that it is tho absurd
combination of waking thoughts, and with
a slur of intonation you may say, "It is
only a dream," but God has honored the
dream by making it the avenue through
which again and again He has marched
upon the human soul, decided the fate of
nations, and changed the course of thc
world's history. God appeared in a dream
to Abimelcch, warning him against an un?
lawful marriage; in a dream to Jacob, an?
nouncing by the ladder set against the
sky full of angels, the communication be?
tween earth and heaven; in a dream to
Joseph, fore telling bk comingpower under
the figure of all the sheaves ol the harvest
bowing down to his sheaf; to thc chief
butler, foretelling his disimprisonment; to
the chief baker, announcing his decapita?
tion; to Pharaoh, showing him first the
teven famine struck years, under the
figure of the seven lean cows devouring
the seven fat cows; to Solomon, giving
him the choice between wisdom" and
riches and honor; to a warrior, under the
figure of a barley cake smiting down a
tent, encouraging Gideon in his battle
against the Midianites; to Nebuchadnez?
zar, under the figure of a broken image
and a hewn down tree, foretelling the over?
throw of his power; to Joseph, of the
New Testament, announcing the birth of
Christ in his own household, and again
bidding him fly from Herodic persecutions;
to Pilate's wife, warning him not to be?
come complicated with thc judicial over?
throw of Christ.
We all admit that God in ancient times
and under Bible dispensation addrrssed
the people through dreams. The question
now is. does God appear in our dav tod
reveal Himself throng]] dreams? Thai is
the question everybody ask?, and that
question I will try to answer. You a-k me
if I believe in dreams. My answer is, I
do, but all I have to say will be Under rive
heads.
Remark the First-The Scriptures aro
so full of revelation from God that if we
get no communication from Him in dreams
we ought, nevertheless, to be satisfied.
With twenty guidebooks to tell you how
to get to New York or Pittsburg or Lon?
don or Glasgow or Manchester do yon
want a night vision to tell you how to
make the journey? We have in this
Scripture full direction in regard to the
journey of this life and how to get to thc
celestial city, and with this grand guide?
book, this magnificent directory, wc
ought to be satisfied. I have more faith
in a decision to which I come when 1 am
wide awake than when I am sound asleep.
J have noticed that those who give a great
deal of their time to studying dreams get
their brains addled. They arc very anx?
ious to remember what they dreamed
about the first night they slept in a new
house. If in their dream they take the
hand of a corpse they are going to die.
If they dream of a garden it means a sep?
ulcher. If something turns on*: according
to a night vision, they say: "Well, I am
not surprised; I dreamed it." If it turns
out different from the night vision, they
say. "Well, dreams go by contraries." In
their effort! to put their dreams into
rhythm they put their waking thoughts
into discord. Now, the Bible is so full of
revelation that we ought to bc satisfied
if we get no further revelation.
Sound sleep received great honor when
Adam slept so extraordinarily that the
surgical incision which gave him Eve did
not wake him, but there is no such need
for extraordinary slumber now, and he
who catches an Eve must needs be wide
awake! No need of such a dream as
Jacob had. with a ladder against the sky,
when ten thousand times it has been dem?
onstrated that earth and heaven are in
communication. No such dream needed as
that which was given to Abimelech, warn?
ing him against an unlawful marriage,
when we have the records of the county
clerk's office. No need of such a dream as
was given to Pharoah about the seven
years of famine, for now the seasons
march in regular procession and steamer
and rail train carry breadstuff's to every
famine struck nation. No need of a dream
like that which encouraged Gideon, for all
through Christendom it is announced and
acknowledged and demonstrated that
righteousness sooner or later will get the
victory.
If there should come about a crisis in
your life upon which the Bible does not
seem to be sufficientlv specific go to God
in prayer, and you will get. especial direc?
tion. I have more faith ninety-nine
times out of a hundred in directions given
you with the Bible in your lan and your
thoughts uplifted in prayer to God than in
all the information you will get uncon?
scious on your pillow.
I can very easily understand why the
Babylonians and the Egyptians, with no
Bible, should put so much stress on dreams,
and the Chinese in their holy book, Chow
King, should think their emperor gets his
directions through dreams from God, and
that Homer should think that all dreams
came from Jove, and that in ancient times
dreams were classified into a science, but
why do you and 1 put so much stress upon
dreams when we have a supernal book of
infinite wisdom on all subjects? A\ hy
should we harry ourselves with dreams?
Why should Eddystone and Barm-gat
lighthouses question a summer firefly?
Remark the Second?All dreams have an
important meaning. They prove that the
soul is comparatively independent of the
bo.lv. The eyes are closed, the senses arc
dull, the entire body goes into a lethargy
which in all languages is used as a type of
death, and then the soul spreads its wing
and never sleeps. It leaps the .A flan tie
Ocean and mingles in scenes 3000 miles
away, lt travels great reaches of time,
flashes bark eighty years, and the octoge?
narian is a hov again in his father's house.
If the soul before it has entirely broken ifs
chain of flesh can do all this, now far can
it leap, what circles can it cut when it is
fully liberated? Every dream, whether
agreeable or harassing, whether sunshiny
or tempestuous, means so much that, ris?
ing from your couch, you ought to kneel
down and sav: "0 God. am I immortal?
Whence? Whither? Two natures. My
soul caged now?what when the door of
the cage is opened? If my soul can fly so
far in the few hours in which my body is
asleep in the night, how far can it fly
when my body sleeps the long sleep of the
grave?" Oh," this power to dream, how
startling, how overwhelming! Immortal!
immortal!
Remark the Third?The vast majority
of dreams are merely thc result of dis?
turbed physicial condition, and are not a
supernatural message. Job had carbuncles
and he was scared in the night. He says.
"Thou searest me with dreams and terri
fiest me with visions." Solomon had an
overwrought brain, overwrought with pub?
lic business, and he suffered from erratic
slumber, and he writes in Ecclesiastes,
"A dream cometh through the multitude
of business." Dr. Gregory, in experiment?
ing with dreams, found that a bottle of
hot water put to his feet while in slumber
made him think he was going up the hot
sides of Mount Etna. Another morbid
physician, experimenting with dreams, his
feet uncovered through sleep, thought he
was riding in an Alpine diligence. But a
great many dreams are merely narcotic
disturbance. Anything that vou see while
under the influence of chloral or brandy
or hasheesh or laudanum is not a revela?
tion from God.
The learned De Quincey did not ascribe
to divine communication what he saw in
s.eep, opium saturated, dreams which he
afterward described in the following
words: "J was worshiped, I waa sacri?
ficed, I fled from the wrath of Brahma,
through all the forest* of Asia. Vishnu
hated me. See va laid in wait for me. I
came suddenly upon brie and Osiris. I had
done a deed, they said, that made the
crocodiles tremble. I wits buried for ti
thousand years in stone coffins, with mum?
mies and sphinxes in narrow chambers at
the heart of eternal pyramids. I waa
kissed with the cancerous k_a of croco?
diles a^ad loy oonfotuaded with Qmrttarabk I
_tm_. thmfifc amon'l wreaths ana 'Nilotic
mud"."-?
Do not mistake narcotic disturbance for
divine revelation. But I have to tell you
that the majority of the dreams are mere?
ly the penalty of outraged digestive or?
gans, and you have no right to mistake
the nightmare for heavenly revelation.
Late suppers are a warranty deed for bad
dreams. Highly spiced salads at ll o'clock
at night, instead of opening the door
heavenward, open the door infernal and
diabolical. You outrage natural law, and
vou insult thc God who made those laws,
lt takes from three to five hours to digest
food, and you have no right to keep your
digestive organs in struggle when the rest
of your body is in somnolence. The gen?
eral rule is eat nothing after 6 o'clock at
night, retire at 10, sleep on your right
.'ide. kara fhn window open five inches for
ventilation, and other worms will not dis"
hub you much. By physical maltreatment
vou take the ladder that Jacob saw in his
dream, and yen lower it to the nether
world, allowing the ascent of the demoni
ical. Dreams are midnight dyspepsia. An
unregulated desire for something to eat
ruined the race in paradise, and an unreg?
ulated desire for something to eat keeps it
ruined. The world during 6000 years has
fried in vain to digest that first apple.
The world will not bc evangelized until
we get rid of a dyspeptic Christianity.
Healthy people do not want thc cadaver?
ous and sleepy thing that some people call
religion. They want a religion that lives
regularly by day and sleeps soundly by
night. If through trouble or coming on of
old ago or exhaustion of Christian service
you cannot sleep well, then you may ex?
pect from God "songs in the night," but
there arc no blessed communications to
those who willingly surrender to indigesti?
bles. Napoleon's army at Leipsic. Dres?
den and Borodino came near being de?
stroyed through the disturbed gastric
juices of its commander. That is the way
you have lost some of vour battles.
All dreams that make you better are
from God. How do I know it? Is not
God the source of all good? It does not
take a very logical mind to argue that out.
Tertullian and Martin Luther believed in
dreams. The dreams of John Huss are im?
mortal. St. Augustine, the Christian
father, gives us the fact that a Carthage
nian physician was persuaded of the im?
mortality of the soul ty an argument
which he heard in a dream. The night be?
fore his assassination the wife of Julius
Caesar dreamed that her husband fell
dead across her lap.
Furthermore. I have to say that there
are people who were converted to God
through a dream. The Rev. John New?
ton, the fame of whose piety fills all Chris?
ten,lom. while a profligate sailor on ship?
board, in his dream thought that a being
aoproached him and gave him a very beau?
tiful rins and nut it upon his finger and
said to him: "As long a? you wear that
ring you will be prospered. If yon lose
that ring you trill be ruined." In the same
dream another personage appeared and
1 y a strange infatuation persuaded John
Newton to throw overboard that ring, and
it sank into thc sta. Then the mountains
in sight were full of fire, and the air was
was lurid with consuming wrath. While
John Newton was repenting of his folly in
having thrown overboard tho treasure an?
other personage came through the dream
and told John Newton he would plunge
into the sea and brine that ring up if he
desired it. He plunged into the sea and
brought it up and said to John Newton,
"Herc is that gem, but I think T will keeD
it for you lest you lose it again." And
John Kewton consented, and all the fire
went out from the mountains, and all the
signs of lurid wrath disappeared from the
air. and John Newton said that he saw in
his dream that that valuable gem was his
t..ul, and that the being who persuaded
him to throw it overboard wa" Satan, and
that, the one who plunged in and restored
thar [rem, keeping it for him, was Christ.
And that dream makes one ot the most
wonderful chapters in thc life of that
most wonderful man.
A German was crossing the Atlantic
Ocean, and in his dream he saw a man
with a handful of white flowers, and he
was told to follow thc man who had that
handful of white flowers. The German,
arriving in New York, wandered into the
Fulton street prayer meeting, and Mr.
J.amphier, thc great, apostle of prayer
meetings, that day had given to him a
bunch of tuberoses. They stood on his
desk, and at thc close of the religious ser?
vices he took the tuberoses and started
homeward, and the German followed him
and through an interpreter told Mr. Lam
phier that on thc rca he had dreamed of
a man with a handful of white flowers,
and was told to follow him. Suffice it to
say that through that interview and fol?
lowing interviews he became a Christian
and is a city missionary, preaching the gos?
pel to his own countrymen. God in a
dream!
John Hardonk. while on shipboard,
dreamed one night tha'; the day of judg?
ment had come, and that the roll or the
phip's crew was called except his own
name, and that these people, this crew,
were all banished, and in this dream he
nsked the reader why his own name was
omitted, and he was told it was to give
him more opportunity for repentance. He
u'oke up a different man. He became illus?
trious for Christian attainment. If you
:!o not believe these thinzs, then you must
discard all testimony and refuse to accept
WV kind of authoritative witness. God in
i dream!
Rev. Herbert Mendea was converted to
Mod through a dream of thc last judgment,
md many of rs have had some dream of
that great day of judgment which shall be
I he winding up of the world's history. If
rou have not dreamed of it, perhaps to?
night you may dream of that day. There
are enough, materials to make a dream.
Enough voices, for there shall be the
loaring of the elements and the great
rarthquake. Enough light for the dream,
"or the world shall blaze. Enough excite?
ment, for the mountains shall fall. Enough
Abater, for thc ocean shall rear. Enough
tstronomical phenomena, for the stars
thal] go out. Enough populations, for all
die races of a1! the ages will fall intc linc
>f one of two processions, thc one ascend?
ing ami the other descending, the one led
>n by the rider on the white horse of
Hornill victory, thc other led on by Apol
ivon on the black charger of eternal defeat.
1'he dream comes on mc now, and I sec
the lightnings from above answering tho
rolcamc disturbances from beneath, and
I hear thc long reverberating thunders
that shall wake up the dead, and all thc
Mas, lifting up their crystal voices, cry,
"Come to judgment!" and all the voices of
the heaven cry, "Come to judgment!" and
crumbling mausoleum and Westminster
abbeys and pyramids of the dead with
marble voices cry "Come to judgment!"
And the archangel seizes an instrument of
music that wa.s made only for one 60tind,
and thrusting that mighty instrument
through the clouds r\nd turning it this
way. bc shall put it to his lips and blow
the long, loud blast that shall make thc
solid earth quiver, crying, "Come to judg?
ment!"
Then from this earthly grossness quit,
Attired in stars, we shall forever sit,
[OorrTiabt, aw. l. kiop?-ii.i
Lightning Superstitions.
It is well known that lightning plays
some truly remarkable tricks, and the,
recent thunderstorms in France have
called attention to the different ways
the French peasants have of preserv?
ing themselves from its disastrous ef?
fects. Some, like the ancient Romans,
believe that a skin confers immunity
from lightning, and it is reported that
the peasants of the Cevennee twist the
tast-of! skins of snakes round their
fiats to preserve themselves from dau?
ber. Some believe that silk will do
:iie trick, and the idea that a garment
nade of silk exerts some influence
ipon the matter is rather borne ont hy
t catastrophe which once occurred in
i church at Chatoauneuf-les^Moutlew,
when two out of three priests who
were officiating at the altar were se?</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-09-21/ed-1/?sp=18&amp;q=dream+dreamed+dreaming+Dreams+dreams+interpretation+interpreted+mean+means+mind</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Scientists Say Dreams Are True
———-IHE gypsies after all are right
T Dreams are true. A new
dream book is out—not by a
gypsy, but by a scrupulous
blue-stocking professor. To
be sure, the gay granddames
have always held their dreams to be true,
and have always interpreted their eerie
visions of the night into future events of
colossal moment. So, too, the romantic
lassies in search of signs of lovers, and
here and there some masculine rhap
sodist, who warmed to the world of the
unreal and fanciful.
But not so the scientific wise men. They
have always known better—until now.
Now there arp certain seers at the van
of the enlightened who say that physiol
ogy tells them that dreams reveal the
fato of the dreamer, and that if the
drramer's physician is a clever fortune
teller he will learn much to his own edi
fication concerning the dreamer's bodily
state through their interpretation.
MM. N. Vaschide and H. Pieron of the
Paris institute are two leading expon
ents of the value of dreams in diagnosing
physical disorders, and havo collected
from here, there and everywhere, of all
times, not omitting the all convincing
pn s.^nt day, illustrations and data >vhich
go to establish the accuracy of their po
sition in a way not known to the igno
minious gypsy.
This is their idea: In sleep the mind fi,r
sakes the outer world and yields itself to
introspection. During our waking mo
ments the external sensations prevail. The
brain is preoccupied with what occurs
out side the body and, unless there be im
portunate calls from internal 6ouvc.ee,
pays no attention to what is happening
within. When sleep overtakes us it is
vice versa. The internal organic sensa
tions predominate and occupy the exclus
ive attention of the mind unless external
demands for Its notice become emphatic.
This is why reasoning begun durlag the
course of the day or a problem too intri
cate for the preoccupied brain of waking
hours can be carried on to succassful is
sues in sleep. The brain is not disturbed
with interruption.
For precisely the same reason physical
disorders make themselves known first
while we sleep. We dream of them be
cause they exist, albeit In too rudimentary
and unobtrusive a state to thrust them
serves upon the notice of the brain while
it is occupied with external Interests.
Sometimes there is a warning pain be
fore the dream occurs. The dream fol
lows along the direction indicated by the
pain. If the pain is in the head the dream
will be about the head, If the pain is in
the foot the dream will be also.
Dreams are chiefly of three kinds, those
which reveal the temperament of the
dreamer, those which prognosticate dis
ease, and those which are symptomatlo
of a disease.
People with Bcanguine temperaments
dream about songs, dances, feasts, merry
making, fights, games. Thote of a melan
choly temperament dream of ghosts, stud-
ious solitude, death. Those of phlegmatio
temperament dream of white phantoms,
water humid places. The bilious dream
of dark bodies, assassinations, incendiar
ies, and the like.
In order to arrive at prognostications
by means of dreams it is necessary chat
the dreamer do not normally dream dur
ing deep sleep. The dream itself l.hen
marks a physical derangement.
In convalescence dreams about eatin?
and drinking and enjoyments of the
pleasures of the table augur well. At the
beginning of the disease, particularly be a fever, eating and drinking express
less favorable omens.
Dreams of gayety signify healthy con
dtions, dreams of tranquility are favor
able. Dreams of baths or of cold water
foretell critical perspirations. Fiery ser
pents in dreams indicate hemorrhages.
Dreams of combats or agitations of
various descriptions when occurring at
the inception of a fever predict prolonged
Illness. Violent pains, if not due to *x
terior causes, are signs^if lesion, inflam
mation, or gangrene in some form.
Mountains in abrupt precipies or 'nex
tricable forests in dreams indicate disor
dered livers. Fire is the ill omen of
anaemia.
Anxiety in dreams is a sign of heart af
fections. Dreams of overexertion and ex
haustion prognosticate hysteria.
Nightmares In the beginning of the
night indicate cerebral affections; in the
middle of the night they mean bad indi
gestion.
Dreams of gustatory enjoyments indi
cate digestive affections. Fatiguing, suf
focating dreams indicate dropsy of the
chest.
Terrifying dreams and hideous pictures
show gastric affections.
Floods, swamps and ponds mean cere
bral disorders. Fear and anguish denote
faulty circulation.
Nightmares with repulsive animals, Ilka
rats, serpents and reptiles, Indicate suf
fering from alcoholism.
Nightmares also precede asthma. Short,
frightful dreams of the nightmare genus
foretell certain heart disturbances.
Veritable romances, sometimes contin
ued from one night to the next, are fore
runners of hysteria and characteristic of
people suffering from hysteria.
The children of alcoholists always sea
animals In their dreams, such as cats,
dogs, horses, lions or other frightful
beasts of prey, although generally the
sort of animals with which they are moat
familiar.
Obstructions of all kinds are omens of
certain varieties of dropsy.
When dreams are repeated several
nights In succession they are certain
signs of physical disorders and should ba
related to the physician, who, if he un
derstands diagnosis through the interpre
tation of dreams, can be materially as*
Blsted thereby in arriving at the correct
conclusion regarding the malady affecting
the dreamer-
Sometimes dreams are helpful where
nothing else will avail In reaching the
seat of the trouble. One old woman re
peatedly dreamed that she had to swal
low nails and asphalt, which were given
her for the purpose.. A month later sne
developed an aggravated case of dyspep
sia. v-
A man apparently sound of lealilv
dreams night after night of assaults upon
•himself by burglars, who slash him across
the chest with knives. He-soes to his
physician and narrates his dreams, and
wants a cure for insomnia. Aneurism of
the aorta is discovered. A woman divan: s
repeatedly that she is surrounded by,
flames. The physician, without hesita-
T tion, r diagnoses.her case as cardiac trou
bles.
At times a subject dreams of fits 'and 0
wakes to find himself an »pt!c.
A young girl dreamed that she .was sur
rounded by menacing men on a pt.i.Hc.
thoroughfare. Several nights in succes
sion the dream is repeated. A numbc-r of
days later she ascends! the staircase and
finds herself taken with an attack of para
phlegia.
Other dreams predict .progressive soft
ening: of the brain* it?
Conrad Gessner, German scholar
dreamed that ho was bitten i y a serpent.
In five hours he had poisono-.n blood af
fections in the plaj^ thaipent bit him.
Another scholar dreamed that he was
bitten by a mad dog in the left foot. Soon
after he discovered to.it in his left foot
there was an ulcerated can:er.
'J A man dreamed he was playing in
water, and was found to have a dropsy
head.
One man dreamed that he had a leg of
stone. He soon after had paralysis of
"that member. Z.)
A man died of apoplexy three days
after dreaming that he had. it. A man
dreamed that he had embarked on a ship
with a captain who entered upon a violent'
discussion with him. They landed on a
desert island and there fought a duel. He
was struck on the same place a number
of times. A few days later her had neu
ralgia at the spot where he had received
the blows.
A physician went to Egypt to study
diseases of the eye, returned home, end
ten years later the scenes of his Egyptian
researches returned to him persistently in
dreams. It was found that his eyes were
affected by some disorder.
I Such faith in dreams has one of the ex
ponents of dream fictions as data for
diagnosis that he says: "Tell me what
you dream and I will tell you what youl
are.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93067634/1903-04-02/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=dream+dreamed+DREAMS+Dreams+dreams+Pieron</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DREAMS AND
USUALLY THEY S
WRONG WITH TI
K,sKiU gypsies, after all, are right
I)realils tire true. A nev
dream book is out-not by i
gypsy, blut by a scrupuloul
1lue stoekhng professo'. 'o be sur
the gray graltlales have always heb
their ireais to be true, and have al
ways interpreted their eerie visions 0:
the night into future events of colossa
moment. So, too, the romantle lassie:
in search of sigr.s of lovers, and here
and there some masculine rhapsodist
who warm(e to the world of the un
real and fanciful. But Mot to the selen
tifle wise men. They have alway:
known better-untii now.
Now there are certain seers at th
van of the enlightened who say tha1
physiology tells them that ireamls re
veal the fate of the dreanier, tnmd thiu
if the dreatier's lphysieiun is ia clevei
fortune teller he will learn much t<
his ediatlation concerning ile tlretnm
er's bodily state throut;h their interpre
tit ttu,.
MM. N. Vaschllde auitd II. Pieron, 01
the P.aris lustItute. ne ltwo leading ex
poncnts of the valur of drenlns iii diag
nosuig phyciet isorei'rs, a1nd h;iV
coilected firou here, there and every
whertc, oif all tilues. 11(11. ouittluig the
atll-contvin iing I)es- 0t day iIlust r:i
thons and dlata whieia go to esta,lisli
the anceUrncy of their im:d;tion in a wa
not knoVi to the igno:nminaous gypsy.
This is their ide: In sleep the inil
forsakes the outer world and yields it
s(lf to inltospcction. I)uring our wak
ing nonilts the :t(rnal sensatIin
prcvatii. 'lThe brain isi prcoccupiedl
vitlh what occlirs outside the body,
andie, untless ther"e hie limporttuate ('n li
from internal sources, pa1ys nio attcn
tion to what is hItappelg within.
W'hen sleep overtakes us it is vte
versa. 'T'he internal orga nile sensatlons
predominate and occupy the exclusive
attention of the mIn hd unless externaI
dei Vads for its notice become em
pha ic. '1'lis is why reasoning begun
turing the course or the (lily or a prob
lem) too intrleate for the )reocuplied
brain of w:king hours tan he ('arriel
on to suecessful issues in sleep. 'The
brain is not disturbed with interrup
tion.
For precisely the same reason physi
cal disorders in mike IItem selvcs known
first while we sleep. Ve dream of
them becnuse they exist, albeit in too
rudimentary and unobtrusive a state
to thrust themselves upon the notice
of the brain while It is occupied- with
external Interests. Sometimes there is
a warning )ain before the iream oc
curs. '1'The dream follows along the di
rection ildieated by the pain. If the
pain is in the head the dream will be
about the head; if the pain is in the
foot the dream will be also.
Dreams are chiefly of three kinds
those which reveal the temperament of
the dreamer, those whlch prognosticate
disease, and( those which are symipto
muatle of a.dlisease.
People with sanguine temuperamnents
drea m nhonut songs, dIanees, feasts,
4M1Tymaking. fights, galmmes. Those of
a melancholy teinperamment tdream of
ghosts, stutdious solitude, death. Those
of' phlegmatic tenmeramlent dIreami of
white phantoms, water-. hmumniid plhaces.
Thet hlillOuls drentamn of dairk hodies. as
sassinaztions, incemdiaries and the like.
In ordler to) arrive a? pnrognostications
by mieans of drmeamus 11. 1sinecessary
that the dreamer do niot normally
dreamil tduring dlee!) shcep. Thle direami
it self then amai:s a phlysical Ideman ge
ment. Iln conivalescence dreams about
eatiung and drinukiung and enjldyments of
the pleasures of the table augur well.
At -the beginining of-the dilsease, plartlec
tlarly if It he0 a fever, eating and drink
Dreams of gayety .slgnify healthy coinn
ditlons-; dlreamsii of Iruanin(lIty aire fa
vorable. D)reamis of baths or or cold
wvater foretell c'rIflea:l pierspiruations.
Fiery serpenits in dream liindien(1hte
hemorrhtages. Dreams of combats or
Ilgitationls (If virious deseripltions,when
occurring at -the .inceptlon .of a fever,
predict prolonged~ Iilness, Violent
paIns, If not dueW tol exterior e~nses, are
signs of lesion, ihlananalitioln or gan
grenme in some f'ormin. Mouintalusn In aih
ruipt proeCillee or Inextricable forests
ini dreaimis iniete disordered livers.
Fire is the Ill omen o' aniaemiia.
Anxiety in direams is a sign of' hear-t
aiffectionis. J)reamis of Over-exertion
and e'xihustion prVognostleat 0 hysteria.
Nightmares In thle beginmning of the
night ladle-nte cerebralI affections; in
the middle of the nilght they mien
had digestion. Dreams of gusta
tory (enjoymnents inidlente dIigestive~
affections. Fatiguing. suffocnting
direaims inidente (dropsy of' the chest.
Tr-rfylng (dreamns and hideous p)ite
tures showv gaistrie niffections. Floods,
Itwamips anld ponds( miean cerebral1 1dis1
ordIers. F"ear antd angumishi denote fauil
ty cireulat ion. Nlghtmiares ithm re
pulsive animals, like rats, se'rpents andi
reptiles, inientel suifferIing from aieo
holism. Nightmares also prced(e ast h
ma. Short, figtful dreams of thme
inilghtmar-e genus foretell ceritainm heart
dlisturbances. Veriable rnomainices,
somet-ts conitimned from one night
to the nlext, arc forerunnmers of hysteria
aind characteristic of people suffer~Iin
from hysteria. Tie chmildr-emn oi' nlco
hiolicta always see ainimauls iin theit
.dreamsi-, Ouch as cats, (dogs, hoises,
lionis or other frighitful beasts of prey,
although generally tihe sort of animahd
with whimleh they are most fanmiliar
Obstructions of all kinds are omencis 01
certaini varietIes of dropsy.
When dreams aire repeated severn
nights inm succession they are certair
signs of physical dilsorders, amid shioui(
he related to time phlysileani, who, if i<
-understamnds diagnosis through the In
terpretation of dreams, can be mnate
rially assIsted thereby in arriving a
time correct conclusion regardimng thu
nmolady affecting thme dreamer. Some
times dreams am-e helpful wvhere nothi
lng else will avail in reaching time sea
of the trouble. One old woman repeat
edhy dreamed that she had to swallov
'nails and asphalt, wihichm were givel
ber for the purpose. A month hater i
'developed an aggravated case of 'dyt
pepsia. A man apparentiy sound o
health dreams night after night of as
maults upon himself by burglars, whi
slashm him across the-chest with kinives
fHe gos to his phwatin-n nd narrate
[H EIR MEANING
IGNIFY SOMETHING
IE BODY.
his drearns and( wanta a eure for inso'
nit. Anrtri:iat of the iHora Is (liscOV.
I ('red1. A wolnan dlrc:ims r, l):tt(edly that
3 sli IS surru111(tded y' iantes. ThIe
phlysiiu, wtithot itc heItatIon, thing.
I noses her ense as a :iInc trouble.
At tilues a sulbject dre:ns of lits and(
Swaikes to ii blinhself alu ('ileptle. A
I young girl dreamed that she was sur
rollnI(ld Iy Linenaciig Ien on ia public
tloro!tt;l' r e. Several nights In sue.
cesslon ile dIrenm IS repe t((i. A num
her of (ays liter she ascenis the strir
cas a11(1 lins( hcrself taken with an
s attnck of paraphlegla. Other (r'eamnS
l'Ndi't progressive softening of the
h r)lln, etc.
(:onrad (essner', a Germaln scholar,
(lreamledll t1hat lie 'is bit Ien by n sr
:pent. In live hours lie hlnrl poisonotis
-blood affc"tions In the plate tlie ser
Ipnt hit hi iii. An1other scholar' dreamled
that lie Was liltten by a mad cldog in the
left foot. Soon :fter lie iiis(ove'ecd
that iii his left foot there waUs an ulcer
'lcl caduner. A mian drem:i,iiec lie was
playli'g il w:teir, aund was fotmid to
-h:ivr' it dlrol;sy he:ul. Oni' n:tn the:imedc
Ih:tl it' h:ttl a l' of st n'. I 0 S 01
a+'er hadl lmrtl.vsis of 1h:tl tut'nthicr. A
Ia dlit'd of alli'xy three d:iys after
dre'ainig tihat hit hado it. A in
(!irr d:'l that he h:il trnhl:irLet1 (nit a
shtip) Wi' i t': ihn w,ho cniterctd upton
:1 violt':t d :li,e .i sion w ith hi;ii. 'I-ii y
lutlt'd on a (!t t'rt isl:tci :incl ihcrc
foui;ht a tltel. Ilc' was stru-k on the
i''in e pliate L ntiniiuher of tilnes. A few
(ays l;ter he had lui(l:ini:t at the spot
where he hil receiv(dl thue bltows.
A ptysiliI Wntlt to Egypt tto sitidy
(1Isc:aSes of the eye, rcturnel homne. an11d
teii years i tcr Ilite secies of his Egyp
tinn resenrehtes ret urnedi to him Persist
cntly In dlrcnms. It was found that his
("yeS Veie affe(t('(d by sontie disorder.
Such faith in drenits hts one of the
expon'ets of darean IiitIons as (ata.
for diagilosls that lie says: "''Tell ie
what you drenm and I will tell you
what you are.))))))))))))))))))))))))))))))))))))</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1910-10-29/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=dream+Dream+DREAMS+dreams+Pieron&amp;r=-0.092,0.202,0.888,0.429,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1911-01-29/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=critical+Freud+psychoanalysis&amp;r=-0.246,0.271,1.1,0.531,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-04-14/ed-1/?sp=48&amp;q=Dreams+dreams+DREAMS+Freud+interpret+Interpret+Interpretation+Interpreted+interpreting+INTERPRETING+psycho-analysis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Interpretation of Dreams.
There is a first stage of fantastlo
exaltation the content of which deals
with the individual's hopes and aspira
tions. The glass vender is in a stato of
euphoria well being; from a or man
he Is suddenly transformed Into a man of
wealth, and his fortune Is rapidly In
creasing. This Is followed by a stage of
dreamlike withdrawal from realty. He
is no longer controlled by logical Judg
ment and reasoning; his fancies there
fore run riot, as it were; everything Is
changed; it is like a dream where time,
space and natural obstacles are absent.
He amasses an enormous fortune and
owns palaces, in brief ho is nn longer
himself,
This Is followed by a very rapid third
stage, which Is dli.tliigulHhsl by a sus
pension of oonsclouHnefto nn absent
mindedness, during whi there nro no
thoughts so to speak, und thn whole
rplsnds Is followed by depreshion ehar
iictertmi by anxiety with its concomitant
ifaantfi-KUitiun, I need hardly buy tint
out hero must havo been depressed on
emerging from his revcry."
In nlmost all cases observed by Dr.
Drill those three stages oould be dis
tinguished, and usually the first stage ii
preceded by a period of craving, as in the
following case, which he cited.
A man who said that was a wearer by
trade complained of strange thoughts
which Interfered with his work. In which
grent concentration of attention la needed,
as much counting has to be done, ttn
consolously he would stop weaving,
forget his work and continue dreaming
until aroused. One of his experiences Is
given in his own words.
"I am working and unoonsoloualy I
begin to think what I would do if I had
I2,ooo, I start a shop and soon earn a
lot of money because I oppress my em
ployees. With the money thus gained
I open a big factory and employ a lot
of greenhorns, whom I force to work
long hours for very little pay. I enlarge
my buines; I have hundreds of people
working for me; I become greater and
greater, when I suddenly find
myself crying becauso I have lost all
my money in Wall Street."
Many more day dreams of tho same
man wero cited. All wore of the same
nature and dealt with wealth or murder.
And all, according to Or. Brill, yiold a
simple explanation under a careful anal
ysis of tho individual's past mental ex
periences. Dreams nro never senseless
Jumbles, but nlwny.s perfect psycholog
ical mechanisms with a definite mean
ing and a wish fulfilment.
Ho goes on to show the necessity In
interpreting dreams of having a knowl
edge of the subject ertendina hiveU intn
Infancy, for many of their components
aro partial impulses which have run
through a definite evolution beginning
j childhood. These impulses, active In
infancy are normally gradually repressed.
leaving only slight traces of their exist
ence; but they are nevertheless the most
prolific source of dream material and of
neurosis.
j or nisiiuicn, no ouoa avtenuoa 10 tne
striking natural qualities in children of I or xrj numbers, the Indian medl
.cruelty nnd exhibitionism, which, whon cln, man dr8(un, hli re.nedu. and not
'7'""m hb ung na
education, form certain reactions Ilka
sympathy and modesty whloh go to
mnka up thn character of the individual.
Hut on no ImpulMi Is entirely suspended
ouo can always find some traces of It
in tho individual's character and in car
,.,in ,nntnl tnt it will h mr,ifi
Whon Ht holnB Dr. BriU oon-
tmit(1 to dUouM m fullnr d8tft
cont ohaDgl)a ln th utttude of soisnos

PICTURESQUE CEREMONIES AT A
Fow foreigners ln India have the privi
lege of witnessing a high caste Hindu
wedding and only special olroumstances
enabled the writer to be present at the
ceremonies described here.
Kuhhodm, tho barber, had arranged
a inarringo between Anandl, only daugh
ter of Dliola Iluksh, a wealthy member
or the Kuhatrlya caste, and Hurindro
Tngoro of the same caste. That Is one
function of barbers in India. Anandl
was not qiilto 10. Surindro was Just
is. Anandl had never soon her future
husband. Xobody had over thought
of asking tho opinion of either of the most
interested parties as to the proposed
marriage.
The house of Dhola Biiksh was built
around a oourt. One side of this en
closure was given up to the women and
children. As soon as the marriage wan
decided on Dhola Iluksh'n entire house
hold, consisting of alout eighty people,
gave ltKilf over to tho liustlo of prepara
tion. I. mil. 's varieties of sweetmeats
and curries had to io made, Then there
wns the daily exch.mgo of presents be
tween thn two families.
Thn exs-riK(i of a Hindu wedding
oomo upon the bride's father, and they
am mi great that a family wtm-M imes Is
mined or impoverished for many yoarn
by tho marriage of a daughter. Tho
next most costly affair is the burial ser
jvievs. Should the head of the family
toward dreams and thn related phenome
non of neurosis or abnormal mental
activity.
Not a Senseless Jumble.
Since the early Greek period," said
he, "numerous theories havo been pro
pounded and entertained in the realms
of religion and of nolonco, but not until
within recent years has investigation
of the dream proceeded on a true psy
chological basts.
"It would lie superfluous and (iiilte
impossible to review the mnny curious
theories held at different epochs in tho
world's history concerning the dream;
suffice it to say that ancients and moderns
differ Tery little in thoir vlows. The
ancient Oreeks believed that the dream
was an inspiration of the gods, that it was
simply a warning or prophecy of things
to oome, and they always gave credence
to It. Kindred thoughts are expressed
In the Bible. Joseph Interpreted all
dreams as a foreboding of tho futtiro
'What Ood is about to do he sheweth
unto Pharaoh,' and al the Scriptures in
form us atsps were immediately taken to
prepare for the approaching famine.
These views have come down to us
trtdltlonally.anddiaregardlngthe numer
ous scientlflo and peoudo-sclentlflo theo
ries we may say that the present popular
belief In dreams differs in no wise from
that of the classical Q reeks and ancient
Egyptians. Every race and religion
still looks upon the dream as something
supernatural and objective, as an in
spiration coming from above, and the
laity still continues to beliove in Its ro-
t tv,. vi. hn.
Midom we hear even of 'dreams coming
true.'
"Modem psychology has oontlnued
the work of the ancient writers and as a
result we have numerous valuable con
tributions to the problem of the dream.
Numerous attempts have been made to
show the relation of the dream to normal
and abnormal life, but so far as I know
no author has solved the problem of the
dream so Ingeniously und successfully
escape bankruptcy whon his daughtor
is married, the eldest son la almost sure
to be ruined whoa he buries his father.
The woman barber, who Is another
great Institution in India, come every
day. For two weeks she bathed Anandl
frequently ln perfumed water. Every
day the girl's hands and feet got an appli
cation of henna. For the last four days
Anandl waa compelled to sit rauoh of
tho time holding a small vessel whloh
looked like u teaspoon with a cover. This
contained the dye with whloh the bride's
eyelids wero being blackened. On the
evening of the wedding day Anandl was
bathed in rose water and her hands and
feet got a lost application of ho,nna.
Bhe was dressed ln a red silk sarree
embroidered with gold and finished with
a golden border at the bottom. Around
her waist were, wound chains of gold,
which were fastened by gorgeous buckles
set with Jewels.
Her arms from tho shoulder to tho
wrist were covered with armlets and
bracelets, Closo under hor throat was
a necklace of pearls, lielow which hung
a dozen or more gold chains, Her ears,
which had iieon prlocod in six places,
had earring of lino workmanship sus
pended from each hole. From who.ro tho
hair mot Urn forehead was hung a fringe
of gold and pearls. On her ankles wore
gold bangles. All of this gold would
have proved a heavy burden to the brids
ns Pror. Freud of Vienna. In developing
his psychology of the psyehoneuroses
Freud found that the dream plays a very
Important part in the psyche (I. e. mental
life) of the Individual.
"Tho dream is not a senseless Jumble,
but a perfect mechanism, and when ana
lyred it Is found to contain the f ulfilmont
of a wish; it always treats of the inmost
thoughts of personality, and for that
reason gives in the best access to the
unconscious. No psycho-analysis Is com
plete, nay possible without the analysis
of dreams. The drenm not only helps
to Interpret symptoms but is often an
invaluable Instrument In diagnosis and
treatment. The causative factors of
many neuroses are extremely vague and
usually unconscious to the patient, and
It is by means of the dream that the under
lying etiological or cuaative factors are
disclosed.
Psychic Censorship.
"In order to understand the mechanism
of dreams It will bo necessary to bear
In mind Freud's conception of repres
sion. To forget h a part of human nature;
thin is so obvious that we never oven stop
to think about it. Yet when wo examine
t he things forgot t on we soon ilnd t hat t here
In n method in forgetting: our forgetting
seems to follow a kind of selection.
It was Freud who first called atten
tion to the motives for forgetting. If
we exclude organic brain disturbances,
we find that we are most apt to forget
painful or disagreeable Impressions. This
forgetting as every one knows is purpose
ful and desired. Tho individual strlvos
The
at all times to rid himself of the unbearable
cither by settling the situation In quee
tion when possible or by dlroctly crowd
ing (t out of his mind. When we meet
with mishaps or failures to whloh we oan
not adequately react, we grieve over
them for a time and then make desperate
efforts to forget them that Is, we repress
them.
Moreovsr. the phantasies whloh are
ooramon to both normal and abnormal
persona may be of a disagreeable nature
or present an unattainable object, and
may therefore be repressed. It often
If she had been obliged to walk, but she
was not.
in another part of the house the gurus
of the two families were laying down
the law to the two fathers-in-law, making
the neoeasary settlements and promises,
'l'h is ceremony, which is tedious and
lasted soveral hours, waa enlivened by
the babus who went among the guests and
sprinkled them with rose water which was
carried in silver vases. Young boys in
gay wedding attire passed from guest to
guest throwing around the neok of eaoh
one a wroath of small white flowers,
Kt ill others glided among the guests of the
higher class off or In g oostly and delicate
perfumes.
Then upon the ears of the guests burst
thn cry, "The bridegroom corneal All
heads were turned to see six little girls
who could not have been over S years
of age bearing lighted torches run through
the oourt and out into the street and
lead Hurindro in.
The bridegroom was seated upon a
rug placed In the centre of the court for
him. While ho was seated on tills rug.
and It was as much as an hour, he was In
structed in his marital rights and duties
by tho family guru,
On the ground, nearly In front of Surin
dro, was a small pan of bright red coals
of sacred fire; and at his side was the
harbor, who waa master of ceremonies
and who from time to Urns blew a trumjfct.
happons that such phantasies aro re
pressed before they are really grasped
by full consciousness. The repressed
material Is pushed into the unoonsolous
and there remains in a dormant state.
Xow and then It is recalled by some asso
ciation but like disturbed ghosts returns
soon to Its resting place.
"In brief, both normal and neurotio
Individuals possess a certain amount
of repression. In tho former this usually
remains inert, manifesting itself only
now and then in psyrhopathologioal
actions or dreams, while in the latter It
forms in addition the symptoms or the
neurosis or psychosis. But no matter
in what form the repression comes to the
surface, whet Her in the form of dreams,
In psychoneurotic symptoms, or in the
utterances or manifestations of the Insane,
it is always so distorted as to be unrec
ognizable to tho individual.
What causes this distortion? When we
examine the literature 'of the past and
present we observe that writers frequently
resort to all sorts of detours, euphemisms
and symbolisms when they wish to ex
press something which would sound either
harsh or objectionable to polite society.
The censor has been established by
society for Its own protection. In the
same way the distortions of the dream
and those apparent in psychotic symptoms
are the work of the psychic censor. This
is a protective mechanism for the good
of the organism."
Three Classes of Dreams.
Without the use of unfamiliar termi
nology Dr. Brill succeeded in giving the
glam vendej&amp; xsbsayi-
I layman a fairly accurate notion of the
components of a dream whloh ha defines
as the manifest and the latent dream
oontenta.
The former.' he goes on to explain,
comprise all the delusive sensory Im
pressions whloh are recalled by the
dreamer on awakening; while the latter
oomprlse the fundamental thoughts of the
dream as they existed before being sub
jected to the distortion of the psychic
oensor. The manifest oon tent of the
dream seemssabsurd and incoherent, but
by psyoho-aaalysls It oaa readily be
HIGH CASTE HINDU
The family guru left the courtyard and
went Into the women's apartments, where
stood the women and children, eaoh
woman with a chuddah drawn tightly
over her face. Then Ave women came ln,
All of them closely veiled and wrapped
In silk sarrees The first was the bride's
mother. On top of her head was a
little tray filled with red hot coals of Are.
Bhe carried a jewelled chatteeof water ln
her hand.
The four other women bore trays loaded
with different kinds of fruit. The women
marched around the bridegroom seven
tlmoB, the mother pouring the water gently
out of the chattee so that it formed a
clrclo around Hurindro. On the soventh
round, when she was standing behind
him, she suddenly threw the tray of burn
ing coals over his head. They glanoed
off his white satin, conical hat and fell
I to his feet in front of htm.
I The mother-ln-law-to-be now loosened
I the tray and removed it from her head.
Turning it upside down on the floor she
stood upon it and with her two hands
I closed together sho touohed the forehead,
lips and chin of her future son-in-law with
oil, plantain and salt. Hho then stepped
oaldo and tho bride was brought In,
A numlxir of symbollo figures had been
chalked upon a board. On top of these
.figures tho brlds was seated and then
carried into the roam by the barber and
bis assistants. Within the circle whloh
Forgotten Things Sometimes Get Past
the Psychic Censor in the Brain
While People Sleep
translated into tho latent thoughts, which
always show the fulfilment of a wish.
In this respect dreams are divided into
three classes:
1. Those which represent an unre-
pressed wish as fulfilled, as seen in the
so-called 'convenience' dream and in
children's dreams. For Instance we often
dream of enjoying cold fresh water after
upper of sardines, olives or otnor salty
food. The thirst incites the dream which
tries to appease the sleeper so as to avoid
disturbance of sleep. A boy of 6 dreams
of finding pennies and nlokels, and on
awakening expresses his disappointment.
3. Those which represent the realisa
tion of a repressed wish in an entirely
concealed form.
8. Those whloh represent the 'realiza
tion of a repressed wish in a form in
sufficiently or only partially concealed:
The last group of dreams is usually ac
companied by fear, which interrupts the
dream and which takes the place of tho
distortion found In the second group."
The interesting process called "dream
work" by which the transformation of
the latent into the manifest content of
the dream Is effected Dr. Brill accounts for
by the following theory:
'During our waking state a number of i
thought structures aro constantly being
formed. This aotlvlty is never finished
during the day and the sum of energy
required for the production of those
thoughts would be sufficient to hold
the Interest of the Individual to such
an extent as to Interfere with sleep.
These day remnants nre therefore
changed Into dreams by the dream
work and the elements threatening
disturbance of sleep are thus removed.
The dream Is therefore the guardian
of sleep. But In order that the work of
the dream may act the day remnants
must be capable of wish formation,
for It Is the wish that forms the nucleus
of the dream.
Relate to the Past.
"We are struck by the marked con
densation which takes place In the
transformation of the thought Into
the content of the dream. This con
densation Is effected by the omission
and the subsequent compression of
syllables, words, pictures or situations
whloh have been present In the thoughts
underlying the dream. And this ac
counts for the many gaps, absurdities
and neologisms In the manifest content
of a dream.
"Another effect of the dream work
Is brought about by the process of dis
placement. Thus the elements which
seem most conaploloua in the content
of the dream do not necessarily havo
corresponding importance in the
thoughts or the dream. An Insignifi
cant element may represent the main
thought. Events, thoughts, sentences,
words and pictures may be turned around.
-Kit
V
had been made by the water the mother
had spilled Anandl waa carried around
Surindro six times. The board was then
lowered from the shoulders that bore it
and the bride was placed at her husband's
feet.
During all this ceremony the bridegroom
had never moved a muscle. The barber
and his assistants now lifted Anandl to
the level of Surlndro's face, underneath a
large sheet whloh had been stretched over
their heads. Tho bride's mother and
another woman, near of Uln mm Ml a1thnt
side of the bridal pair. Each woman held
a light close to the faoe of the bride and
bridegroom and the sarree was removal
from the bride's face.
Anandl covered her faoe with her hands
and sobbed softly; nor could Surindro
master up courage to look at hla partner
for life; but they wero kept ln the same
position for five minutes, while the barber
alternated the hlowln of tli hnrn uv.
wild shrieks, which wero supposed to bring
uown curses upon mo Deads of any who
might speak ill of the bridal pair.
The sheets were then carried away and
ihtk hrl,trnAm wailful Int.. t U
house. Tho barltor nnd his assistants car
irind the bride in Just after her husband.
niinin a circle ehnlked on the floor the
bride and bridegroom worn seated oppo
site oneanother; lietweeon them wasa vaae
lilted with flowers. On this vase the back
of the brldsgroom's hand waa placed, while
To these two processes of condnnsatmn
nnd dlsplHccment tho formation of tho
dream Is chiefly due."
It has nlwnys been the symbolism
of the drenm nnd Its reirlizntion which
makes the appeal to the non-Kclcnilflo
curiosity. According to tho translator
of Freud, "tho symbolism in the drenm
is the same to-day ns It was in Ilihllcal
times whon Joseph noted the part of thn
onelroeooptlst and ns we still see it
in the dream books. Bui whereat
the ancients and thn laity of to-day
Ignore their own subjective mind nnd
seek interpretation from magicians nnd
drenm books, wo allow the droamer tn
interpret his own dreams and to find the
symbolisms In his own mind. What
we do Is simply to oall his attention to
the different connections which lis
himself generally cannot see lecaiM
of his own critique, prejudices and
resistances.
"We also differ from thn ancients and
laity by not seeing ln tho dream thi
future but rather the past. Yet, In a
way, the dream Is alo related to the
future inasmuch as its fulfilled wish repre
sents what we are striving for. This, In
mv nnlnlon. einlalna the ancient nn,l
modern superstition regarding tho future V
realization or dreams. To take another
case which came to my notice and which
shows how there aro dreams which con
tinue to manifest themselves for week
and months until the wish they contain
is actually realized.
His Dream Came True.
"A chronlo alcoholic, showing delusions
of jealousy, disliked a dog because his
wifo 'was more attached to the dog than
to him.' He continued to dream at dif
ferent times that the dog was run over or
taken away by the dog catcher, until on
day during his wife's absence he really
disposed of it. Hem the dream ostensibly
treated of the future, at least, so the wife
thought on her return home.
"Poor Fido,' she exclaimed. 'My hus
band John dreamed only last week that ha
was caught by the dog catchers and now
the dream has come true.'
"This Is the so ml led 'resolution dream.'
The person resolved, perhaps uncon
sciously, to do a certain thing and the
dream continues to represent it as real
ized until It is actually accomplished.
Tills explains the mechanism of the
'dreams that oome true.'
"The realization of our waking dreams,
concluded Dr. Brill, "shows precisely tho
same mechanisms. This con be observed
not only in the individual but in who!
races. Wn all know that the leitmotif
of orthodox Judaism is and always has
been the ret-stahlishment of a Jewish na
tionaiitv, the 'return to Jerusalem,' and
should Zionism over sucoeod in obtain!::
Palestine, tho Biblical dreams, the proplie.
cies. would lie considered as having 'coni'i
true.' Popular language expresses the
idea in the saying, 'Where there is a will
there is a way."
WEDDING
the back of the btlde's hand was placed
in his palm. The two bands were then
bound together with wreaths of flowers,
while In them the marriage fee was plsced-
Each family guru laid down the I."
to the opposing father-in-law; but not
one word was said to the bridal couple.
At the side of the bride's father was a law
dish ft'led with water from the sacred
Ganges, into which he bad dropped a ruby
ring and a thin Iron bracelet. The bracelet
waa given to the bride and the ring to the
hrldogroom, who wero both sprinkled with
somo of the sacred water and the flowers
were thrown at them.
The brldo, still on the plank, was lifts!
and carried, first to the right side of the
room and then to the loft. The sirreei
of the bride and bridegroom were neit
tied together. This mndo them hustund
and wife.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-10-31/ed-1/?sp=82&amp;q=Freud+psychoanalysis+Psychoanalysis</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1922-01-11/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=controversy+criticism+Freud+psychoanalysis+Psychoanalysis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Psychoanalysis
You and Your Mind
By ANDRE TRIDON
oftui unsung In our histories. I Paine know that On. Washington
Die incident given, however, refers 'was a momocr of the first societj in
ll
Judges Hie Irish .iti,-
t,..i f r, jiii the -l i. n of it sung.e ol.
and' noi i their Imown detdn. tco
to Washington, and let us sen some
other tacts cnnrernlng his relations
wi-h fie Irish. I wonder it .Mr. fame
v lint mi Jr'shman was liodv
!n i, and "r,niildential cum sp indent
I saved iuu superior' lifiJ lcea ilr. Uriah (,nUjrants,'
Ameilca to foster the cause of Irish
freedom, the Friendly Sons of 8t.
Pntrlrk In Philadelphia? posnlhly Mr.
r'uuip aim iiiwsu who snare iiih lews
ui.i'x oe enlightened by the words of
Lord Jtountjoy. "America was lost by
L.I r"t Ml. f T T V
No. II. THE SWISS ANALYSTS.
How do Freud and Jung difler in
their contentions on this new science
of psychoanalysis?
Dr. Carl Jung of Zurich, whoso
name was mentioned frequently In the
American press when Mrs. McCor
mlck of Chicago returned to the
United .States after studying under
his direction, is the leader of tbo so
called Swiss school of psyclfoanalysls.
Dr. Jung refuses to consider erotlo
cravings us tho most Important ele
ment In human lit. The "bfc urge,"
which he calls tho "libido" (pro
nounced lpe-tiee-rto, with the accent
on "bee"), Is infinitely bigger than
the "sex urge."
Jung thinks that the Influenco ot
the parents is much more important
In deciding tho children's normality
or abnormality than the children's
erotic development.
He disagrees with Freud as to tha
mrunmg of dreams. To him, dreams
aro not so much a fulfilment of re
pressed wishes as a picture of tho
present situation as tho dreamer real
ly sees it In his unconsciousness. In
other words, tho fantastic visions of
our dreams are a representation of
our present problems dramatized and
thrown on tho screen of our mind la
sleep.
Jung does not attribute mentnl dis
ease to the explosion ot childhood,
cravings long repressed. Tho neu
rotic ailment, ho .tells us, Is due to
the fact that this neurotic finds him
self in a difficulty which he does not
care to solve for himself.
Freud contended that the task of
the analyst simply consisted In mak
ing the patient rea(lze the wishes
which he had been unconsciously re
pressing for years. Jung coi sldora
the analysis as a hlgn moral task of
Immense educational value.
Jung and bis followers treat tho In
sane bv leading them gradually to
seek a resolution of their dif'lcultles
on a higher plane, where pnmltlva
cravings and ethical duties no longer
are in conflict.
Fiend placed tnu cmpnasis on tho
past and on pmo animalism. Jung
stresses tho present nnd our social)</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1922-05-08/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=dreams+Freud+Interpretation+psychoanalysis+Psychoanalysis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"The French women are not
giving as much time and thought
to psychoanalysis as the Ameri
can women," Dr. Goiodiche told
me. "In fact, Americans seein
t have taken this new science
so seriously that I am afraid the
fad' will prove i. moral danger.
And that Is wry 1 wish to, warn
our society vomen, our busi
ness girls and our flappers
against It.
"I do not think I need wain
your American men against
psychoanalysis," continued Dr.
C'.orodlchu with n merry sparkle
in his brown eyes "Your Cap
tains of Industry, of trade, youi
men of action iu the business
world have no time to spend upon
the so-called 'complexes' of
their youth or hUppretsud de
zlies. They are too busy wit i
thi- present to dig Into the past
ami whys and heiefores o'
things which happened long ago.
It is the women, esiM'cially the
society womenl and very young
girls who are delving into these
things and evincing an Interest
and curiosity which may lead to
moral .dauger.
."To the schntlst, psychoan
alysis Is capable of opening up
i he wen Id of the subconscious
and is a form of pscho-therapy.
It l an excellent method of
reaching the subconscious mind
by the Interpretation of dreams.
Ih.it to the layman, the society
woman, the dapper and the
Im.sine.ss girl, it is a science
wlm-h I .ould warn against.
"To many young people this
new science bus served as a
meie piete.xt for licentious men
tal Intercourse, u pseudo scienti
fic shelter for cheap conversa
tions. The flapper and her es
cort think' it smart to discuss
many questions und sex prob
lems under this guise which
should never be mentioned be
tween the sexes. They ure so
fed up on Freud's theo that
all men's dreams and actions
can be traced to sex that they
discuss In a free and frank man
ner subjects which young men
und young women should avoid."
"But, after all. society women
and flappers must have some
thing to think ubout," I Inter
jected. "Isn't It possible that
a KllBht knowledge of the com
plexes ot their childhood und the
suppressed desires will make
them bigger, broader and give
them a better insight t humun
nature?"
Dr. Gorodlcht held up his Land
fad. American
ulo the scientist
psychoanalysis Is enna
hie of opening np the
world of the snbeon
sclqng and In a form of
psycho-therapy."
and Jungitc -Theories
while his shoulders gave a
French shrug of disapproval.
"Psychoanalysis will not help the
society woman, It will not belp
the business girl nnd it ,vlll not
help the younger generation," he
declared emphatically. "It will
simply open the way for cheap
conversation and morbid thoughts.
You cannot expect to get at the
real truths of human aatuie
through so fragile a hypothesis.
Freud's theory that all mankind's
weaknesses, fallings and actions
arc based upon sex complexes and
suppressed desires Is a fragile
statement. 1 do not like to believe
that the baby's persistency to
suck its thumb is his first sexual
ImpiilHe."
'Then do jou not think the study
of the sub-conscious mind neces
sary to the averagu person?"
"Not at all." replied the doctor.
"While the little things we did In
the past may affect our ilves It Is
hardly worth while to sit down
and think about them. It Is much
belter to study tho piesent, to uso
the opportunities we have right ut
hand and find an active occupa
tion In to-day's life, rather than
looking back and digging up old
things.
"Because a boy was denied all v
the jam he wanted from his
mother's cupboaid. or a little girl
was not allowed to go to parties
and play kissing games at thir
teen. Is no reason why they nhould
sit down ten or twenty years
hence nnd see if that incident
termed n "suppttflfced desire"
made a. dilteience in tlrf-lr whole
lives. It is much better for them
to go ahead and live to-day, ac
complishing the woik and doing
the things they want to do and to
push down and bury any sub
conscious feelings.
"The scientist Is the only one
who may really obtain results
from this philosophical doctrine
If a nervous man or woman goes
to him with a series or dieams he
may bo able to shed some light In
to the depths of the subconscious
mind by the Interpolation of
tho.se Uieams. This pruces3 Is
often successful, provided ono
doesn't force or solicit the facts to
reveal to the psychologist the
latent and hidden mechanism at
the loot of which are often our
apparent leactions."
"What about the practical,
cutatlve value of psyclioanalyais
which humanity is more Inter
ested in than the theory Itself?"
1 asked.
"In this psychoanalysis gives
no better or worse results than
those usually obtained by tho or
dinary methods of clinical psycho
therapy," said Dr. Gorodiche.
"But It frequently leads to grave
and serious disappointments. Tho
psychoanalyst, entunglcd by his
own theory and the slave of hla
doctrine (founded on an alto
gether fragile hypothesis) com
pels his nervous, ill-balanced and
anxious patient to accept an
amazingly unexpected and, often
humiliating explanation of his ills.
Instead Of acting as a tonic the
psycho-analtlcal findings of the
practitioner 'tend to depress and
dishearten."
"As a neurologist, how .would
you treat such patients'."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90060762/1901-05-30/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=dream+meaning&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=dream+meaning&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-01-11/ed-1/seq-19/#date1=1756&amp;index=1&amp;rows=20&amp;words=dream+meaning&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=dream+meaning&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066651/1919-12-11/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&amp;index=2&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Dream+MEANING&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=dream+meaning&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-06-09/ed-1/seq-172/#date1=1756&amp;index=7&amp;rows=20&amp;words=dream+dreaming+mean+meaning&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=dream+meaning&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>If you mean the popular dream books, in which there is
a pet explanation for every kind of dream, scientists do not
accept these for anything more than entertainment. They
should not be taken seriously. But scientific dream interpre
tation is an important and controversial phase of the
psychoanalytic school of psychiatry..
It seems quite well established that dreams are condi
tioned, if not caused, by the events of the preceding day, and
by stimuli reaching the brain during sleep. Such stimuli
may come from the digestive tract, the skin, the hearing, the
sex organs, or in terms of pain or discomfort from any
portion of the body.
Even strong light may influence dreaming. But the
meaning of any dream depends on the dreamer, and can
only be interpreted by a trained person.
. Good night. Pleasant dreama. rm bm</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1913-06-08/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&amp;index=19&amp;rows=20&amp;words=dream+meaning&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=dream+meaning&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Now Thought to Cause Our DREAMS
c „ itT? VERY dream Is the luifllment of
JLj some wish. In the great ma
jority of cases the wish is one that'has
been repressed by the waking con
sciousness, and Its fulfilment In the
0 dream is disguised according to rules
that are both complicated and diverse."
L Dr. William Brown, head of the psy
*? chological Department, King's, College.
" University of London, used these words
In expounding Freud's theory of dreams
before the Llsterian Society a few
weeks ago. *
Dreams, according to Freud, are a
a normal function of the mind. ; They
a are made up of memories from the past
° life of the dreamer, especially mem
ories of the day before, which are still
fresh in the mind, and memories of
long-forgotten childhood, which have
been repressed. '
? Memories of the "dream-day"—that
is to say, the day before the dream,
form part of every dream without- ex
ception. Every dream fulfils at least
one wish—the wish to go on sleeping.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-walt-whitman</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030362/1852-03-14/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Walt+Whitman+Adventures+Jack+Engle</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86053516/1856-05-14/ed-1/seq-2/#words=Walt+Whitman+Leaves+Grass+Characters+Character+Book+Trade+Rough+Tumble</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030213/1860-04-24/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Distinctive+Poem+Walt+Whitman+Leaves+Grass</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>F1RBT DISTINCTIVE POEM.
WALT WHITMAN'S
LEAVES OF GRASS.
(Now Complete.)
1?? td r r, >? part ef Con'ent?,
PROTO-LEAF,
CHANTS DEMOCRATIC,
ENFAN8 D'ADAM,
POEM OF JOYS,
ME8?EN(?ER LEAVE?,
CALeMUS.
BO LOiiO,
kt.,kt,
PORTRAIT OF THE POET,
Engraved by St h or?.
LTO BF, READY ABOUT FIRST Or MAT.
In or.? lolume, ?fj i?im, Ihn?., he.t paper, pri?t, sadesecti?
typiag Borten can tura ont.
Price, $1 IS.
TUAYER aT?LDRIDGE,
Publisher?,
Ne. HS Withiagtoiret.,
_Best? w, Mata.
AN INDIAN MAIDEB.
A
AN INDIAN BOY.
HOW THE INDIANS MAKE LOVR.
HOW THB INDIANS M4KE WAR.
?
FIDELITY AND TREACHERY AMONO THE INDIANS.
FOR A TRUE AND 8TARTL1NO BTORY
INDIAN LIFE.
THE NEW-YORK LEDGER.)</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1887-04-15/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Gray+Poet+Walt+Whitman</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Walt Whitman the venoraUo poet rend a
lecture yesterday in the Madison Square Thoa
tro before a large audience The subject was
Abraham Lincoln Yesterday wa tho
Twentysecond anniversary of Lincolns assas
sination It wan a plcturosauo Bight when the
curtain arose and the poet was discovered sit
ting In the middle ot a gorgeous bluo plush and
gilt boudoir scene From the proscenium box
at the loft of the stage oxMlnlster James Bus
sell Lowell and Prof Charles Eliot Norton and
from tho proscenium box on the right Mr B C
Btcdmtm among others saluted the poet on
tho stage Whitman did not rise to his feet
during tho lecture Ills long and flowlngwhlto
hair and beard made a halo around hUfaco
and caused his features brMrned by outof
door walks toVpok tho broivnftr
In collar and cuff Mr Whitman adopted the
most Byronlo style possible ftls looBoflttlng
Mack broadototb coat won unbuttoned and his
figure fell Into cay lines M he loaned ono iirm
on a light stand upholstered in blue plush
and began to read Ills olainBhloneu cane
with a curl at the top waozijbe carpet at his
feet On a chair near Mr Whitman hung u
laurel wreath tied with red whltn and blue rib
bons the gift of Mr Wilson Barrotu
Mr Whitman described the Urn time he Raw
Lliuoln The pool was sitting on an omnibus
In runt of tho Astor llouse when Lincoln came
through Nowiorkon his ivny to Washington
for his first Inauguration Tho i sullen silent
way In which Lincoln was received In Now
York on hut day the vast silent crowds that
thronged Broadway to we him tho way Lin
coln got out of his carriage and untangled hit
long logs in front of the Aster House looked
calmly about him with his stovepipe hut on
the hitch of his heed Mr Whitman descrllwd
no that Ills aUdience could see them In
truth It was comedy almost such farce Mr
Whitman kiild na Bhakespearo puts into his
J blackest tragedy
I With equal vIvidness Mr Whitman plcturod
1 ttu historic scone of thin shooting of Lincoln
by Douili and all through the recital the ntidl
onco was half Inclined to cry at the tragic tale
l and half to laugh at Whitman1 nrhimslcal iitid
passlnnnto ridicule of the play of Our Ameri
cnn Cousin which was on tbottago when
Llncolu was altot
This with regard to Lincoln had its sequel
The lilacs wore In full bloom in the place where I was
when the news of Itncotn0 assassination rrathtd rue
and I lied myself remlndtd ot that day at the sight or
odor nt lilacs
At thin conclusion of the lecture just as the
last accent of the old mans musical olco fell
from his lips Mr E C 8k > dman8 tloyeurohl
granddaughter Laura tripped upon the stage
from thojlKht upper entrance twisting a bas
ket fllled with cut liliws The poet loojiwl around
in surprise fumbled the flowers and ended by
kissing the lIttle one twice hcBrtlundornoath
her NormimdvcBP The entertainment netted
nearly t20 In thn evening Mr Whitman held
a rcgcptlon seated in a big chnlr in tho private
parlors uf the Westminster Hotel
THE AXOtlCAX SChOOL AT AT11EX8
A JBsmsjaet s > t < ne Hotel Brnwiwlck to Cele
brate It EatabllthnseDt
Paintings ol famous Grecian ruins decked
tho walls of the Hotel Brunswick banquet hall
In which a hundred college professorsand well
known citizens gathered last night to cat the
big modern dinner that was spread In com
memoration of the establishment in Athens of
tho American School of Classical Studies
George William Curtis presided beneath
Churchs costly painting of the Athenian Par
thenon Tho painting was lent by Mr Morris
K > 7e Min to indicate his Interest in the clas
sic institution that educated Americans intend
to maintain on Grecian soil
About tile Chairman were grouped these
Professors and laymen who have lent the
school their enthusiastic support ExMintit
tor Andrew D White Dr Provost of the Ienn
sjlvanln University Howard Crosby Prot
Brown of the Theological University Prof
Harkuessf Hrown University Prof Van Ben
schotten of Wesleyan Profs Charles Norton
and Goodwin of Harvard Imf Heymour of
Yale Profs Duster Merrimon uittl Iirislor of
Columbia Prof Sloano of Princeton Prof
Hut of Cornell Prof Baird of the University
of Now York nod Prof Tibduli of the College
of the City of New York
Beside Chairman Curtis sat Dr Jamsut lIes
seil Lowell and Dr Charles Waldstein the di
rector of the Fitzwilliiim Museum of Cam
bridge England a young American archipolo
gist whom the American patrons of the Athens
school have united to become its permanent
director nnd who ha accepted the proffered
appointment upon tho condition that the school
shall bo adequately endowed
The menu of the dinner was decorated with
woodcuts of the American school which show
It tO t IK uspaciousthreestoryediflcoof lireclnn
architecture It stands upon a hill near the
Aeropolis a fitting companion of the schools
which the French English and Ciermun Gov
ernments have already established in Athens
Mr Curtis and Mr Lowell made earnest ap
pmiU to generous New Yorkers to contribute to
the thorough arcluivtlogieal equipment of the
new school and Dr Waldstelii and Prof
Charles Norton spoko of the vast bcnnllt which
ito school would exert in spreading clns
ideal education in America Tlie school would
repif ° nl the test aud highest thought of the
people and would but t credit to thin advanced
civilization of the American nation</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1889-05-31/ed-1/seq-2/#words=Walt+Whitman+Whitmans+Seventieth+Birthday+Leaves+Grass+Gray+Poet</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOOD GRAY POET.
Walt Whitman's Seventieth Birth
day Is Celebrated To-Day.
Delegations of His Admirers at Camden
to Do Mm Honor.
They Will Dine and Toast Htm While
He Jjles Stricken In Ills
Ilmnblo Home.
trrrciAL to mr kvemho wotn.l
Camden, N. J May 31. This is Walt
Whitman's seventieth birthday and the good
people of Camdou havo prepared to do honor
to tbo occasion in a befitting manner.
It is to be celebrated by a dinner in Mor-
WALT WHITMAN.
gen's Hall, at which more than two hundred
porsous aro exacted to be present, and dele
gations of tho poet's friends and admirers aro
arriving from all parts of tbo country.
Tho ' ' good gray " poet Ir now n vencrnble
personage, nud his growing feebleness in
coiibeiiuenco of his last illness will not per
mit him to tsko nn activo part in tho fes
tivities. For months past ho has bcon confined to
his room in tho modest littlo cottago which
bo occupies in ono of the by-strects of the
town, nnd in tbeso dingy ono might almost
say squalid quarters be has been waiting
patiently for tho end, for he novcr expects
again to recover his physical powers.
The little parlor which he occupies is fur
nished in the plainest style. Tho table and
floor, which was nuco littered with his books
and papers when ho was still able to move
aronud nnd dovoto himself to his literary
woik, aro now kopt spruce nnd tidy, and tho
few tiooks which ho can now read, although
they aro handy to his chair, nro kept in good
order by his housekeeper.
Ho is accustomed to sit in his chair, wrapned
in blankets, although on tho mild Spring days
he throws the covering from his shoulders.
Then the wide open shirt-collar which is so
familiar to all those who know him falls aside
and lays bare tho brown, hairy throat and
upper chest.
But It is tho noble bead, so massive and
full. proportioned, with its halo of silvery,
silken hair falling in long.soft locks from tho
high, rounded coronal, instlct with life and
thought, that most impresses tbe visitor,
Tho wblto beard so singularly clear, and
pure and silken in aspect nnd texture makes
nobly venerable the strongly masculine
moulded features. Tho arched oye-brows
are also white liko bows of driven snow, and
beneath them smoulder tho wondrous gray
eyes.
Although in bis present enfeebled and
crippled condition ho can do but littlo work,
ho ennnot completely abandon bis habits of
Industry, and when ho is feeling brighter
than usual be will somotimos take up tho old
tiBks. Ho feels, however that his working
days nro over, and as ho himself pathotically
says;
"' I just sit hero and wait. What else can I
do?"
Walt Whitman was born at West Bills, Suf.
folk County. L. I., May 31. 1810. During
his boyhood ho attended tho publio schools
in Brooklyn and New York, and thero ob
tained bis education.
At nn early ago ho learned the printers'
trnde aud worked nt thiBdurins the Suuimor,
whilo ho taught school every Winter. In the
years of 1847 snd 1818 he made a very exten.
sivo tour through tho United States and Can
ada, roughing it everywhere, aud in this
way acquired a vast amount of information
and uxporience, which he afterwards utilized
in editing newspapers in Now Orleans and
Huntiugton, L. I.
Ho tired of this, however, although ho was
always writing, and devoted himself to tbo
carpenter's trado in Brooklyn. Iu 18.55 he
published the first edition of "Leaves of
Grass," which created such a sensation in
literary circles.
Fivo editions of this work havo been pub
lished, to each of which numerous additions
wro mado by the poet. IUb "barbaric
yawp," as it was called at first, excited only
ridicule, but ho afterwards found a host of
friends and admirers among tho shining lights
of the lilorarv world.
Ho claimed to inaugurate " an original
modern style," aud nnnouueed himself as
the poet of tho Democracy. Ho says: "Wo
must fouud our own imaginative literature
nnd poetry, and nothing merely copied from
and followintfthe feudal world will do. I dis
miss without ceremony all tbe orthodox accou
tiemeuts, tropes, iaberdnhery ot words, feet
measures that lorm the entire to;k in trade
of the rhyme talking heroos ami heroines. My
metro Is loose and free, the lines aro of in oc
ular length, apparently Ian less nt first
iicrnsal. but on closer aoqualntcnce you will
lud that there is regularity, like the occur,
anco, for example, of tbe leaser and larger
waves on tbe seashore, rolling in without
intermission,; nnd fitfully raising and fall
ing "
From 18C2 to 1B65 Walt Whitmon was a
voluntee nurso iu tbe military camps of
Washington nnd Virginia. Ho filled a govern
ment clerluhlp in Washington from 1865 to
1874, nud while ho was a Dennrtmout olerk he
lived lu the nttla chamber of an old-fashioned
houto opposite tho Treasury, where tbe
Corcoran Art Guliory now Mauds.- Ho was
taken there when am stricken with paralysis
Iul873.
Siuce 1871 he has lived bore In tbe plain
littlo frame oottnge ou Mlcklo street, and for
year tbe children have been familiar with
tho big armchair ot the poet and his plo.
turesque, kindly face in its framework of
flowing white balr at the front window.
During the last year bis absences have been
numerous, illness confining him to his bed
for loug interva(ls) but now during the warm
days of the approaching Summer he is seen
more regularly at his familiar post.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn2008058170/1890-10-22/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Walt+Whitman+Ingersoll+Poet+Poems+Gray+Leaves+Grass</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WALT WHITMAN
COL. 1KGEH80I.L EULOGIZES' THE
(MEAT POET OF NATURE,
LOYING PRAJSE OF THE GRIZZLED SAGE
The Great Infidel Orator Talks of
Liberty and Literature.
FOINTF.D DIG AT THE GOOD WAtUHAKER.
"These Wendreus 'Liave3 of 0ra8.'"
The ByPalhs sf Oenius"An Rlo-
quenlasd Brilliant Peroration.
l'litLADRtritiA, Oct. S2. When Col
onel Jlobcit O. Imersoll stepped to the
front of the singe In Horticultural Hal
last night to deliver Ms lecture on
"Lllierly and Literature," for tlio testi
monial benefit tendered to "Walt "Whit
man, the poet of Camden, he was
greeted with a hearty round of ap
plause from an auillcnco of about 0,000
perron.
Sealed on the platform were Walt
"Whitman, the ngl beneficiary; Sirs.
Robert G. Ingersoll, 5IUs Maud Ingcr
soil, Dr. John K. Mitchell, Mr. Whit
man's biographer! David McKay, his
publisher: Colonel JSuclld norland,
chairman of the ways and means com
mittee of the New York Legislature.
Dr. Ittirko of Montreal, ltcv. J. II. Clif
ford of (Jormanlowii, Horace L. Trocbel,
Francis II. Williams, Harrison 8. Mor
ris. T. 11. Harold of Philadelphia, and
W. IJ. Hicks of New York.
The eloquent lecturer lost no time In
Introduction, but launched atnncc upon
his subject, which he treated last night
for the first time, and he held his
nudlcncc spell-bound for nearly two
hours.
Colonel Ingcrsoll's eloquence Is as
maikcd as ever, and as lie made the
various points In his discourse and coin
patcd tbo literature and the Intolerance
with which tliu authors and poets of the
past were treated with the liberty unit
aplrlt of toleration of the present day,
uiu auuicncemaniiesieti its appreciation
by punctuating his remarks with loud
nml piolonued upplaute. and at times
when the orator was especially marked
and Impressive, by that rapt silence
that showed the keen Interest of his
listeners.
WAl.T WHITMAN' ACIIIEVKJIKNT.
He said: "In the year 1M the
Amorloan people knew but little of
books. Their ideals, their models
were Kngllsb. Young and 1'ollok,
Addison and "Watts wue regarded as
great nocts: some of the more reckless
reail 'lhomson's Seasons and the poems
and novels of Sir Walter Scott. A few
not iiultc orthodox delighted In the me
chanical monotony of i'ope, and the
rofllly wicked those lost to all religious
shame were worshipers of Shakes
peare. The really orthodox I'rotestant.
untroubled by doubts, considered Milton
the greatest poet or them all. ltvron
ami Shelley were hardly respectable
not to lie read by young persons. It
was admitted on alt hands that liurns
was a child of nature, of whom his
mother was ashamed and proud.
"At this time a young man he to
whom this testimonial Is given he upon
whose head have fallen the snows of
more than seventy winters this man,
bom within the sound of the sea, gave
to the wotld a book, 'Leaves of Grass.'
Tills book was, and is. the true trans
script of the soul. The man Is ua
ma'ked. No drapery of hypocrisy, no
pretense, no fear. The book was as
original lu form as in thought.
"It was a marvelous collection ami
aggregation of fragments, hints, sug
gestions, memories and opheeUM,
weeds and flowers, clouds awl clods,
sights and sounds, emotions ami pas
sions, waves, shadows and constella
tions. HOW 'LKAtEfc' WAS KErKIVEU.
"ills book was received by many with
disdain, with horror, with indignation
and protest by the few as a marvelous,
almost miraculous, message to the
world, full of thought, philosophy,
poetry and music.
' Slbce the year IMS the American
citizen Las concluded that it is hardly
vinilU while being a sovereign unless be
has the right tu think for himself. And
now from this height, with the vantage
wound of to-day, I propose to eiautine
this Wwk and to state in a getwral way
what Walt Whitman has done ami the
place he has won U the world of
thought."
The lecturer here divided the dis
cussion of "Leave of Grass" into
litsTeiesa topics. Under the "Heligloe.
of the Body." he said "Walt Whit
man announced the gospel of the body,
fle confronted the people, lie deeded
the depraviiy of nuus. He insisted that
love is not a crime. lie taught the dig
nity and glory of the father and mother,
the aecieu&amp;tzs e' maternity. Matetnlty,
tender and pure as the tew of pity, holy
as suffering the crown, the dower, thin
ecatSA-y of love.
"Tome Uw most obscene wool In
our language is celibacy. Walt Whit
man defended the sac redness of love,
tke purity of passion the passion that
builds etety tome and tills the world
with ut and sung- Whoever dBsfet
frocu Use miiiiHerfe, especially wit a
led snuhitmse. will ind out flow tfceir
kaden thai he has eosa fitted an um
uaiuVtfsvbbt sis. It is a crisne to travel
a road of your own, especially if you
Cup guide-boatds for the utforei
of oihawsv
"Ko writer must be measured by a
word or line or paragraph, lie is to
be measured by his work. We cnot
measure Shakespeare by a few lines.
awilker can we measure the Bible by a
few chapters, nor , Levee of Grass' by a
few usfugrnfssjs.
"WaltWnkman had the couraze to
s kpreaa his tsvougbt tfj eamior to toll
the truth. Most writers suppress indi
vlduality. They wish to plense the
public. They tatter the stupid and
pander to the prejudice of their readers.
"If what ace hnowu as the beat
people could have their way the works
of llMkkcueM would have bee sup
pressed- If she Scotch kirk couVl have
otcuicd nothing would suve been
known of KuUit Burns. But we axe
uoi fenced to n.0 very far back If
Mi.ektiipt.aic bau bec-u publUhcd for the
Uiftl tiu.c eio Ut'.se ditluc pUya
Uulii lliu. i uLIUcjIj Sud aciu ',iu'.ci
cv n than the ctclltttliirrt of the mld
nlelit sky wotthl be erelttded from the
malic.
tub ritKdF.nrATTOs or i.ibrrtv.
"Walt Whitman is In th hlghMt
sense a believer In democracy. He
knows that there Is but erne exonw for
fwernment the preservation of liberty ;
to the end that man may be liappy. lie
knows that there Is but one excuse for
any Institution, secular and religions
the preservation of liberty ; ami that there
Is but one excuse for schools for uni
versal etlwatlrn, for the ascertainment
of facts, namely, the preservation of
liberty.
'He resents lire arrogance ami cruelty
ot pflwer. He has sworn never to Ire
tyrant or slave. He has solemnly
declared: 'I speak the password
ptlmeval I give the sign of democ
racy. I will accept nothing wlilcu all
cannot have their counterpart of on the
seme terms.'
"lie fell as all should feel, that the
liberty of no man Is safe unless the
liberty of each Is safe. Whitman has
reminded the people of this countiy
that tbey aie supreme, ami lie lias said
to them: 'The riesldcnt Is there In the
While House foryou It Is not vou who
are here for him.'
"In fpeaklng of the Individuality of
tlic American, he said: 'In order to pro
tect the liberties of a nation we must
protect the Individual. A democracy
Is a nation of free Individuals.' Walt
Whitman has told us that 'The whole
theory of the universe Is directed lo one
single Individual namely, to you.'
Whitman Is lire port of Individuality
the defender of the rights of each for
the sake of all and his sympathies nrc
as wide as tbo world. He Is the de
fender of the whole race."
The next point dlscusod was the
humanity of the poet. Colonel Inger
soll said: "Tho great et is Intensely
human, infinitely sympathetic onteri tig
Into the Joys and griefs of others. When
the rcrticctable people of the North, the
rich, the successful, were willing to
carry out tho fugitive slave law, Walt
Whitman said:
"I am tlie wounded slave I wince at Hie
tiltoot tlie Clogs.
Hell ihJ despair are upon me 'Crack'
aril again crick' Hie marktmen;
I clutch the rails of the fence my Mood
chips thinned with the ooieof my
skin;
I fall on lite weeds am! stones;
'1 lie riders fpur llictr unwilling liorwi
haul clow;
Taunt hit illzry enrs ami beat me with tus
butts ot their whip.
Atonies are one of my changes of trarment.
1 do not ask the won mini jiersun lionr l
feels. I mjielf become the wounded
Irsen."
The lecturer then discussed the points,
"What Is 1'oilry?" "The Philosophy of
Poetry" and Whitman's two poems,
"A Word Out of the Sea" and "When
Lilacs Last In the Dooryard Dloomed."
WAJ.T WHITMAN I.Ktl TJIK WAY.
He closed with the following brilliant
peroration:
"Walt Whitman has dreamed treat
dreams, told gteat truths nml uttered
sublime thoughts. He has held aloft
the torch ami bravely led the wiy.
"As you read the marvelous book, or
the pirwn. called 'Leaves of Grass,'
you feel the freedom of the antique
wotld; you hear the voices of the morn
ing, of the first great singers voices
elemiutal as those of sea and storm.
Tho borlon enlarges, tbehenveus grow
ample, limitations are forgotten the
realization of the will, the accomplish
ment of the Ideal, will be within your
power. Obstructions become petty ami
disappear. The chains ami bars are
broken ami the distinctions of caste are
lost.
"The soul is in the open air, under
the blue and stats the nag of Nature.
Creeds, theories ami philosophies ask to
be examined, contradicted, recon
structeil. Prejudices disappear, super
stitious vanish and custom abdicates.
The sacred places become highways,
duties and desires clssp hands and be
come comrades and frleuds. Authority
drops the sceptre, the priest, the mitre
and the purple falls from kings. The
Inauimate becomes articulate, the mean
est ami humblest things utter speech
and the dumb and voiceless burst Into
song. A feeling of Independence takes
possession of the soul, the body ex
trends, the Wood Hows full and free.
superiors vanish, rUltery is a lot art
and life becomes rich, royal and su
perb.
"The world becomes a personal pos
session ami the oceans, the continents
ami constellations belong to you. You
ate in the centre, everything radiates
Hem you and in your veins beats and
Ibreibk the pulse of all life. You become
a lover, cateleas ami free. You wander
by the shores of all seas and hear the
eternal psalm. You feel the silence of
the wide forest, and stand beneath the
titer twined and over arching boughs,
entranced with symphonies of winds
sod woods. You are borne on the
tides of eager and swift rivers, hear the
i ush and roar of cataracts as they fall
beneath the seven -hued arch, and watch
the easeies as they eirclintr soar.
"You traverse gorges dari and dim,
and climb the scarred and threatening
clllfs. You stand la orchards where
the blossom i fall like snow, whet the
birds neat and sing, and painted moths
make aimWss journeys through the
happy air You live the lives of those
who till tue earth, and walk amid the
perfumed nehis, hear the reapers' song,
and feel the breadth and scope of earth
and shy. You are in the gteat dries, in
Use uddet of multitudes, of the etui teas
professions You are on Use wfcie
plains the nrairiaa with hunter and
trapper, with savage and pioneer, and
feel tke soft grass yielding under your
feet.
"You sail in many ships and breathe
the free air of the sea. You trsvel
tuany roads and countless pihs. You
visit unlaces asui prisons, hospitals and
courts, you pity kings and convict,
and your sysnnntby goes out to all the
suffering and insane, the oppressed and
enslaved, and even the inf uutoua. You
heat the din of labor, ail sounds of
factory, inkl and forest, of all tools. In
struments and ntachines. You becosne
familiar with men and wosuen of all
tuiploynujuls. trades and professions
with birth and burial, with wedding
feast and funeral chant-
"You see the cloud and inine ol
a.r vou eniov the tBitslahhi uerfect isms
of nance, in tfrfa one book, in these
wondrous 'Leaves of Grass,' you fnd
hint and suggestion, touches anst frag
ments, of all there is of life, thai Mas
between the babe, whose rounded
cheehs uinude h$nnnth has ittoahnv'i
laughing, laving eyes, and Uw oUsnan.
snow crowned, who. wish a wtafcte. ex
tends frft hand to death-"
iu row' kvci-i.T.
At the close of the lecture Colonel
lniiclt saked the t:ucl vf the even
lo.' i oikc a few remarks.
In Wlaiman is growing feeble,
It... ' ;v.ni3 ifj'i u I a n wlili
rtlfflnillt that Ire liegsn his brief ad
dress. He sen!, tremblingly
"After all the main fretor with me
this evening is being face lo face with
this anttterrce In a meeting like this. I
thought I would come to night to be
with ymt ami thank yon for coming and
Colonel Ingerwdl for speaking, ami with
there wortfi I bW you good-bve."
After the meeting broke up rmny
cam forward to shake the hand of the
aged pret. He Imde Colonel Ingersoll
a very atTectirmate farewell ami offetwl
his sincere thanks, to which Mr. In
gersoll replied: "The debt is all on Ihe
other side. I am Indebted to yon, Mr
Whitman."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87060190/1892-03-28/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Walt+Whitman+Aged+Poet+Peacefully+Rest+Gray+Leaves+Grass+Poets</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PEACEFULLY AT REST
Death of Walt Whitman, the
Aged Poet.
WENT TO SLEEP LIKE A CHILD.
Trie End Came Just no Day Wa Fading
Into Night Career of the Venerable
Muse, Whoso Declining Days Were
Passed Away In Ills Humble X.lttle
Cottage at Camilen, New Jersey.
Philadelphia, March 28. Calmly
and peacefully, like a child asleep,
Walt Whitman, the "Good Gray Poet,"
passed away Saturday evening at his
home, in Camden, N. J. He had been
weaker than usual for some days past,
but for some reason the knowledgo
of his condition did not becomo public
property. Ho had a sinking spell Fri
day night, but recovered Bomewhat.
Again at 4:80 Saturday afternoon he be
gan to sink. A messenger was hurriedly
Bent for his physician, Dr. Alexander
McAllister, who reached the dying
man's bedside a short while afterwards.
The doctor found the aged po6t in a
dying condition, and so informed those
around his bedsido. Ho asked tho
patient if ho suffered any pain and tho
whispered answer was "No."
WALT WHITMAN.
Almost immediately before he died he
said to his attendant, Warren Fitz-
einger.
"Worry, shift," meaning to turn
him over
on tne neu. inese were nis
last words, and they were uttered so
low that they were hardly audiblo.
He remained conscious to the last,
but owing to his extremely weak condi
tion, was nnablo to reply to tho repeatqd
inquiries of the friends who had gath
ered round his bedside. These were
Mrs. Davis, his housekeeper; Warren
Fitzsinger, his male attendant; Lawyer
Thomas B. Hornad, Horace Trouble and
Dr. McAllister. Mr. Whitman has been
confined to bed since Dec. 17, when he
was attacked with pneumonia. Shortly
after his physicians pronounced him
cured, but the attack so weakened his
constitution that he never rallied, and
his death was practically due to ex
haustion. The news of the death was cabled to
Lord Tennyson and other friends in En
gland, Dr. Buck, of Ontario, his bio
grapher, and friends in this country.
The sick man took very little nourish
ment during tho past three days, an oc
casional sip of milk punch being all that
he could be induced to swallow. Satur
day morning he declined nourishment of
any kind. He had at intervals since the
illness, beginning Dec. 17, last, which
rondered him bedfast, expressed a weari
ness of life and a willingness to die, and
it is believed that the old poot realized
that death was near-and rejoiced accord
ingly. It is with regret that tho world nears
of the "Good Gray Poet's" death. His,
contemporaries were not always kind to
him. The critics "cut him up" with
their pens, but the sturdy old man never
deigned a Kjply or a defense.
His chief crimes in the eyes of his op
ponents were his utter lack of conven
tionality, his use of words not often
Bounded in "ears polite" and his total
disregard of tho laws of versifying.
But Whitman calmly ignored the on
slaughts made on him and insisted that
he had merely inaugurated a new
stylo.
"I dismiss," he has said, "without
ceremony all the , orthodox accouter
ments, tropes, haberdashery of words,
feet, measure that form the entire stock
in trade of rhyme talking heroes and
heroines, My meter is loose and free.
The lines are of irregular length, appar
ently lawless at first perusal, but on
closer acquaintance you will find that
there is regularity, like the recurrence,
for example, of tho lesser and larger
waves on the seashore, rolling in with
out intermission and fitfully rising and
falling."
This sort of reasoning, however, by no
means disarmed his critics, 6omo of
whom are quite as opposed to his efforts
to-day as they were at the timo of their
original publication. Naturally the
general public was tp a largo extent pre
judiced by these opinions of trained lit
erary men. No other result was pos
eible, for Whitman was called "sen.
aual," "immoral," "gross," and with
such persistence that the ordinary reader
in America came after a time to look
upon him as a person whose writings
were objectionable. Of late years, how
ever, there had been a decided reaction.
Perhaps tho new generation have come
to understand and appreciate hia works
better, in the reflected light of tho pure,
poverty burdened lifo which their author
has been leading in the humble Camden
cottago. Whutevor the explanation, re
8Pct for the. lonely old man has cer
tainly replaced to a large extent the
ridiauj formerly expressed for, him.
Abroad there Is no" question as to tho
feeling wnich will bo called out by the
the news of his Idemiso. In tho darkest
hours of his struggle for famo it was
Whitman's consolation that ho was
appreciated in Europe. The English
people particularly hailed him as a
genius, ad tho true American poet,
greater than Bryant or Longfellow. In
America, when "Leaves of Grass" ap
peared, in 1855, there was practically no
ono to utter a good word for it except
Ralph Waldo Emerson, who said of it
in a letter written to the author:
"I find it the most extraordinary piece
of wit and wisdom that America has yet
contributed."
Elit there was no other prominent
American writer to etho the sentiment.
In Great Britain, however, tho literary
n-nrld accented tho work .nt Emerpon's
valuation, ud when Whitman subse
quently followed it up with his other
poems, he was accorded a singularly
exalted place in tho foreign world of
letters.
Tennyson and Browning and Sir Ed
win Arnold all wrote of him in the
highest terms, and no English writer
visiting America ever neglected to call
at the poet's Camden homo. His first
interview with Sir Edwin Arnold two
years ago was almost pathetic in its
earnestness. Tho two men literally fell
into each other's arms, arid the distin
guished English litterateur afterward
related that he had spent one of the
happiest days of his life in tho company
of the Beptuagenarian poet.
Nearly all the British literary men of
note were equally enthusiastic in their
praise of tho American bard. Ho was
held up again and again in tho English
magazines as the long looked for apostlo
of a new and perfect Bchool of poesy,
and when it became known that the
poet was actually in want the depth of
the English admiration for him was
manifested in the most convincing man
ner. An appeal for aid was printed in
nearly every paper published in tho
kingdom. After reciting his merits and
the good ho had done for literature, tho
appeal concluded:
"Walt w mtman starving.
"A man's ransom wanted. Tho
victim is in the hands of a relentless
enemy, who, if the ransom bo not
speedily paid, will immediately make
an ena of him. Will his fellow men
put forth a hand to keep ono of the
world's immortals a little longer here,
or will they allow death to take him ere
his time?"
The response to this call was prompt
and generous, and saved the poet from
any future fear of actual hunger. In
view of this general admiration and
esteom awarded him, it is no wonder
that Whitman held the English in high
regard, and it would seem that no
would have sought an asylum among
them. But he never once dreamed of
such a course. He was beyond every
thing an American, proud of his parent
ago,.and prouder still 'of his country.
"My" tongue, eory atom of my blood;
formed from this soil, this air. Born
hero of parents born hero, from parents
the same, and their parents the same,"
is his boast in one of his compositions.
And there are few Americans who had
a greater right to be proud of their
Americanism, for his family on both
sides counted back over nearly 800
years' residence in the New World. Hia
father caino of English stock and his
mother of Dutch, her" maiden name hav
ing been Van Velsor. He was born a
farmer's son at West Hills, L. L, on
May 81, 1810j and received a common
school education, partly at his birth
place nnd partly in Brooklyn. Subse
quently he entered a job office in the
latter city and learned tho trade of
printer, to which he clung with more or
less regularity for some years.
Incidentally, however, he inter
spersed his typesetting with school
teaching and literary work. He edited
several Brooklyn papers for short
periods, among others The Freeman and
Eagle. But his restless disposition did
not content itself with any regular pur
suit, and in 1648, accompanied by his
brother, he made a trip to New Orleans,
traveling by easy stages, sometimes
walking, sometimes' driving, and when
convenient proceeding by steamboat.
For a year he came to anchor in New
Orleans, doing editorial work on Tho
Crescent most of the timo, June of 1849
found him back in Brooklyn, where,
oddly enough, he went to work as a
carpenter. He followed this business
for five years, without, however, discon
tinuing his writing! entirely.
Early in 1855 he issued tho first edi
tion of "Loaves of Grass." The contents
of this singular book were neither verse
nor prose, but a series of ejaculations
and aphorisms presenting many original
ideas and appealing to the common feel
ings of mind in favor of the natural en
joyment of life, the exorcise of tho ac
tive powers of mind and body and the
frank reception of wholesome influences.
At first the critics did not notice this
work, either to praise or condemn. They
ignored it entirelyt In a few months,
however, a copy fell into the hands of
Ralph Waldo Emerson. He wrote a let
ter (from which a quotation is inado
abovo) to Whitman praising the work in
the most unrestrainod manner. This
letter was published shortly after its re
ceipt, and at once attracted the atten
tion of the reviewers to tho book which
they had entirely overlooked before.
On all aides tho work was condemned,
and in Boston and other cities it was de
clared unfit for circulation in tho public
libraries because of its alleged immoral
tono.
But Whitman defied all his censors,
and between other writings continued
to mako tho "Leaves of Grass" his spo
cial work. In 1850 he published a sec
ond edition of tho work, and four years
later a third, followed between tho
yeurs of 1807 and 1883 by five other edi
tions, and in 1889 by the last and ninth,
with tho final authentic text. All of
Whitman's readers ngreo that on this
work his fame will rest.
The period of the poet's lifo most pro
lifioof experience and suggestions for
stirring verso was certainly that from
1883 to 1805. In tho former year he
wenttQ,th.e'fro.nta8a volunteer irarset
arid until hostilities ceased between the
north and south he remained at his post.
He personally attended nearly 10,000
wounded soldiers of both sides, and his
tender sympathy eased the last days of
many a poor fellow who, but for him,
would have died friendless.
His ceaseless labors in field and hos
pital afterward told on him, producing
the disense from which he died. During
all his active life in the war he managed
,to do sufficient writing to support him
self, and on the occasion of Lincoln's
death he brought out the famous "O
Captain! My Captain!" which is prob
ably the best known of all his writings.
When tho war was over Whitman was
appointed to a clerkship in the attorney
general's office in Washington, which
placed him in comparatively easy cir
cumstances for the first time in years.
Until 1873 ho remained nt the capital one
of tho principal figures in the city. Then
the disease contracted in the army mani
fested itself in a dangerous form known
as "progressive paralysis," and he had
to retire from all active work. He took
up his abode in the poor little frame cot
tage at 328 Mickel street, in Camden, N.
J., just ucross tho river from Philadel
phia. There ho remained until death
came to relieve him.
It was there, paralyzed and unable to
work, that he almost starved, until tho
English appeal for aid in his behalf
awoke the American people to a. senso of
his condition, and led to some efforts at
raising funds for his support. But
somehow the "benefits" and other af
fairs given never yielded tho results they
should, and a small circle of his intimate
friends were the chief providers.
Through their efforts he was enabled to
end his days in tho moderate way that
contented him.
On April 14, 1887, Mr. Whitman
spoko for the last time in public. He
lectured at tho Madison Square thoater,
in New York, on Abraham Lincoln.
His appearance was as striking and
venerable as ever. Long, flowing
white beard, hair like spun silver hang
ing down in wild profusion under a
wide sombrero; a strong patriarchal
face, with soft, benevolent eyes; a tall
imposing frame, over six feet high, and
still muscular and almost straight, des
pite the weight of years and the ravages
of disease. It was generally thought
that it would probably be tho poet's last
appearance before the people, but a few
months ago he managed to attend a
Philadelphia reception in his honor, at
which Colonel Ingersoll delivered an
eloquent address.
The New York affair was well man
aged, and many prominent literary men
patronized it; yet, in order that the poet
might go home with $200 in his pocket,
the Rev. Robert Collyer had to add a
handsome personal contribution to the
receipts. But despite his lack of appre
ciation the sweet tempered old man
never felt any bitterness toward his f el
Iowp. To all who visited him at his
home he never expressed a word of re
proach against the American public,
and his final address to the world
breathes only tho most fervent grati
tude. It was published just before his
last severe illness, which threatened at
the time to carry him off ou tho journey
for which he has long been so well pre
pared, and which he viewed with the
utmost complacency:
Thanks in old ue thanks ere I go,
For health, the midday Run, tho impalpa
ble air for life, mere life.
For beings, groups, love, deeds, words,
books for colors, forms,
For all the brave, strong, men devoted,
hardy men who've forward sprang
In freedom's help, all years, all lands,
For braver, strongor, more devoted men
(a special laurel ere I go to life's
war's chosen ones,
The cannoneers of song and thought
tho great artillerymen the foremost
leaders, captains of the soul;)
As soldier from an ended war return'd
ns traveler out of myriads, to the long
procession retrospective,
Thanks, joyful thanks I a soldier's trav
eler's thanks.
Thereafter the days with him moved
on in a monotonous round, hia strength
each day growing less. Yet his ramd
remained clear, his temper as cheerful
as ever and his 'love of nature seemed to
grow stronger as the parting grow near.
The trees and tho flowers talked to him,
the eunshino held philosophy for him,
the voices of children and the twittering
of birds were mnsio in his eare till those
organs were hopelessly dulled.
At an early hour Sunday morning
Thomas B. Harned, an old friend of
Walt Whitman and ono of his literary
executors, met George Whitman, a
brother of the poet, and together with
other friends, arrangements for the
funeral were finally decided, and the in
terment will take place at 2 o'clock on
Wednesday afternoon.
The remains of the poet will bo placed
in the recently-completed tomb in Har
leigh cemotery, in the outskirts of the'
city of Camden, a Bpot selected by Mr.
Whitman when he was enjoying his
usual health, and which he visited many
times during the construction of thu
tomb. The idea of tho tomb was his
own and one of his friends could not dis
suade him from it. He selected his own
lot, which is in a portion of tho ceme
tery known as Woodlawn, and the tomb
is built in the side of tho hill in a grove.
When asked why he selected such a
spot he replied: "I would rather go in
the' woods."
Tho tomb is a substantial structure,
built of massive rough granite blocks,
some of them weighing over seven tons.
The door if- of granite, six inchos thick.
No rods, bolts or other fastenings are
used in the $tructure, tho four corners
being held together by interlocking or,
morticing tho blocks of granite. The
only metal used was the heavy hinges
on which the door hangs and tho mas
sive brass lock that secures it. Tho
tomo contains receptacles for eight
caskets or coffins, arranged in two tiers.
They were constructed of marble, and
will be sealed with polished marble
slabs. The roof is also of granite, the
top piece containing simply tho name,
"Walt Whitman."
The ooL'ft wbh wa that tka remains
ot his mother, which aro buried in Ever-
freen cemetery, and those of nis father,
uried in Brooklyn, should be exhumed
and deposited in the tomb. This wish
will be compliod with by thos to whom
ho instructed the bequest.
Yesterday an autopsy was made upon
tho body of the 'deceased poet. The
physicians found, it is said, that the left
lung was entirely gone, and only a
breathing spot of tho right lung re
mained. They found about three quarts
of water around the heart, and a large
number of small abscesses about that
organ. The pain in the loft side had
been occasioned by peritonitis.
The brain was found to be abnormal
ly largo and in a quite healthy condi
tion. Portions of the brain and other
organs were taken for microscopic ex
amination. After they had finished
their labors the physicians stated that
the poet was one of the most splendidly
built men they had ever examined.
SSpgg&amp;gsSy V ' ; "i
WALT WHITMAN'S CAJIDKN HOME.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015104/1892-03-28/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Walt+Whitman+Venerable+Poet+Silent+Majority+Gray+Leaves+Grass+Poets+Poems+Poetry</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WALT WHITMAN.
TLTE VEJVEP.ABJLE POET JOINS TIIE
SILENT MAJORITY.
110 Passed Away Calmly nnd Peace
fully, Like a Child Asloep, at Ills
Home In Philadelphia.
PitiLAOELVirtA, March 27.—Calmly and
peacefully, like a child falling asleep,
Walt Whitman passed away last evening.
He had been weaker than usual for some
days past, and had a sinking spell Friday
night, but recovered somewhat. Again
at half-past I o'clock in the afternoon he
began to sink. I»r. Alex. McAllister
reached tbe dying man's bedside shortly
alter. The doctor lound the aged poet in
a dying condition. He asked tho patient
if he suffered any pain, and ho whispered
the answer "no." Threo minutes be:..re
death he said to au attendant, "Weary,
shift." They were the last words uttered
by Mr. Whitman. His breathing came
fainter and fainter, and at exactly 6:43 p.
.m. he passed away. At the timo ol the
"good, gray poet's" death his bedside in
the little frame cottage was surrounded
by a littlo group comprising Thomas i..
ilarned, his close friend; Horace L. Trab
bet, his Secretary; Dr. McAllister, and
his housekeeper and a faithful male at
tendant.
I'CNIJHAL ON V.'KDNESDAY.
Camden (N. <?.), March 27.—The funeral
of Walt Whitman will take place
Wednesday. Al ihe autopsy held to-day
the organs of tho poet were found in a
state of disease that should, by all laws of
medicine, have killed him years ago.
BNSHBOUJDKP IN GLOOM.
Puilaiu-li'Ula, March 27.—The quaint
little homo ofthe "good gray poet," at 328
Meckle street, Camden, was enshrouded
in the deepest gloom to-day. Ats:Bo P.
m. Drs. Alexander, McAllister and Dan
iel Longa.re and two other physicians
met at the poet's house to perform the
autopsy. They were met by Lawyer
Horned, who stated to them the objec
tions of George Whitman to a' post
mortem. The physicians thoroughly dis
cussed the matter.
Their purpose was not a satisfaction of
professional curiosity. They said they
believed that tho autopsy of Whitman
would be of great value to science. He
suffered from bronchial pneumonia, and
had survived for months when his con
dition at one time indicated that he
could survive but five hours. He suf
fered from mysterious pain in the left
side for years, which hud been diagnosed
as a cancer. It was desirable to know
whether this was true or not.
It was also desirable to know whether
there were any evidences in his braiu of
the strokes of paralysis from which lio
suffered a year ago, and other facts. The
importance in tho interests of medical
science might be shown. The physicians
stated that they had discussed she subject
of a post mortem examination with Whit
man last December, and be had assenedt
to it.
Walt Whitman was born of an English
father and a Dutch mother at Hunting
ton, Long isiand, N. V., on the gist ol
May, 181 ft At dilferent times ho was a
lawyer's clerk, a doctor's clerk, a type
setter, a teacher, a reporter, an editor, a
farmer and a house-builder. In pursu
ing such avocations ho traveled ail over
this country, seeing every large moun
tain and river and lake, and getting a
good general idea ofthe principal com
munities. In 1«02 he went t.» the front
with the army, aud his ministration
among the wounded made his name- al
most famous as an humanitarian. "Alter
the war he had several smaii Government
positions.
lv 1864 he began to write his compo
sitions, which were so original that no
one understood or appreciated them. In
1855 be published twelve compositions
under the titlo of "Leaves of Grass."
He himself helped set the type. The
b< ok attracted no notice, but "Whitman
was in no wise discouraged. He added
new pieces whenever tiie inspiration
came, and year alter year issued new
editions of the "Leaves of Grass," gain
ing auditors with every issue, until it be
came a volume of 283 poems.
in an appreciative sketch of Mr. Whit
man, li. Buxton Fonnan says; "The
term poet does not fully describe V alt
Whittr.an;ibc prophet would come nearer.
Ot all optimists he is the most absolute;
bis faith in the ultimate pertection of the
scheme of things never wavers; he sees
promises of eventual good in ali that is
evil—uay, he even discovers a present
got.d in what is evil; he will hear of no
annihilation of the individual and no ulti
mate loss or failure Of any human
creature, and it ;s the endeavor of his
writings to inspire every man and woman
with a sense of his or her personal dig
nity. Nothing of tho nature of a com
plaint has ever proceeded from him."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87062245/1902-10-05/ed-1/seq-26/#words=Personal+Recollections+Walt+Whitman+Jack+Engle+Leaves+Grass+Gray+Poet</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FIRST met Walt Whitman In the
winter of 1S6G at tho old Washington
I
ington House corner of Pennsyl
vania Avenue find Third Street
A number of Big Injun chiefs
were holding a reception in the parlors
of the hotel and were dressed out in
all the wild fantastic war gear of the
plains and mountains of the boundless
West
A notable gathering of private and
putillc citizens bad assembled to shake
the red hand of the noble savage and
hear the grunt and chuckle of blazing
warriors who had lifted the scalps of
many white settlers and left their lone
ly cabins in ashes Senator Henry Wil
son of Massachusetts Introduced me
to several noted men Anson Burlin
game Ben Wade John A Bingham
James Buffington Henry Winter Davis
Charles Sumner Thaddeus Stevens and
last but not least Walt Whitman
To me Walt Whitman then only a re
tired army nurse and Government clerk
seemed the biggest man In the crowd
V2
-
-
because hie high broad brow luminous
eye shambling Independent gait and
epigrammatic expressions showed a su
perior Boul He wore long straggling
bslr over a massive brow a kind of San
ta Glaus that everybody recognized as
a Mend He was so mild simple and
unajBsumtng that he was great par
ticularly In sympathy for the wounded
and oppressed The brain may be bril
liant and lofty demanding admiration
but It Is tho true and tender pulsations
of the heart that Impress mankind and
spread the Derfume of life lasting be
yond the grave and growing greener
with the lapse of ages
Whitman had a great heart that ever
beat responsive to the cry of the poor
and fallen and his whole life was a sac
rifice to duty While he was not a
poet in tho rhythmic sense ho was a
chunk logic philosopher sending his
broadax of thought through the tim
bers of literature that still echo In
the whispering Leaves of Grass in
dependent shots from the soul of can-
dor love and truth As army nurse
during the civil war he was the philan
thropist to both blue and gray Whit
man soared away in the sky of truth far
above creeds fashion and policy and
while he was dismissed from a clerkship
in the Interior Department for writing
an immoral book and using bllnt
language the Secretary who wTeaked a
short lived religious vengeance on the
grand old army nurse is forgotten or
only remembered by his bigoted tyranny
over a genius in literature
Whitmans Varied Career
Whitman was born In West Hills N
T May 31 1819 and died in Camden
X J March 26 1892 He worked in a
lawyers and doctors office after quit
ting school afterward taught school
learned thp printers trade owned news
papers ard was editorial writer on the
Brooklyn New York and Xew Orleans
journals
His first venture in literature was in
1853 when he launched his unorthodox
Leaves of Grass that has beon re
vamped and enlarged until it has run
into twelve editions
Drum Beats Autobiography and
Ov
V
3tem hiSa agSSsu
magazlnc articles have sailed on the set
of literature all bearing the imprint of
Whitmans strong elephantine strides
like his African prototype rushing
through the jungles of sophistry hy
pocrisy and tearing away the tangled
brush of scholastic philosophy
I frequently roamed around Washing
ton with Whitman riding through rain
and shine on the old street cars talking
with drivers and conductors and pass
ing early morning and twilight evenings
in confab with the common run of hu
man chubs suckers and sharks blend
ing our Ideals with the web and woof of
working life where truth is mostly
found
The Social Ladder
The higher you climb the ladder of
society the more frigid become tho in
habitants and the more disgusted an
honest man becomes with pelf and po
litical people who live by a system of
financial chicanery join parties and
combinations rob according to law en
dowing churches hospitals and libra
ries and then go down to an honored
grave
THE STAGE REUBEN 15 NO MORE
Wnat has become of Reuben Where
are to be seen his lank visage fringed
with scrubby beard bis suspenders tied
with twine his carpetsack and linen
duster
You loiter along the crowded down
town thoroughfares and watch in vain
for the wiry framed irAiocenl cyed fig
ure Not one of the hurrying throng
carries a carpetsack Xot one cranes his
neck In an effort to read the signs on
the steenth story windows
Has Reuben been so warned that he
-will not leave the farm Xo for every
incoming trains bring Reuben to town
Ho comes to give his wife a good time
on her semi annual shopping trip to
attend a thrashermens convention
or to see about subdividing some acres
he used to work near the city limits
He wears a coat that If not in the
latest cut is at least unobtrusive He
carries a bag that if guiltless of the
labels of tho traveled Is ihe conven
tional dress suit case as to shape He
has his Chicago banker and his Chicago
lawyer probably t school friends with
whom he lunches and dines apparently
undisturbed by the stir of lights and
music
But Reuben has vanished too from
tho country station the shady lanes
far from traveled roads from the farm
itself He has gone and taken his pic
turesque language with him
Country fair grounds are crowded
as ever but the talk ono hears while
quite as uncivilized is the barbarity
of the pavement and not of the dusty
road Slang whose picturcsquencss
depends on a background of alleys and
brick walls eems strangely out of
place among ihe elderberry thickets
bramble bushes and ragweed
Reuben no longer chews a bit of
timothy ns he leans against a pic
turesque fence nor hits aloft like an
admiral aboard his flagship as he goes
through billows of grain
Alas Reuben has indeed left us to
smile only In hollow mockery from the
pages of the so called funny papers
or to appear now and again In dreary
travesty upon the vaudeville boards
Chicago Evening Post
v -
Jsl JAiiKjfe
On Decoration Day May 30 1SCS at
Arlington Walt Whitman and myself
walked across the Aqueduct bridge
along the river road on the Virginia
side to the National Cemetery and lis
tened to the ceremonies tho first of
ficial memorial held in honor of the pa
triot dead
The day was bright and cool while
the waters of the shining Potomac
flashed and twinkled in the sun as va
grant zephyrs skipped across its placid
bosom The wild flowers peeped from
every nook along the roadside while a
sheet of daisies covered the fields and
hills like a garb of snow and Hitting
rrOr
yssij
Ci
V
Kfti
Vrf
m
m
a
ara
WHITMAN IN HIS LAST DAYS
birds made music through the forest
aisles
Halt naked colored children and old
tottering uncles from the Freedmans
villages adjacent beset us for pennies
In exchange for bunches of daisies and
Wild flowers and It was as funny as a
circus to see Whitman empty his pocket
of pennies nickels dimes and quarters
and fling them in the dusty road while
the group of smoked Yankees scram
bled and tumbled for the filthy lucre
In climbing through the woods of Ar
lington wo passed through the dilapi
dated Confederate graveyard just out
side the red sandstone wall inclosing
i
WT
itMl
SUKrtTj
mm
2I
IDlfp5
m
J
SrViKk
fAM
t jW
VtS sT
E25i
lxV3i
wr7
rESS1
mm
vm
AltD
AJ
COL JOHN A JOYCE
i HV ItiiHS wtCSte
THE TIMES WASHINGTON SUNDAY OCTOBER 5 1902
Heproduccd by the kind permission
of Mr David MtKuy of Philadelphia
the Union dead In our scramble up the
hill Whitman strolled ahead and when
I finally caught up with him he was
standing under a weeping willow beside
a rough headboard marked Frank
Gordon Company A First Georgia
reciting the following verse of poetry
Tlioe in their robing of glory
These in the gloom of defeat
All with the battle blood gory
In the iut of Kternity meet
KnJer ihe od and tin dew
Waiting the judgment day
Under the roses the Blue
tluler the willow the ray
This to me was a great generous pic
ture to behold Walt Whitman the loy
m
iSMs
tiilt
i
aggi
PET
V
jOjT
W
JAagy M ji jiCfeaifea iL J rsA ssnlfei22ii -
L 1aRsjk
Sfejrg
alist and philosopher reciting love lit
lines over the remains of Confederate
soldiers -and an incident I shall never
forget- -Life is too short to hate each
other and love Is too sweet to barter
for vengeance Whitmans broad gen
erous nature went out to all mankind
like perfume from a field of new mown
hay and over the mouldering remains of
a late enemy his noble heart responded
to the dictates of charity that still
spreads a glow of living light over the
pathetic ashes of remembrance
When we arrived in front of the Ar
lington mansion the decoration ceremo
nies had bogun Gen N P Chfpmac
was chairman of the committee of ar
rangements and called the assembly tc
order Col W T Collins read General
Order Xo 1 establishing Decoratloc
Day signed b Gen John A Logan the
national commander of the Grand Army
of the Republic Dr Byron Sunderland
delivered the opening prayer Gen
James A Garfield delivered a most elo
quent and patriotic oration Col J C
Smith rendered an original poem Gen
Holbert E Paine read Lincolns Gettys
burg address and Dr C B Boynton de
livered the b nedlction at the tomb of
1
the Unknown The cannons thundered
a national salute and 20000 people
spread flowers over the graves of their
sacred dead
As the golden beams of sunset nestled
In the towering treo tops of Arling
ton the Good Gray Poet and myself
sauntered through the woods and by
paths to the historic Long Bridge and
passed over Its tottering timbers to
Washington where we bid good by for
the day as the flickering lamps ot om
nipotence sparkled In their eternal
realm
Words That Live
Eighty three years have passed since
Whitman was born yet the words of
Bob Ingersoll ten years ago over his
pulseless clay speak the hope ot im
mortality
Over the grave bends Love sobbing
and by her side stands Hope and whis
pers We shall meet again Before
all life is death nnd after all death is
life The falling lent touched with
the hectic that testifies of autumns
the mention of mental affections In the
lower animal is apt to excite incredulity
or even a smile But the occurrence ot
hysteria among them has long been
recognized In fact there is nothing odd
about this Many of the lower animals
are endowed with the most lively emo
tions and their disordered emotions
arc fruitful causes of various psyrhoses
The emotions of the dog cat and Uin
horsj are familiar to all
A French veterinary surgeon SI
iimry has just discoursed entertainingly
in La Nature on this sunjecl Fear
and joy according to Loplnary aro ih
two emotions which net most disas
trously upon the nervous system of ani
mals Tims a dog was separated from Its
luistress for several mentis of each
XtC r - oatSwcSask
I
-- iis4
f
death 13 in a subtle sense a prophecy oi
spring
I lay this poetic spray upon the hon
ored grave of my old friend
WALT WHITMAN
In youth I knew the grand old man
Who lived upon the Cod like plan
Of doing daily every good
T lib human brotherhood
I roamed with him among the hills
And heard the music of the- rills
That echoed back the red birds call
Where leaped the sparkling waterfall
And giant oaks in rhythmic tune
Made music in the leafy June
We talked of flowers and birds and tree
While through our locks the balirjRbrreze
Went tripping on with joyous
The heir of every sun and sea
Whilp wood nymph with their wistful eye
Looked out with innocent surprise
And when we tried their realm to cass
Tney tangled up with Leave cf Grass
While lustful Pan through woods nnd weodl
Pursued fair Syrant to the reeds
i That still give forth their troubled tune
Amid the Bowers of May and June
Through rmstic gods the good gray seer
Invoked Dame Nature year by year
And from her breathing bosom brought
The richest gems of ripet thought
That down the agr shall endure
And keep hi memory gieen and pure
We saw Potomac roll away
Mid vales and hills of green and gray
Fr rcver running night and day
To plunge at last into the bay r
mf
And mingle with the ocean spray
A patriot of purest mould
With heart and soul like virgin gold
He ever soothed the bed of pain
And never worked for greed or gain
Who knew no color race or creed
But put Ids words in doing deed
FUU knowirg well upon this sod
All men are equal with their God
We often roamed amid the mart
Where men contend with trade and ar
And heard the wrangling voice of gain
Discussing in the saow and rain
The price of trout ducks and collars
All or pVnce dimes and dollars
And then upon the rumbling car
Through street and lane wed ride afir
Until the burning setting sun
Went down on glorious Washington
And when the stars with magic light
Illumed the curtain of the night
Upon some rocky pyramid
- Wed listen to the -Italy-did
While far away amid the hills
The hooting owlt and rippling rill
Would echo back the poets sigh
Tlut fluttciNl through the evening sky
When Luna and her gorgeous train
Diffused their beams oer mount and mala
But now alone upon the stream
I drift at twilight in a dream
ct Whitman ghost like by my sua
Repeats his words that never died
lie true and kind to all you meet
In forest aisles or crowded street
And ever go with nilling feet
To help a comrade in retreat
ANIMALS WHO SUFFER FROM HYSTERIA
The pathology of the lower animals
has been extensively studied both for
Its own sake and for the light which it
throws on the disease ot man It is per
bnps in the nervous system that tho
least advance has been made in com
parative especially In the
iomaln cf the psychoses At first thought
year when thp time for a reunion came
it was necessary to act with great cau
tion otherwise the excessive Joy of tho
animal caused a nervous crisis the ef
fects of which lasted several months 3f
Leplnary had n canary bird which
while singing in its cage was frightened
by a prowling cat The bird fell
Isclous nnd was revived with difficulty
complete aphonia resulted nnd lastea
for six weeks r this hysterical stigma
then disappeared suddenly Just as in
the human subject and the bird resumed
its singing A traumatic thock can causo
hysterical paraplegia in a cat as wn3
observed by Leplnary Tho animal wa
attacked and bitten by a dog and wa
left completely paraplegic dragging its
hind quarters as it tried to walk This
persisted for two month when the
unlmal wa3 suddenly cured by being
thrown from a window by a cruel ser
vant It jumped up and ran away
This subject has been studied by the
French and has not been neglected bj
Gllles do In Tourette in his treatise on
hysteria Philadelphia Medical Journal
PERSONAL RECOLLECTIONS OE WALT WHITMAN
WHITMAN IN WAR TIMES rhcto by Brady jH VO i B k WHITMAN AFTER THE WAR photo by Brady</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1922-06-18/ed-1/seq-57/#words=Woman+Care+Genius+Walt+Whitman+Gray+Poet+Good+Leaves+Grass+Housekeeper+Mary+Oakes+Davis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE WOMAN WHO TOOK CARE OF A GENIUS
aait Whitman's Xeglected and Misiutderstood Housekceper,
)lary Oakes Davis, Fittds a Champion in Mrs. Elizabeth Lea
0 Keller, Now Eighty-two Years Old, Who Nursed the Poet
?? His Last Days, and Who Writes a liook About Miekle Street
By ARTHUR CHAPMAN ? Portrait _y ROY williams
TWO women took care of Walt Whitman
ag his final illness at Camden in
jgp2 One of them was Mary Oake*
Pav.?. irbe for *even years had bern
.^-?ner nurse and friend" to the poet, as
. The other woman
Fliza ? '*? KeWt-r. one of the flrst
vtbii eeaatry'i jtraduate nurse<*. who had
^ joon-nned in her profess.ona! capaci';
# care fcr tb. |
Ir*. *********** who * ' ??"'vlwo ypar"
? ? g at Walt Whitman's
t^jpit in Camden the basis of an absorbing
?^?v fine and -.ist.r'y tribute to
T, .??-?.acr.nce and
.^ -ioubtedly did much toward
in'a last work aoesiMe, but who
i ?
^fr.,.. - ? part of the poet's biog-.
^.,,. learned t" _a_et
?n Daf i, who had sacrificed her health and
' , in caring for tho poet. a
_^v, by some and cruelly misun
;*itcd the little ******
? .cn famc ar.d prospcnty
? Whitman.
fiot c Flattering
Biegraphy. This
Mr$ v. . ? Whitman in Hl
- Mar- Oak.~ Da*
? Qniti aataraUy. in Um
. . lighta are eaal -
ll' P^t ** afra.
" bccame ki.own te
... i iat-natc
?ugh the daily rOBH
... ,., the .ord.d surroundint
i ?aw hica, -
. r blof-aaheri who found
? ired BMMBentS. lt \t
? Btely human.
herteH a remarkable woman.
,s publi-hed by M;tche!i Ken
... Was brouRht out on her
rthday. 5he had woAed on
rteea year*, rewrittaf lt and
? here and there through eor*
ar.d persnnal vi.itr. with tho
?tef Whitman's last
?ted hrr book it began u
ai ' W ?
? another." wai
';.?.
.-? f the- mar
. . Bu< when il caaa to
Kennerley's har.ds he recogni.ed ll
among the many publications bear
1 rntman's ILfe. He published
ft a few months ago. and none can read the
?woyear-old author and
act bc Itruek by its cleamess of thought and
gyla ar.d the vividr.ess of the picture it draw*
uven years in Mickle Street which
ut^f. ?? f ohscurity and poverty.
haracter of Mary Davis eeems to have
t*%*x* in D-aaa Mrs. Keller which
tsMr.ot be shaken off. Every time the poet
? ^ken of, Mr?. Keller would
ahkof that quiet, self-sacrificing woman who
**i foar.d Whitman at her kitchen door?a
Poor, s.ck old man?and who had taken a
aoth*- - f him which undoubtedly long
?rtained his ailing body and enabled him to
****?-j_a_ work which was the culminating
i-taa*. of hia '.ife. Rather than see Mrs. Davis
Pa_ into obscurlty merely as "Walt Whit
***** hou-ekeeper," Mrs. Keller determined
-?iet down what she kr.ew of the woman and
I some way of preserving the record for
ftXtr ars _he made notes, based on
?*r own monthfl of nursing in Whitman's
***?*, aad, in order that she might have leisura
?ottrry o.t fo deMgn and complete her book.
?*?? ett-red an old ladiea' home ln her own
fy of B.fV.o?truly a remarkable example
**d?<a*-*a__atioa. With the e-avings of a life
??**? d -vided herself with a home.
'?*?*? aa Blgkt wrtta.
PxVpWith Whitman'*
Whimt, Which Were Many
^ Keller has been visiting Mrs. Jeasie L
??alBadar, of 703 Sterling Place, Brooklyn,
?*?*** **ra. Charles Gay, of 426 East Eighty
*T?ith Street. New York City, recently. She
*M ifterviewed at Mrs. Harkrader'a home,
?* _dke4 Uaajj 0< the experience*
write the book concerning
*'1 Divij ,-,* Wa.t whitman. She ex
****** H aa her firm helief that if tt had
not been for lln Da*/ia, muh of Whitman a
***** work wouM not hav.' b*Mfl WI
I'avis pave tho po-t Um uttee* ? whicli
the sick man demandod, and furthormore put
up with all his whims and eccentr.
would have been too mu. h f.ir any but the
:>atient of ?oul-< to bear.
In hf*r book .Mrs. Kl f th* wom.in
to whom Whitman was ii for so much
of motherly care:
"Mr?. Di from the cradit *o tho
jrrave was one of seif-<
|
h hlmd old woman to whom I
a*i*/aa a home. ln tpeaking of th:
*I narer bad a childli 1. nor I I ?? ? at that
I had a right to pla*/ |jkc other children, f'-r
in of agt
c?pecial eharg*. On arakins ln tho ma
my tirst thoucri I I and then I
I must no* . another minute. !
quickljr, made my own toilet, and I.
the promiso that bt
Would not tell tho
Knta-ingers until his re
turn from the trip h?*
was on the e\e of tak
Ifl u few days he
niden. Hi
was wrecked off the
coast of .Maine and he
was buned vh<
rt. Hii
haaty man
vented him fro:
irift the ir<
^ ir.i'in for hi^ wife, and.
as she shrank from on)
COnt**rai family,
?11 that was left to her
were hil namo ?v
cherishcd memory of
Mrs. Elizabeth Leavitt Keller, whose book, "Walt Whit?
man in Mickle Street," sheds new light on the poets life
her.' She ront:nued with a detailed account
r.f the attt-fnttorj daily *tr*t*m * ;: Vjntie,'
how ?-he put on her stocking? and sho
handed her each articie of c^othinc: as
needod; how she brought f.'-sh water for her
ablutiors. combed her hair and made h? i
sentable for the table; how at ill mtal
sat by her sjde to wait upon her, and how,
after helping her mother with tha di.-hes, she
? d up and down the lidawalk until i
tJJJM tO ttr.-e 'Aunt ?
being repeatcd when Mhool a
"When M
Auntie' died. Then came two moi'
schooling, after which the girl volu I
sumed another burden?th<- care of a melan
choly, sellish inralid, a distant relative living
in the coun'ry. With her she *.*a.
years. being in turn nurso, companion, I
keeper or general yervant. Bl need req ?
Life work of Mrs. Davis
Was "Mothering"
At tho aa*,* of twanty,
!>>nj- period of rr.remitting care an.l
abnegation, aht summor.ed up rrs'-lut:
leave. She paid a Tllit to a dear l
Mrs. Fritzingcr. wife of ., . tain m
Camden. N. J. Sho found her friend il! ar.d
remaint-d to nurte her. 1
ende.i "V
Fritaingaf r-av.- bar two youns
,;ir.. and from thi ti n they calied her
. ? 1- ritzingi
and hi ? *** ** *****
Ulnan. ,}ii;>'- The taPu*in
appointed Mai; ***** *n(i
divided his property M|Oally BflMmg
Captain I'avi--, a frieiAi cf the Fritzinger*.
proposed marria.ro to Mnry. He was aeeepted
on condition tb;.* ling r-houM r.ot take
place until her frit-nds had no further need
of her.
-But Ua by! ?? ma:-' h"
Davi* thought their natd of bar wotald i
meeting her in Phiiadelph.a one
morning. he insisted upon U
minister's and becoming man and *.*?
thu* forcefully pressed, tonsentaed, but exacted
CnpUin Fri'.zir.Kfr
was blind nine ycars,
: during that I
Mary toofc unrenn'
ef him. The boy?,
Soconiing fourteen
aad abrteea. n
??.-4. and 0:1
thoir return found t
They re
arked for longer
v <>> ...
I, an "Id
shipmatv and friead
Captala Fritsiai
who wa* in poor health
?emcly croch
| f>en
board and for com:
? I ?
?
"Thei
.
?" Sdelity ard
con'tant ll -ay*
?
. r.ipmate went
the way of the oti
But even now the long
tricd woman wa* not left **r
. ?
I ? I had been int. g I I' wa.*
. uiy her de.uiny to find fall ao '
? ?If-sacrifice ?o early imt
?o neisistently called upon. . .
h was the woman who antered ao i
into Walt Whitman'.- life durir.j; the
ycars ipeat in ?' 1,ort'
to him than he wa_ pcrhap? awar
.ortainly, than he ever tared te nd::
was incapable of measur.nj* the fui
?able to measurc th
f ben. B.it he was glan I
Mr-. l?a'lia1 bl BM ? .ens Str"
whuh -treet Walt Whitman had liv.
<*r George. who says. "Walt was ah* I
trying person to live with." But when Gt
Whitman and his wife, for whern Wait Wh.t
The little house in Mickle St eet, Camden, where
Walt Whitman ditd
man ? *i tne -???*"
?:-e* i.nd lli
able existonre which cou! . ;i1?,fl
rinMaatataedhMll Hewa
?na of
.which. ac >.nald
mself usually paid i
Keller:
M old man. w.th hia bar,. ratare
rumden and Philadelphia. had long
_ fami'iar aight. U
f comfor ***** ""
Bal at thii time his life had M
.t deaire?that - I
?Leaves of Grass,' and living lo iee it put be
"The Good Gray Poet"
n a full. improvcd and complete
form."
"Whitman was cxtrcmely poor in Camden
after bll brother moved away and up to about
' says Thomas Donaldson. "His change
of laek began about then. He had previously,
e a sailor's phrasc, been 'scudding under
bare poles.' Hc had -everal runs of luck after
ln His Neighbor's Judgment,
Whitman Wat "a Bit Off"
Whitma: l "run of luck" about this
time seem >>en his acquaintance with
the mothcrly Maiy Davis. Mr*. Keller writes:
(fall Whitman and Mrs. Davis were not
-.crxonally acquaintcd. To be surc. he had seen
her innumerablo times leading Captain Frit
_mgcr past his brother's house, but he had
r.-vt-r ipoken to ber. As for her, the poor old
man had long been a secret pensioner upon her
tender heart. drawing a full bounty of pity
therefrom.
"Their first interview took place on one cold,
;. morning. when, in decpest dejection, he
came a suppliant to her door. Surprised as
. t'.nd him there. she invited him in.
and a fOOd breakfast soon followed the kind re?
eeption.
?With his mritiai ? totally unac
quainted, and she natural'.y shared the univcr
r-al opinion of her neighbors that he was 'a lit?
tle off.' Netertheleea, when from the gratcful
warmth and gor-d cheer he grew loquacious and
dilatci upon his work and aired his lofty hopes,
<he liateaed attentively, that he might not aus
ped that to her all this scemed but an empty
dream and delusion.
"She talked encouragingly, and on his ris
mf. t .illy invited him to repeat hi*
visit. Hn did **o, and thenceforth thia com
passionato wonian's homely kitchen became
his on..- haven of rest. Ho knew that a hot
meal and many thoughtful attentions always
awaited him then*; attention* such a* laemg
aaahiag and mending his clothing
and not infrequently auperintending a refresh
mg foot bath.\s the fall advanced and
the weather became more sevcre. his bachclor
quartera became more and more unsuitable
and he was indced fortunate in the compan
ion*hip he had so auspiciouily foimed. He
dereleped late a dai'.y visitor, and each morn?
ing might have been seen scuffing along in his
unclasped arctic*. cano in hand, and hia long
white hair and beard blowing in the wind.
Mrs. Dav:s said that the very sight of those
ungainly old arctics always brought tears to
her e; ?
Mrs. Keller tells how Whitman, in the win?
ter of 18S.'S:>. ?hrough the generoaity of
fleorge W. t hilds and the aale of his book.
wa* able to arrange for a payment upon a
small houie. He secured the property at 328
Mickle Street. "a coop at boat," as Donaldson
ealled it. his arrangement being to board with
the tenants. But they left and Whitman was
aoliury, hia household goods conaisting of "a
BCaataily furnished beditead, a home-mada
table, a rirkety chair and a large pa.
The table served as a w
packing box as kitchen and dining Ub!< Ipon
it was a small oil itove, where ho would cook
a bite at the ri*k of his life," say* Donaldaon.
Mr*. K.'Ili-r says his daily viv' Havit
were resum'-d. "Her back door would .
upen, and rte, would appear, aaymg in -x
pathetic voico: 'Pity tho sorrows of a poor
old man, whose tromblini? limbs have brought
him to your door.' "
Mrs. Davis did h<-r beat to make Whi'man't
house habitahle, At that time, according to
Donaldnon, ihe wt* "a strong, rosy-ch
Jersey woman." She found the back door
held opm by iro. resultinjr from a br
water pipe. This ice she chopped away.
rarpeted hij sleeping room, gave him a
-ird hedding ar.d in many other waya
? make his u*****m romfortthle. Mn.
Kelbr >ays:
"In ipeakmg of this time she aaid: *H
the poor old man was not in sight, hf was SO
much upon my mind I i P*m one
fal hour.'
Poet Had a Canny Eye
For His Own Comfort
n-r. bavt con idered him a cunnmg man;
all ajjr'f* that h<> was a rcmarkahle judge of
chara'-ter. I"nder?tanding this woman ?
as he must have done?had he rosolved.
to have her iir-\ ?' to him? The i
tion can MVtf be truthfully >
whethrr with premedita'
tainly gained a great influence over her."
Whitman proposed finally that -Mr>. l,*r*3
bt his hnunckr-eper. He said: "I havc a houie,
while you pay ront; you have furniture, while
my rooms are bare; I propose that you
and live with me. brinj-ing your furniture for
tho u H
until finally Mrs. Davis .-.
"TJ ral all on the poet's side,"
aays Mrs. Keller, "as he must hav.
'."events had raised his hopes and he
made promise.s of adequate and more than adt
for all that ha ?
miirht bc done for him.
his money wts 'only in sight,' to uw
his own words, all th<* expenses a*.
were paid ! f Ml I'.v. ??: at ba was disabled,
.-?rk and worry v><re hera as Wellj
tinajly all was accomphihcd, her good* wer*>
transferrod te hil hou.-.e ind put in thiir raw
placcs, and the seven years of their d< ?
life togethei ln this way did tha
'good Rray poet' retiro with I I a*
..r.t' to the little framo cottage,
Mickle .Street."
There were biographers and commcntat/irS
in plenty comir.g te th* little house, in Mickle
? | in laler years. when Whitman'-- famc
pread and when monetary rowarda
U) the poet. But these ?
: they had the man's viewpoint of
. Man hke, they did not understand tho
tremendous burden of work and worry that
had been assumed by Whitman's "single at
tendant." Kot did they know of many other
things roncerning tho poet which were brought
n talks whiefa Mrs. Davis held
Ki !lcr. and wh;ch in all proba;
WhitmaV.'s motherly guardian never ????
h:ive told to anybody but a woman, becauao
only a woman could have underst
Mrs. Davis even accompanied Whitma
the walks he loved to take, particularly to tha
. He was a heavy man, and, owing to h:a
crippled condition, ho "clung to her arm with a
i"-:p of iron." On her suggestion sufficient
fund*- wtrrt sccured by aubscription from V
man's friends to buy a pony and carriaga.
The poet was delighted, and drove tho pony n
much and so fast that its knees wero aoon
>.prung, and he sold it and bought a fast hor?e.
He usod to invite youths in the neighborhood t->
drive him, but. according to Mrs. keller, "a1.
thouKh Mra, Davis was the usutl messonjrer ti
and from the stablc. although she jrot her chargt
ready for his drives, assisted him to the car
I and almost liftcd him in and out of lt,
neithcr he nor any one else ever proposed that
ihe ahould have tht plcasure al a drive."
\< Whitman's fame increasod, visitors be
i.ime more frequent. This meant much ad
ditional work for Mrs. Davis. Whitman ll
friends to a meal at any time. His own meals
v-r-re very irregular. Ho rapped on tho floor
whefl ho wanted to get up, his breakfast hour
being at any time in the forenoon. Whitman,
tsuffering from the effect of his first paralytic
stroke, required much assistam-e in dressing.
All the water for his baths had to be carrifd
lin until later a bathtub wts put in?at
Ml . Davis's expense. Says Mrs. Kelltx:
Consideration for Houteheeper
Not "a Good Cray" Specialty
? iKcasionally, to suit her own convenu nce,
she would have his breakfast prepared; hut
if she mentioned this faet while helping Tiini
te dress, he would invariably aay, 'Ah, I will
not eat anything for a while.' Whon tho di?hrs
had been set aside to be kept warm and Mary
was again busily engaged?the wash ptrhapi
partly hung on the line or her deft hands in
the dough?the peremptory aignal would come,
and on being helped d<>wn and aeated at tht
table he would coolly demand aomething er*.
tircly different from what ahe had provided."
He would keep company at tht table for/
hours; he refused to ltt hia room bo swept, al
he "detested a broom"; and the litter of
papers, twine and printera' proofs in his room
and the front room threatened to spread to
the rest of the house. Mrs. Davis, ao Mrs.
Keller points out. was often blamed for tht
had condition of Whitman's home, whereaj the
fault was not hers.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82004649/1918-01-24/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&amp;index=4&amp;rows=20&amp;words=American+AMERICAN+poet+poets+POETS+Poets&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=american+poets&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The poets thus passed under review are Bryant,
Emerson, Whittier, Poe, Longfellow, Lowell,
Holmes, Lanier, and Whitman.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89061521/1939-10-26/ed-1/seq-10/#date1=1756&amp;index=10&amp;rows=20&amp;words=American+Poets&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=american+poets&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84029838/1880-06-12/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&amp;index=18&amp;rows=20&amp;words=American+poets+Poets&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=american+poets&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89061521/1938-01-12/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&amp;index=3&amp;rows=20&amp;words=AMERICAN+American+POETS+Poets&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=american+poets&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90060762/1922-04-13/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&amp;index=6&amp;rows=20&amp;words=American+poets&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=american+poets&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
